(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-06T21:55:04.454786",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
開けた？開けた？ / 開けたの？
Did you open it? Did you open it? / You opened it?
開けたの？ / 開けた開けた！
Did you open it? / I opened it!
ちーっす！ぐー！
Hey there! Nice!
開けたよ今！今開けた！
I just opened it! Just now!
今開けた！今開けたよ！
Opened it just now! Just opened it!
開けた開けた。なんだよその開け方！
Opened it, opened it. What kind of way to open it was that?!
一応作ってあげたけど。
I made it for you, though.
ぬるって開けるやん。
It slides right open.
スッと...スッと。
Smoothly... Real smooth.
じゃあの...
All right, so...
話すの前に集合！集合！
Before we talk, assemble! Gather 'round!
はーい！はいはいはい！
Okay! Coming, coming!
アイアイサー！集合しました！集合しました！
Aye aye, sir! We're here! All assembled!
おーし、じゃあこれから朝礼を始めます！
All right, let's start the morning meeting!
はい！お願いします！
Yes! Let's do this!
おはようございます！
Good morning!
昨日も一晩、お疲れ様でしたー！
Thank you everyone for your hard work last night!
お疲れ様でした！お疲れ様です！
Thanks for the hard work! Good work!
で、今日はですね、ちょっと昨日は至らなかったんですけど...
So today, though we didn't manage to do it yesterday...
ちょっと「やることリスト」なるものを作らせていただきましたので...
I went ahead and made a "to-do list,"
それをメインに... / おーー！
so based around that... / Ooh!
さすがリーダー！ / 役割を振りつつ、頑張っていきたいと思いまーす！
That's our leader! / We'll assign roles and do our best!
はーい！お願いしまーす！
Okay! Let's do it!
抜け自由！具合悪かったら配信中止なもうみんな勝手なんで...
Feel free to leave anytime! If you feel unwell or need to end stream, do whatever...
タスクやっていきましょー！
So let's get through these tasks!
はーい！おーい！
Yay! All right!
で、何だっけ？なんか届いてる...最初に開けるか？
And what was it? Something arrived... Should we open it first?
これよこれよ、デイリー報酬の... / デイリーミッションみたいなのの報酬、これ何？
This is it, the daily reward... / The daily mission reward? What's this?
これどうぞ！開けてくださいよ、リーダー！
Here you go! Open it up, Leader!
樽を密封されています。長押しで樽を...
"The barrel is sealed." Long press to open the barrel...
開け...はい！ / はい
Open... Okay! / All right.
なんだ？
What is it?
マインドワイプトニック。
Mindwipe Tonic.
は？なにそれ？
Huh? What's that?
うわ、バカになっちゃう。
Whoa, it'll make us dumb.
は？すげぇカタコトだったな、今。
Huh? That sounded so robotic just now.
ね！長押しで開封。
Right! Long press to open.
何？
What is it?
うわっ、こっち左腕ですね、職人レベルの...
Whoa, here's the left arm, Journeyman level...
装備が、ギ、ギリー系装備が入ってます！
There is ghillie-type equipment in here!
おおー！ギリー！
Ooh! Ghillie!
人数分ある？ / 逃げちゃった、逃げちゃった。ちょっとユニコーンを見つけてね、テイムしてーなと。
Is there enough for everyone? / It got away, it got away. I really want to find a unicorn and tame it.
ユニコーン？ / 人数分ある？人数分。
Unicorn? / Is there enough for everyone?
人数分あります！人数分あります！なんでじゃあここから...
There's enough for everyone! Enough for everyone! So from here...
あ、これ皆さん開けられますよね？開封はしたから開けられる。
Ah, everyone can open this, right? I unsealed it so you can open it.
たぶん...たぶん開けれる。
Probably... We can probably open it.
開けれる開けれる。おおー！
We can open it, we can! Ooh!
これね、じゃあみんなこれ今日着てやっていく感じになるかなと思いますんで。
So I think everyone can put this on today and we'll go from there.
はーい！うっし！
Okay! All right!
どれやどれや？
Which one, which one?
ギリーが... / うひょー！ギリー！うひょー！ギリー！
The ghillie... / Whoa! Ghillie! Whoa! Ghillie!
うひょー！ガントレット！
Whoa! Gauntlets!
うひょー！うひょー！ / 靴...頭...
Woohoo! Woohoo! / Boots... Helmet...
で、マインドなんちゃらっていうやつは、なんかステ振りができるアイテムらしいので...
And that Mind-whatever thing is an item that lets you reset your stats,
入って右奥のロッカーの中に入れておきます。
so I'll put it in the locker in the back right as you enter.
なんかね、紫色っぽい粉みたいなやつです。
It's kind of like a purple powder.
はーい！
Okay!
全身やばい！全身やばい！
Look at our whole bodies! Look at us!
みんなゴミ箱マンやで！ / 私は木。
Everyone looks like Trashcan Man! / I am a tree.
ゴミ箱マン？ゴミ箱マンだ！
Trashcan Man? It really is Trashcan Man!
可愛い〜
So cute~
ゴミ箱マンだ。 / 可愛いか？
Trashcan Man. / Is it cute?
じゃあ、割り振りなどをちょっと発表ドラゴンさせてください。
Now then, let me Dragon-Announce our task assignments.
はい！お願いしまーす！ / 発表ドラゴンがー
Yes! Please do! / The Announce Dragon is~
本日は、えっとですね、あのーさっき個別で...
Today, um, earlier in the individual...
個別というか、グループチャットに送った「片付けできるもん.exe」みたいなやつを開いてもらったら...
Well, in the group chat, if you open that "TidyingUp.exe" thing I sent...
大体やりたいことを皆さんに書いてもらったんで...
Everyone wrote down generally what they wanted to do, so...
まず、えっとー原油集めチーム...
First, um, the crude oil gathering team...
ミッションをやる方と...
Those who will do missions, and...
えっと、昨日アルゲンをえーテイムできたので...
Um, since we were able to tame Argentavis yesterday...
キチン・ケラチンを大量に集めていただき、サドルを作る方。
Someone to gather lots of chitin and keratin to craft saddles.
はい
Okay.
と、あとはちょっと恐竜が多くなってきたので...
And next, since we're getting more dinosaurs...
あのカリカリカリカリ拠点に、あの石の恐竜ビッグキャッスルを建てる方。
Someone to build that big stone dinosaur castle at the temporary base.
はい！はい！
Yes! Got it!
と、プラスそこの方は、えーとなんだっけ、ブリーディング？
And in addition, whoever's there, um what was it, breeding?
はい
Yes.
をやりつつ、ちょっとアルゲンを増やしたいと思っております。
Doing that while increasing our Argents, is what I'm thinking.
はい！ほいほい！
Yes! Roger that!
えーっと、一旦仮拠点とブリーディング、アルゲン...
Um, for now, the temporary base and breeding, the Argent...
アルゲン無限編はござるとイナ先輩で請け負います。
The infinite Argentavis arc will be handled by Gozaru and Ina-senpai.
はい！
Okay!
で、キチン・ケラチンの場所が分かるのがフブキ先輩？
And the one who knows where chitin and keratin are is Fubuki-senpai?
うん、行きます！
Yep, I'll go!
ね！フブキ先輩にお任せします。
Right! We'll leave that to Fubuki-senpai.
はい、じゃあぼたんちゃんについて行きます。
All right, I'll follow Botan-chan.
あーい、しろいくぜー。
All right, Shiro, let's go.
はい。
Okay.
そしたらトワ先輩が昨日なんかやりたいって言ってた、な、何でしたっけ？原油？原油じゃない、なんだっけな？
So, Towa-senpai, what was it you said you wanted to do yesterday? Crude oil? No, not oil, what was it?
あ、常闇はね、真珠と原油ポンプ担当いたしますよ。
Ah, Tokoyami will be in charge of pearls and oil pumps.
あ、お願いします。なんかウサちゃんがいっぱい荷物持てるって聞いて。
Ah, please do! I heard Usa-chan can carry a lot of stuff.
そう、ウサちゃんが持てるんで。行ってきますよ、もういいですか？
Yeah, Usa-chan can carry it. I'm heading out, are you ready?
じゃあ各地物資を… / はーい。
Then let's collect supplies all around... / Okay!
本日よろしくお願いします！
Let's do our best today!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Let's do this!
しゃっしゃっしゃっしゃっ
Sha sha sha sha sha!
じゃあぼいちゃんに行くか。 / ぼいちゃんいいね。
Well then, let's go to Boichan. / Boichan sounds good.
じゃあイナ先輩、このままで、はい、こっちに一緒に行きましょう。
Then Ina-senpai, just like this, let's head over this way together.
おーい。よし。
Okay. All right.
あ、トワ、トワだったけど…まあ。
Ah, it was Towa, but... oh well.
あ、トワ先輩、もし…
Ah, Towa-senpai, if...
仲間に入れてー
Let me join in~
…いてくれるのであれば、ござる、全ロスが怖くてギリースーツを置いていく人です。
...if you can stay with me, Gozaru is the type of person who leaves her ghillie suit behind because she's scared of losing everything.
ギリースーツね。
Leaving the ghillie suit, huh.
怖い！怖すぎるー！
It's scary! Too scary!
え、私も、なんか安全な場所に…
Yeah, me too, I'll just put it in a safe place...
怖いですよね、あれ。
That really is scary, isn't it?
そしたらちょっと昨日のあれで…
So, following up on what we did yesterday...
なんかイナ先輩、 / はい。
So Ina-senpai, / Yes?
どうやらアルゲンを…あ、待って、もう1回テレポートします。すみません。ええっと…
Apparently the Argen... Ah, wait, I'll teleport one more time. Sorry. Um...
アルゲンを… / あ、ちょっと待って、ミスったかな。
The Argen... / Ah, wait a second, did I mess up?
昨日捕まえたじゃないですか。 / はい。
We caught one yesterday, right? / Yes.
それをね、増やしつつ、なんかアルゲンを5体倒すっていうミッションがあるらしくって、
While breeding more of those, there's apparently a mission to defeat five Argens,
もしかして…うちのアルゲンを…？
Don't tell me... our Argens...?
ま、産んで、殺せば達成するらしくて。
Well, apparently if we breed them and kill them, it counts.
ごめんね、本当に。産んでやる。
I'm really sorry. But I'll breed them for it.
産んで、やっちまえば…
Breed them, and then take them down...
「生贄だからー！」って。
Like, "You're a sacrifice!"
…って思って。なんで、今日なんですけど、 / はい。
...is what I was thinking. So for today, / Yes.
1番最初に、昨日みたいにあそこでアルゲンをちょっとテイムしつつ、
first off, like yesterday, while taming some Argens over there,
あっちでアルゲンのブリーディングを同時にしようと思って。
I was thinking of breeding Argens at the same time over that way.
ああ、いいですね。
Ah, that sounds good.
ね。なんで、昨日で言うと…待って、でもプテラはまだ今手元にありますか？
Right? So based on yesterday... Wait, do you still have a Ptera on hand?
えーっと…あの、ここですよね？多分けど、入れた…あれ？
Um... It was here, right? I think I put it in... Huh?
あ、そうそうそう。昨日入れたのはね、ここだと思う。
Ah, right, right. I think you put it in here yesterday.
どこ行った？ / 隣のところ？
Where did it go? / The one next to it?
なんか居ます？このハウス…
Is there one here? In this house...
ここに…
In here...
アルジェント… / もしかして入れてない？もしかして。
Argento... / Could it be you didn't put it in?
ないですね。
It's not here.
あ、じゃあ、じゃあ…えーっと、
Ah, then, then... Um,
これ何だっけ？
What was this again?
もしかして誰かが持ってログアウトしてる気が…
I feel like maybe someone logged out while carrying it...
ああ、なるほど。 / …可能性アリなので、
Ah, I see. / ...is a possibility, so,
これはアンキロか。あ、じゃあこれだ。
This is an Ankylo. Ah, then this is it.
今日これに、今日はイナ先輩に乗ってもらって、
Today, I'll have Ina-senpai ride this one,
アタックZERO…
Attack ZERO...
アタックZEROに乗ってもらって昨日みたいにやりつつ、 / はい。
having you ride Attack ZERO and doing things like yesterday, / Yes.
向こうでブリーディングもしよう。 / はい。
while we also breed over there. / Yes.
なんで、ちょっとだけ木とかが必要なのかな？石の土台とか作りたいな。
So, I guess we need a little wood and such? I'd like to make some stone foundations.
ちょっとお待ちください。石…石…
Please wait a moment. Stone... stone...
これも整理しなきゃなあ。
I need to organize this too.
ギリーちょっと怖いのでここに…入れとこうかな。
Ghillie is a bit scary, so maybe I'll put it in here...
確かに。いや、分かる。めっちゃ怖いですよね、あれこれね。
Indeed. No, I get it. All this stuff is super scary, right?
じゃ、ここ…これに…落として…
Well then, here... into this... drop it...
ほいであ…イナのギリーはここに…
And then... Ina's ghillie goes here...
えっと、スタックを半分に分けて… / はい。
Um, split the stack in half... / Yes.
はい！そしたら…
Okay! Then...
じゃあ、行きましょう。このアタックZEROに乗ってもらっていいですか？ / はい。
All right, let's go. Could you ride this Attack ZERO? / Okay.
で、今日先輩たちが恐らくアルゲンを捕まえてきてくれるので、
And today, our senpais will probably catch Argens for us,
あ、アルゲンのサドル用に…きてくれるので、 / はい。
ah, for the Argen saddles... since they'll be bringing them, / Okay.
あの、キチン・ケラチンを、それを使って色々やりましょう。
let's use the chitin and keratin to make various things.
よいせ、よいせ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
え、私が走っても大丈夫ですしよ？
Um, it's totally fine for me to run instead, you know?
全然全然全然！ござる場所覚えてるから。ただクマ居るからさ、気をつけて。
Not at all, not at all! Gozaru remembers the way. But there are bears, so be careful.
あった、あった。
Found it, found it.
え、待って、なんか近くにでっかい…あ、でもあれ草食か。あれ草食だな。
Wait, there's a huge one near... Ah, but is that a herbivore? That's a herbivore.
お、でっかい。
Oh, it's huge.
なんかお魚っぽい。
It kind of looks like a fish.
お魚っぽい、確かに！平たい。
Like a fish, definitely! It's flat.
じゃあここで
So here,
お世話を...
to take care of...
卵をまず産まなきゃいけないから
First, they need to lay eggs, so...
ちょっとブリーディング用の簡易施設を作りたくて、まず
First, I'd like to build a simple facility for breeding.
はい
Okay.
ええっと...
Umm...
石の壁...
Stone wall...
石の土台...
Stone foundation...
で、めっちゃ昨日イナ先輩が取ってくれたから
And since Ina-senpai gathered a lot yesterday,
素材はうちはまあ今んとこ潤沢にあ、あるはず
we should have plenty of materials for now, ah, hopefully.
いや、必要だったらもう行きますので
No, if you need anything, I'll go get it.
助かるー！
That helps so much!
え、じゃあ焚き火作っ...焚き...あ、たいまつだっけ？焚き火、焚き火作ってもらっていいですか？
Um, then could you make a campfire... camp... Ah, was it a torch? A campfire, could you make a campfire for me?
焚き火？
Campfire?
焚き火。たい、キャンプファイヤーっていうのかな
A campfire. Camp... campfire, I think it's called.
ああー
Ah.
ええっと、英語が雑魚くてごめ...うぅ...
Um, sorry my English is so bad... ugh...
あ、なんかざ...
Ah, kind of...
え、なんか気絶した！くそ、やばい、また水が...
Wait, she passed out! Shoot, oh no, water again...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
お水飲んでなくて気絶しちゃった！
I passed out because I didn't drink water!
ああー！大丈夫ですか？
Aah! Are you alright?
た、た、た、訪れ...
Ta, ta, ta, otozure...
あ、なんかそのうち、お、起きる...お、起きて...起きて...
Ah, soon... will wake up... W-Wake up... wake up...
意外と...
Unexpectedly...
あとご飯入れとか無きゃ
Also need to put some food in.
水筒いっぱい作んなきゃ。え、イナ先輩、この中にね
I need to make a lot of waterskins. Um, Ina-senpai, inside here,
はい
Yes.
このご飯をパック半分にして入れとくんで、これで今日のご飯として
I'll split this food stack in half and put it in, so for today's food...
あ、ご飯はいっぱい...あ、いや、もう...
Ah, as for food, there's plenty... Ah, wait, it's already...
あ、腐っちゃったのかな
Ah, maybe it spoiled.
腐っ...かも！もう腐った！
Spoiled... maybe! It's already rotten!
え、かも？
Eh, maybe?
あ、なんかちょっと戻って、水とあの木とちょっと持ってきます
Ah, I'll head back for a bit and bring some water and wood.
確かに水筒を持ってきてもらえると大変助かります
Indeed, it would be a huge help if you could bring a waterskin.
はい。じゃあ行ってきます
Okay. Well, I'm off.
はい、じゃあこっちで今のブリーディング施設を作りますね、ござるが
Okay, then I'll make the breeding facility here in the meantime, gozaru.
天井、天井...まず...
Ceiling, ceiling... first...
人間は脆い
Humans are frail.
人間だ。体が弱すぎる。あまりにも...
Humans. Their bodies are way too weak. Far too...
ですよねー
Right?
こいつらの体が弱い！
Their bodies are weak!
給水樽みたいなのね、水筒にしか頼れないからな
Like water barrels, we can only rely on waterskins.
人は脆い
People are frail.
ええ、で...
Um, and...
これ...を、これも...
This... and this too...
おいしょ、おいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
天井って4つで1個なの？
Are ceilings four for one?
あ、ここにもあっ、ありました。あの、恐竜...
Ah, here too, there was... Um, the dinos...
誰かが...はい。誰かが入れてました
Someone... Yes. Someone put them in.
あ、連れてきてもらえるとウチのアタック...アタックZEROを
Ah, if you could bring them, our Attack... Attack ZERO.
アタックZEROと行きます
I'll go with Attack ZERO.
アタック、アタックZEROを何卒よろしくお願いします
Attack, please take good care of Attack ZERO.
パイパー、か...
Piper, huh...
ちょ、あまりにも牢獄みたいな見た目してるけど大丈夫かな、これ？
Uh, it looks way too much like a prison cell, is this going to be okay?
大丈夫ですよ
It'll be fine.
行けるかな？すごい牢獄みたいな見た目になっちゃった！
Will it work? It turned out looking completely like a prison!
あまりにもちょっと...
It's just way too...
流石にバッドか。流石にだ、ダメか、これは許...
Is it bad after all? As expected, is this no good...?
大丈夫ですよ
It's fine!
そうだよね
Right?
なんか、ちょっと...
Like, a little...
ちょっと...
A bit...
デザインは大事じゃない
Design isn't what matters.
ちょっと狭い...
A bit cramped...
そう！見た目じゃない！性能なんだ！
That's right! Looks don't matter! It's about performance!
見た目じゃないですよね、イナ先輩！
It's not about looks, right, Ina-senpai!
うん、うん、そう
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
よかった、イナ先輩...
Thank goodness, Ina-senpai...
心が広い人だ、助かる
She's so open-minded, what a lifesaver.
よっし、じゃあこれで焚き火を...
All right, so with this, the campfire...
え、え、え、え、え、何？何？誰？
Wait, wait, wait, what? What? Who is it?!
中いる？
Is something inside?
な、え、何かなんかめっちゃでかいやつが...
Wha- There's something huge...!
え、え、え...
Wait, wait, wait...
え、逃げて、逃げて。全然逃げて。大丈夫。
Wait, run away, run! Just run away, it's fine.
え、や、やった、アタック、アタックゼロが...
Wait, Attack, Attack Zero is...
戦っちゃった？
Did it start fighting?
え、え...
Eh, eh...
ふぉ、フォロー、フォロー、フォロー...
Fo- Follow, follow, follow...
フォロー...
Follow...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫かな...
I wonder if I'm okay...
え、どっから来た？いててててて！
Wait, where did it come from? Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
アタックゼロどこ？マジで。
Where is Attack Zero? Seriously.
あんたは何をやって...
What are you doing...
いててててて！
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
あああー！
Aaaaah!
やっべえ！
Shoot!
見えなかった！
I couldn't see it!
どっから来た？
Where did it come from?
アタックゼロどこ？
Where is Attack Zero?
ちょっと飛んだかも。え、ここどこ？
I might have flown off a bit. Wait, where is this?
ドアはこっち...
The door is this way...
アタックゼロ多分回収でき...
Attack Zero can probably be retrieved...
大丈夫ですか？
Are you alright?
行けた。
I got out.
え、ここどこ？
Wait, where is this?
やばい、ヨウシドンが戦っちゃってんなこれ。ちょっと待って。
Oh no, Yoshidon's fighting it. Hold on.
よし、ちょっちょっちょっちょ...
Yoshi, wait wait wait...
あれ？ちょっとこっち来て、こっち。
Huh? Hey, come over here, this way.
ヨシドン、来て。
Yoshidon, come on.
待って、ちょっと待って？
Wait, wait a second?
あれ？ここどこ？
Huh? Where is this?
ヨシドンどこ行ったあいつ？あ、行って...
Where did Yoshidon go? Ah, go...
ちょちょちょちょ、ヨシドン来て！
Wait wait wait, Yoshidon, come here!
居た居た居た居た！
There he is, there he is!
ヨシドンおいで。よし。
Yoshidon, come here. Good.
めっちゃ遠い場所に...
In such a far away place...
いや、アタックゼロがどこ行ったかわからないけど、ヨシドンを保護します。
Well, I don't know where Attack Zero went, but I'll protect Yoshidon.
あれ？拠点が襲われてしまった...
Huh? Our base got attacked...
ちょっと待って。
Hold on.
ヨシドン、着地してー。
Yoshidon, land please.
今度2階...
Now the second floor...
ここどこー？
Where is this?!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
めっちゃ遠い場所に...
In such a far away place...
あ、集会場に戻ってきてくれたら...
Ah, if you can come back to the gathering area...
いや、行ける... 行けるかどうか分からない！
No, can I make it... I don't even know if I can get there!
何？ちょっと待って。
What? Hold on.
いや、ここで死んでもさ、あの... アイテムはまだ死んだ場所にあるんですよね？
Well, even if I die here, um... my items will still be where I died, right?
あ、そうそう、あるある。けどね、ドラゴンくらいかな。やばい、ここやばいな。
Ah, yeah, yeah, they stay. But it's about... Oh man, this place is bad.
じゃあ死んでもいいかも。なんか別の... 島にいる...
Then dying might be fine. I feel like I'm on a different... island...
別の島にいる？やばい。ちょっと待って、こいつを...
On a different island? That's bad. Hold on, let me...
じゃあ、引き離しチーム...
Then, lure-away team...
ほら！
Take that!
あ、キリヤネンがチェイスしてくれてる。
Ah, Kiriyanen is chasing it away.
よしよしよし、これで...
Good, good, good, with this...
え、誰か死んだ？
Wait, did someone die?
あ、ござるござる。え、でも全然平気。これね、ちょっとベッドでリスポーンして...
Ah, it was me, Gozaru. But I'm totally fine! I'll just respawn at the bed and...
戻ってきちゃった？
Did they come back?
うわっ、旋盤が...
Ugh, the Fabricator is...
ちょっと待って、壊されちゃった...
Wait a minute, it got destroyed...
あ、ここか。シンプルベッド。
Ah, here it is. Simple bed.
旋盤が... 旋盤が...
The Fabricator... The Fabricator...
あ、シンプルベッドで...
Ah, at the simple bed...
ああ、よかった！
Ah, thank goodness!
なんか別のところにカーソルがあって...
The cursor was on a different spot...
ああ、よかった。
Ah, what a relief.
ちょっと待って、一回旋盤が壊れちゃったんで、ちょっと下に行ってきますね。
Hold on, since the Fabricator broke, I'm going to head downstairs real quick.
はい。
Okay.
え、あそこって誰かめっちゃ戦ってる？
Wait, is someone fighting really hard over there?
ええ、アイテムどこかな？この辺？
Now then, where are my items? Around here?
かと思うけど...
...I think, but...
あ、いや、こっちじゃない。
Ah, no, not this way.
あ、これか。
Ah, is this it?
ああ、よかった！よかったー。
Ah, thank goodness! What a relief.
いやー、怖い。
Man, that was scary.
お、戦ってる。
Oh, they're fighting.
えっと...
Let's see...
あっ... なぁ...
Ah... no...
大丈夫かな...
Are they okay, I wonder...
戦おう？
Should I fight?
え？見ないで、私を見ないで。
Huh? Don't look, don't look at me.
どっか行け...
Go away...
見た？
Did it see me?
見たぁぁぁ！
It saw meee!
なんでぇぇ...
Whyyy...
戦ってる。
They're fighting.
怖い...
Scary...
怖いよ。
I'm scared.
どうする？
What should I do?
手伝う？
Should I help?
I am... I am... I am tree.
怖い...
Scary...
大丈夫かな...
Are they okay, I wonder...
イナ先輩...
Ina-senpai...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
今ちょっと、拠点、大ピンチすぎて...
Right now, the base is in super huge trouble, so...
はい。
Yes.
今ね、全力で拠点からあのデカいやつを離そうと頑張ってる最中です。
Right now, we're desperately trying to lure that huge thing away from base.
はい、私も...
Yes, I also...
みんなで。
Together with everyone.
ヤツ... TONDERUで？
With... with Tonderu?
ね、飛んであげてー。
Yeah, go fly him over!
じゃ、OK。
Then, okay.
行く行く。
On my way, on my way.
やば、草食動物に釣られてんのか、これ...
Oh no, is it being lured by herbivores...?
頼む、こっち来てくれ！
Please, come over here!
て、くれ... な、なんか違うやつ来た！
Ple- Wait, something different showed up!
トンで...
Ton-de...
お前じゃないやねーん！
Not youuu!
テラバ来ちゃったー！
A Therizino cameee!
あ、でもだいぶ行ったか？
Ah, but did it go pretty far?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
いや、もう違うね、弱い弱い動物をこう、餌に連れてきてみたんだけど...
No, I tried bringing other weak animals as bait, but...
違うの連れちゃったー。シンプルベッド、いやー。
I lured the wrong thing. Simple bed, nooo.
鳥やーん！
It's a bird!
大丈夫ですかね...
Are they okay, I wonder...
大丈夫か... あ、でも結構上まで連れてってくれた！
Is it okay... Ah, but it lured it pretty far up!
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
いや、ホントびっくりしました、なんか...
Man, I was really surprised by that...
ね、びっくりした！
Right? I was surprised!
焦った、さすがに！
I totally panicked!
結構上まで連れてってくれたっぽいな。
Looks like it lured it pretty far up.
これ旋盤の中身とか消えた？
Did the contents of the fabricator disappear or something?
あ、旋盤の中身はですね、あの左の1個だけ孤立してるチェストに入れときました、全部。
Ah, the fabricator contents, I put them all in that one isolated chest on the left.
あ、ありがたーい！
Ah, thank you so much!
プテラ2匹がいったん入ってます、そこに。
Two Pteranodons are temporarily in there.
あ、了解！お願いしまーす。
Ah, roger! Please do.
あいよー。
Alrighty.
ほいじゃ、これでそのプテラを1匹失ったんですけど...
Alright, so we lost one Pteranodon with that, but...
その代わりにプテラがさっき1匹保護できたので...
instead, we were able to rescue one Pteranodon just now, so...
はい。
Yes.
そして... そいつを使ってやりましょう。
And... let's use that one.
そしたら、イナ先輩、歩きでめっちゃ申し訳ないですけど、さっきのとこ戻って...
So, Ina-senpai, I'm super sorry it's on foot, but if you could head back to where we were...
え、これプテラ乗ってんのか？
Wait, is this Ptera being ridden?
私のプテラ使ってください！
Please use my Ptera!
ありがとー
Thank you~
あとね、もう一匹ね、プテラなんか
Also, for the other Ptera,
多分その辺で捕まえれば大丈夫です
it'll probably be fine if we just tame one around there.
一匹、え、生きてる？元気、その子？
One of them... wait, is it alive? Is it doing well?
その子が元気だったら一番！
It's best if that one's healthy!
その子が元気なのが一番助かります
That one being healthy helps out the most.
はい
Yeah.
よし、じゃあさっきのところちょっと集合で
Alright, let's meet up where we were earlier.
何が要るんだっけ... えっと、あったあったあった...
What did I need again? Um, here it is, here it is...
いやでも良かった、イナ先輩のプテラが見つかったのナイスです
But I'm glad! It's awesome that your Ptera was found, Ina-senpai.
はい
Yep.
ストーンに、あった。オッケーオッケー
Stone, and... got it. Okay, okay.
いやー、びっくりした、はは
Man, that was a surprise, haha.
いやびっくりっしょ！マジでビッ... あ？
Right? Totally surprising! Seriously surpr... Huh?
なんか平和で...
It's so peaceful...
待って、え？嘘、待って。なんかいる？
Wait, what? No way, hold on. Is something there?
なんだ？
What is it?
わっ、キチン・ケラチンだ！お前キチン・ケラチンだろ！
Woah, chitin and keratin! You have chitin and keratin, right?!
え？
Huh?
トワ様恐竜出したいんだけど...
Towa-sama, I want to deploy a dino, but...
来た来た来た！
Here it comes, here it comes!
来た！キチン・ケラチン発見！
It's here! Chitin and keratin spotted!
おー
Ooh.
飛んできた、キチン・ケラチンが！
It flew over, the chitin and keratin!
ケラチン飛んできた、嬉しい！
Keratin flew over! I'm so happy!
おーー
Ooh--
置いてけ、置いてけ置いてけ
Lure it away, lure it away, lure it away!
大丈夫かー？
Are you okay?
あ、何とか！
Ah, managing somehow!
あの、拠点、拠点の近くにでかいやつの肉食が来ちゃって...
Um, a huge carnivore showed up near the base...
めちゃくちゃいるやん、あいつ。どうする？
There's a ton of them! What should we do?
どうしますー？
What should we do?
トワがちょっと追っ払うわ。ちょっと待っててね
Towa will go chase them off. Just wait a sec, okay?
うん、なんかデカ罠作ってハメてもいいかなって思ってた。
Yeah, I was thinking we could build a big trap and catch it.
入るのかな？
Wonder if it'll go in?
トワがね、いや、引き寄せとくわ
Towa will... no, I'll draw its attention.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
じゃあイナ先輩こっちでやりましょう。
Then let's do this over here, Ina-senpai.
レッツミッション！
Let's mission!
来た来た来た来た
Here it comes, here it comes...
149か。虫がいたら勝ったな
149, huh? If there are insects, we've won.
おーい、こっち来い！
Hey, come over here!
おーい！
Hey!
来た来た来た来た
Here it comes, here it comes!
2匹いて草！
There are two of them, lol!
ぐっ... 2匹いて草！
Gah... There are two of them, lol!
ヤバすぎー！
That's crazy!
命大事にで
Prioritize your safety!
2匹笑った！
Two of them is hilarious!
何やねん2匹て！
What do you mean two of them?!
じゃあー
Alright then...
いや、3匹！
Wait, three of them!
すっごい遠くに、仮、仮、仮、仮拠点が有りまして...
Way out far away, there is a temp, temp, temp, temporary base...
ちょ、あの早くこっち... あ、こっち来てる。ヤバいヤバい
Wait, um, hurry over... Ah, they're coming this way. Oh no, oh no.
こいつか
This one?
この虫がケラチンの？
This bug has keratin?
あ、そう。虫殺すと、ケラチン...
Ah, yeah. When you kill the bugs, keratin...
いや、いらんねんこいつ。ふざけんなこいつ、もうふざけんなこいつ
No, I don't want this guy! Screw you, seriously screw you!
ね、なんか、え？ねねねね、イナ先輩、イナ先輩！
Hey, wait, huh? Hey hey hey, Ina-senpai, Ina-senpai!
はいはい
Yes, yes?
あそこあそこあそこ！あそこなんかアルゲンいる。
Over there, over there! There's an Argentavis over there!
あ、あいついっぺん捕まえたって良くない？あれ
Hey, shouldn't we try taming that one?
ですね
Right.
行きます？
Shall we go?
レッ、レッツチェイス、レッツチェイス！
Let's, let's chase, let's chase!
オッケーオッケーオッケー
Okay, okay, okay.
おーい！
Hey!
じゃあ、レッツゴーレッツゴー
Alright, let's go, let's go!
行きます
Going in!
はーい
Okay!
来いよー！
Come on over!
はーい
Okay!
お前が挟まるんかい！クソ、こいつ邪魔すぎる。ブロウバックとかいうやつ
You're the one getting stuck?! Damn it, you're so in the way! This "blowback" thing or whatever.
なんでやねん！今トワが罠作ったのにー！もうなんでだよ！
Why?! Towa just made a trap! Man, why?!
え、行きます
Um, going in!
レッツゴーレッツゴー！カモンカモーン！
Let's go, let's go! Come on, come on!
おーー
Ooh--
レッツゴー
Let's go!
本当にすごいとこだ、ここ。
This place is seriously amazing.
カモーーーン！
Comooooon!
ナーーーイス！
Niiiiiice!
ま、ちょっと離れたからもういいでしょう
Well, it got a bit further away, so we should be good now.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
もうちょっとだけね。また来たら追っ払うわ
Just for a bit longer. If it comes back, I'll chase it off again.
助かります
That helps a lot!
で、私は、えーーっと
And for me, ummm...
ここ見てー
Look over here~
やばい、ちょっと... こっち見てー
Oh no, wait... Look this way~
ははは！「ここ見て」
Hahaha! "Look over here."
カモーーーン！
Comooooon!
入った！ナイス！
It's in! Nice!
ご飯
Food.
ナイスー！よし
Nice! Alright.
オッケーオッケー。そしたら、この... あっ
Okay, okay. And then, this... Ah.
あっ？
Huh?
あ、もうこいつ、こいつこいつ！これこれこれ！これ斧でこうやってやるとね...
Ah, this guy, this guy, this guy! This one! If you hit it with an axe like this...
お、なんか分かりやすいとこに
Oh, right somewhere easy to spot.
弱い、こいつは
It's weak, this guy.
で、これで... こう殴ると
And then with this... if you hit it like this...
あれ？待って、旋盤ってどこ行った？
Huh? Wait, where did the fabricator go?
旋盤が破壊されたんです、奴に。
The fabricator was destroyed by that thing.
オッケー
Okay.
そうなんです、悲しみ...
Yeah, so sad...
あ、で、中身は左の倉庫っていうか、あのチェストに全部入れてあります。
Ah, but the contents were put into the storage on the left, or rather, into that chest.
ほっ... と
Ph... ew.
オッケー
Okay.
苦しい... ごめんなさい...
It hurts... I'm so sorry...
守れなくて...
I couldn't protect it...
こいつと、水晶...
This one, and crystal...
と、インゴットとセメント...
And ingots and cement...
なるほど
I see.
水晶...
Crystals...
えっと、水晶...
Um, crystals...
よし、来た！交配レッツゴー！
All right, here we go! Mating, let's go!
お！
Oh!
おお！卵！
Ooh! An egg!
卵来た！え、それを回収して...
The egg is here! Pick that up and...
拾ったっし...
I picked it up...
あ、そうそうそう、このモヤモヤのやつ、イナ先輩これ拾ってきて...
Ah, right, right, this glowing one. Ina-senpai, pick this up...
はい
Okay.
で、これで...
And with this...
この、ちょっと一酸化炭素中毒になりそうな場所すぎるんですけど...
This place looks a bit too much like a carbon monoxide poisoning hazard, but...
ここで...
In here...
おお、はいはいはいはい。
Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes.
え、狭いか？もしかして狭い？
Eh, is it cramped? Maybe too cramped?
え、多分この中に入れたら多分...
Um, if you put it inside here, maybe...
この中どこか適当にポンって置いたらあったかくなるんじゃないかな？
If you just drop it anywhere in here, it might warm up?
ここでドロップ？
Drop it here?
フブちゃん作ってくれてるの？
Did Fubu-chan make this?
ドロップ
Drop it.
おお！おお！
Oh! Whoa!
卵燃えてる、見た目的に！
Visually, the egg is on fire!
なんか美味しい匂いが...ん？
I smell something delicious... hm?
美味しい匂いが...え、熱いって言われた！
A delicious smell... Wait, it says it's too hot!
消火した！
I put it out!
え、待って。
Wait.
熱いって言われた、ちょっと待って。
It said it's too hot, hold on.
この中なだけでいいのでは？もしかして。
Maybe just being inside this room is enough? Perhaps.
受精卵これだ、これを...
Here's the fertilized egg, this one...
ドロップ
Drop.
どうですか？
How is it?
え、なんかやばいやつが来たかも？
Uh, did a dangerous one just show up?
やばいやつだねー。
It's definitely a dangerous one.
あれ、誘導するか？
Should we lure it away?
します？ちょっと...
Shall we? Um...
飛び場所に...
To the take-off spot...
どうしてこんなに...
Why are there so many...
お、戦ってる？
Oh, are they fighting?
戦ってる。逃げていいかも全然。
They're fighting. We might be able to just run.
あ、テイムが...
Ah, the tame...
お！
Oh!
ビルゲンも回収しとこう。
Let's retrieve Bergen too.
こいつが早よテイム終われー
Hurry up and finish taming!
あ、でもなんか向こうに行きましたね。
Ah, but it went over that way.
向こう行った。
It went over there.
拠点の方戻るとでもちょっと...危ないかも。
Going back to base might be a bit dangerous, though.
そうですね。
Yeah.
怖い...
Scary...
ねー。
Yeah.
あ、戻った！戻った戻った！
Ah, it's back! It's back, it's back!
戻った...戻ってきた！ちょっと隠れて...
It came back! Hide for a sec...
イナ先輩、シンプルなベッドって作れますか？
Ina-senpai, can you make a Simple Bed?
なんかテイムできました。名前どうします？
It looks like it's tamed. What should we name it?
あ、名前決めちゃっていいですよ。
Ah, feel free to name it whatever you like!
アルジェント1...
Argent 1...
アルゲン
Argen
あ、やばい。
Ah, oh no.
ここ拾えるかな、まだ。
Can I still pick it up from here?
あ、拾える。
Ah, I can.
え？どうしよう。
Eh? What should we do?
どうしよう、どんな感じ？
What should we do? How is it looking?
あ、でもまあまあまあ... 今は大丈夫っぽいですけど...
Ah, but well... It seems fine for now, but...
ちょっと近い、また... やばいやつが。
It's a bit close again... that dangerous one.
なんかアルゲンの子供いて草。
There's an Argen baby, lol.
こっち。
This way.
うん、オッケーオッケー。
Yeah, okay, okay.
通じた、通じた、通じた。
It went through, it worked, it worked.
エホ、エホ
Huff, puff...
あれ？
Huh?
オッケー、ナイスナイスナイスナイス。ふう。
Okay, nice, nice, nice, nice. Phew.
オッケ、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
よし、ブリーディング頑張りましょう、こいつの。
Alright, let's do our best with breeding this one.
はい。
Yeah.
こいつ...気候どうしてあげたらいいんだ？
How should we adjust the temperature for this guy?
なんか丁度良くしてあげないと...
If we don't make it just right...
なんか、卵が孵らないみたいで...
It looks like the egg won't hatch...
ああ。
Ah.
この子。で、今...あ、ちょっと熱いみたい。
This one. And right now... ah, it looks like it's a bit too hot.
え？熱すぎる？
Huh? It's too hot?
そう、熱いみたいだから...
Yeah, it looks like it's too hot, so...
ちょっと涼しい所に連れて行かないといけないらしくて。
apparently we need to take it somewhere cooler.
あ、じゃあ、あの山のところ...
Ah, then maybe by that mountain...
あ、確かに。え、ちょっと危なさそうだなぁ。
Ah, true. Wait, that looks a bit dangerous.
ですよね。
Doesn't it?
一緒に行くか。
Shall we go together?
え、ちょっとレッツゴー、レッツゴー。
Let's go, let's go.
うわぁ！見つけた！
Whoa! It found me!
やばい、見つかった！
Oh no, I've been spotted!
逃げろー！
Run!
私たちもちょっと...
We should also...
我々が見つかった！
We've been spotted!
逃げてー！飛んじゃって飛んじゃって！飛んでる？どこ行った？
Run! Fly away, fly away! Is it flying? Where did it go?
飛んでる、飛んでるちょっとカプセルに...
It's flying, wait, into the cryopod...
入ったんじゃない？ワンチャン。あ、入った！待って！痛っ！
Maybe it went in? Ah, it did! Wait! Ow!
これ、ドア閉めれば行ける！
If we close the door, we're good!
え、なんか別のやつが私を追いかけてる！
Wait, another one is chasing after me!
いやー！ちょっと入れてみた。
Nooo! I managed to put it inside.
気絶しないかな、ワンチャン。
Wonder if it'll get knocked out.
麻酔矢持ってますか？
Do you have tranq arrows?
持ってます！でも別のやつに...別のやつに...
I do! But another one... another one is...
あ、オッケオッケ！
Ah, okay, okay!
うわぁ！やばい！死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ...あ、死んだー！
Whoa! No! I'm gonna die die die... Ah, I died!
オーマイガー！
Oh my god!
やばい...
Oh no...
あ、飛んでる、飛んでるのか。なるほど、飛んでるが飛んでるんですね。
Ah, flying? So it is flying. I see, "Tonderu" is flying.
飛んでる...飛んでないです。あの、カプセルに入れていました。
It's flying—no, it's not. Um, I put it into a capsule.
カプセルに入れた？はい。
In a capsule? Yes.
また違うやつか。めんどくせぇ。
Another different one? What a pain.
え、でも走って戻れる...多分。
But I can run back... probably.
えっと、シンプル...
Umm, simple...
いやー、やばいところ...
Man, what a dangerous place...
やっべ、バレピー！
Oh crap, I got spotted!
バレたんですか？やばい！
You got spotted? Oh no!
バレちゃったー。
I was spotted~.
いやー。
Oh no.
カルノタウルスにバレた。
A Carnotaurus spotted me.
まあでもシンプルベッドで...
Well, but at the simple bed...
クマ...クマも頑張る。
Bear... The bear will try its best too.
ま、実質ダメージゼロ！
Well, virtually zero damage!
置けなかった...
Couldn't place it...
いや、もし...もしも、ここやばい...
No, what if... what if this place is bad...
この辺一帯ちょっとレベルが強いですよね。
The levels around this area are pretty tough, aren't they?
原油ポンプ、げ- 原油ポンプ、えー、設置完了しましたー。
Oil pump, oi- oil pump, um, installation complete~.
ありがとうございまーす。
Thank you very much~!
ちょっとアクシデントが発生しまして。
A bit of an accident happened.
うん。アルゲンの罠にユティラが入ってしまって、今麻酔矢撃ったらワンチャン気絶してテイムができます。
Yeah. A Yutyrannus got into the Argent trap, so if we shoot tranq arrows now, we might knock it out and tame it.
いいよ、いいよ、いいよ、いいよ...いいやん！行こうや！そっち合流しようか？
Nice, nice, nice, nice... That's great! Let's go! Should we meet up over there?
ちょっと来てもらえますか？
Could you come over for a bit?
はい、今、今の...
Yes, right now...
アルゲンT1っていう名前がついた、この近くにいます。
I'm near the one named "Argen T1."
オッケーオッケー、行くわ。ちょっと整理したらすぐ行くわ。
Okay okay, I'm coming. I'll head over right after sorting out my stuff.
で、カルノがめっちゃいて、近くに1匹。
And there are tons of Carnos, one nearby.
え？
Huh?
カルノもいて、実は。なかなかヤバくって...
There's a Carno too, actually. It's pretty dangerous...
もう消えたかな...？
Did it disappear already...?
まだいる...まだいます。
Still there... It's still here.
何か私達にできることある？
Is there anything we can do?
飛べる...飛べる人がいれば、こいつを誘導して離す...
If someone can fly... lead this guy away...
飛べる、飛べる！
I can fly, I can fly!
あと、麻酔矢かな。麻酔矢があると助かる。
Also, tranq arrows. Tranq arrows would really help.
私持ってます！
I have some!
よ、よし。
Al-alright.
じゃあ飛んで...
Then I'll fly...
麻酔矢ね。
Tranq arrows, right?
麻酔矢が欲しいです。
We need tranq arrows.
オッケー。麻酔矢ね、ちょっと作るわ。
Okay. Tranq arrows, right? I'll make some.
お前飛びすぎ、飛びすぎ！
Hey, you're flying way too far, way too far!
こいつ寝かせたらいいんですか？
Should we knock this one out?
あ、誰かの...
Ah, someone's...
なんかいる。
Something's there.
飛べる？
Can I fly?
なぜこんなにいるのか...
Why are there so many of them...?
なんだったっけな、やべ、作り方忘れちゃったわ。
What was it again? Shoot, I forgot the recipe.
イナ先輩。
Ina-senpai.
はい。
Yes?
39本で足りるか？
Will 39 be enough?
石を持ってきてくれませんか？
Could you bring some stone?
石？
Stone?
うん、拠点から。
Yeah, from the base.
え、1個ずつ？
Wait, one each?
1スタック、500個のまとまりを1つ。
One stack, one bundle of 500.
500個...
500...
まずは、あの...
First, um...
くー、ハット...
Guh, hat...
ここに来てる、来てる来てる来てる！飛んでる！飛んでる！
It's coming here, coming, coming! It's flying! Flying!
行って！うわー、いるわ！
Go! Whoa, it's there!
こっち！
This way!
ゴザルチェイスするわ。ゴザルチェイスする。
I'll chase Gozaru. I'll chase Gozaru.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
あ、行ける、チェイス。行ける行ける！
Ah, I can chase. I got this, I got this!
石持ってくるね。石持ってくるよ、じゃあ。
I'll bring some stone. I'll bring stone then.
なんか罠使ってこいつの...作ってこいつをハメようかなって思ったんですけど、
I was thinking of making a trap and trapping this guy, but...
ああ、石持ってくる？
Ah, should I bring stone?
ゴザルがチェイスできてるからワンチャンいいかも、大丈夫かも。
Gozaru is chasing it, so it might be fine, might be okay.
大丈夫？
Are you sure?
オッケー。とりあえず合流するよ。
Okay. I'll meet up with you for now.
お願いします！
Please do!
ごちゃごちゃ言わずに...
Stop complaining and...
ノープロブレム、ノープロブレム。行ける行ける行ける。
No problem, no problem. I got this, I got this!
つーか生肉持ってないけど平気？
By the way, I don't have raw meat, is that okay?
あ、生肉あります、生肉あります。
Ah, I have raw meat, I have raw meat.
じゃあこいつを寝かせて...肉を？
So we put this guy to sleep... and the meat?
やべ、なんかしょうもない麻酔矢しか持ってきてない...原始の弓しか持ってきてないけどいいか。
Shoot, I only brought useless tranq arrows... only brought a primitive bow, but is that fine?
私いるわ。
I'm here.
よく分からんけど。
Not sure though.
今放したから、あのユウティラ...だっけ？あいつに、
I let it loose, so into that Yuty... was it? Into him,
頭にぶっ放してほしい、麻酔を。
I want you to fire tranqs right into its head.
まさかのとんでもないの、大物が来たー！
No way, something insane, a big one has arrived!
ハマってるでしょ？なんか知らんけど。
It's trapped, right? Somehow.
入れてみた。
I got it in.
すごい、すごい！
Amazing, amazing!
入れてみた。よし、チェイス完了。撒いてきました、あいつを。
I got it in. Alright, chase complete. I lost him.
ねぇ待って、これさー、虫眼鏡とか欲しいなー。
Hey wait, for this, I really want a magnifying glass.
いや、欲しい、わかる！
Yeah, I want one, I feel you!
あ、行った？いやびっくりした。行ったように見せかけての？
Ah, did it go? Whoa, that startled me. It pretended to walk away?
頼む！なんかいい感じにテイムできてくれそう、あいつ。
Please! Looks like we'll be able to tame him pretty nicely.
来た来た来た！
Here it comes!
Go to sleep!
スリープ、スリープ、レッツゴースリープ。
Sleep, sleep, let's go sleep.
でもヒューチーズと繊維があれば弓矢が作れるんだよ、クソ。
But if I had thatch and fiber, I could make arrows, damn it.
なんかちょっと大人しくなった感じするけど。
Feels like it's quieted down a bit though.
私もね、もうすぐかな？
Me too, is it almost ready?
みんなで麻酔矢を撃ち込んで...
Everyone shooting in tranq arrows...
まだか。あ、逃げ出した！
Not yet? Ah, it ran away!
逃げるなー！
Don't run away!
寝ろー！寝ろー！寝ろ！
Go to sleep! Go to sleep! Sleep!
崩れてない！
It didn't collapse!
ねぇねぇ、ヒューチーズとさ、
Hey hey, thatch and...
はい。
Yes.
えっと、ワラある？
Um, do you have thatch?
あ、待って、ありますあります。
Ah wait, I have some, I have some.
てか弓矢ね、弓矢をくれれば、麻酔の矢を作れそう。
Or arrows, if you give me arrows, I can make tranq arrows.
なるほど、矢あります！矢めっちゃある！
I see, I have arrows! I have tons of arrows!
あ、矢欲しい！矢もらっていい？
Ah, I want arrows! Can I have some arrows?
矢落とした落とした落とした。あと藁も一応落としときます。
Dropped arrows, dropped, dropped. I'll drop thatch too just in case.
ありがとうありがとう。これで、あのボディで作っときながら...
Thank you, thank you. With this, while crafting on the go...
寝ろ！
Sleep!
ボディで作る、やりながらやるわ。
Crafting on the move, I'll do it while shooting.
寝てくれ。寝ろ、お願いだ！頼む！寝てくれ！
Please sleep. Sleep, I beg you! Please! Sleep!
え、なん...なんか別の恐竜が私を...狙ってる気がする。
Huh, wha... I feel like another dinosaur is... targeting me.
あ、やばい、お前射線に入ってくるな！
Ah shoot, don't walk into my line of fire!
やばい、逃げろ！みんな逃げろ！
Oh no, run! Everyone run!
ほらごらー！
Look at you!
大丈夫？見た？見た？！
Are you okay? Did you see? Did you see?!
早く肉入れろ、早く肉入れろ！
Put in the meat quick, put in the meat quick!
で、こいつのインベントリがこいつがデカすぎて邪魔すぎて開けねぇ！
And this guy's inventory, he's so huge and in the way that I can't open it!
待って大丈夫？
Wait, are you okay?
今体で塞いじゃってるから、そっち行けない。
It's blocking with its body right now, so I can't get over there.
なるほど、オッケー。
I see, okay.
お前ら...え、ちょっと待って。
You guys... wait a second.
やばい。体がガタガタする。
Oh crap. My body is shaking.
ちょっとちょっと、飛ばさないで、やめてー！
Wait, wait, don't blow me away, stop it!
いや、ま、この飛んでるをどうにかするか。
Well, let's do something about this flying one.
あ、飛んでるで。
Ah, with Tonderu.
開けてんじゃない？
Isn't it open?
ポイツーンて。
Plop it in.
こっち来るかな？
Will it come this way?
いや、あ、それでいける？
Ah, can you do it with that?
来た、来ました来ました！こっから...
Came, it came, it came! From here...
ナイスナイスナイス！
Nice, nice, nice!
イェーーイ！
Yay!
ありがとう、これ。
Thank you for this.
とんでもないの手に入れたんじゃないか、これ。やっば、これ！
Didn't we just get something unbelievable? This is insane!
えぐい！えぐ！
Crazy! That's insane!
てかさ、これさ、攻撃されるとキツいんだよな。ちょっとこっち...
By the way, it's rough if we get attacked here. A bit this way...
ちょっと...上手いことできたりします？
Could you... do something about it smoothly?
移す？ちょっと遠い場所に、この...
Move it? To somewhere a bit further...
今ちょっとね、こっちに呼び寄せてるけど、あ、来た来た。あの、こっち運んじゃうね。
I'm luring it over here right now, ah, here it comes. Um, I'll carry it over this way, okay?
お願いします！
Please do!
よしよしよし。
Good, good, good.
ユウティラも持ってくれれば...
If you also hold onto the Yuty...
ユウティラ持ってきます。
I'll bring the Yuty.
ナイスいいな、ナイスいいな。
Nice, that's great. Nice, that's great.
ナイス！
Nice!
まさかの。
Unbelievable.
すごー！えー！
Amazing! Wow!
なんかアルゲンの罠に入ってくれてラッキーでしたね。
It walked into the Argent trap, that was so lucky.
やばいな、それ！ラッキー！
That's crazy! Lucky!
ここに走って良かったー！
I'm so glad I ran here!
ねえ！なんか入るかわかんなくて走ったら入ってくれて、めっちゃラッキーでした。
Right? I didn't know if it'd fit, but I ran and it went in, super lucky!
ちょっと何か帰っていくティラノかなと思って、あっちに走ったんですけど、ラッキー！
I thought it was a Rex heading back, so I ran that way, but lucky!
ねえ！アルゲン...
Right! The Argent...
攻撃してこない？
Won't it attack us?
プテラをこれ...
This Pteranodon...
あ、はい。
Ah, yes.
これ肉にしちゃう肉
I'll turn this into meat, meat.
肉
Meat.
高い！
So tall!
食え食え
Eat, eat.
サンキュー
Thank you.
ここ熱いって言われるアルゲン...
The Argentavis that is said to be hot...
卵
Egg.
暑いんか
Is it hot?
雪山に、あの、近くに持ってくとか？
Maybe bring it near the snowy mountain or something?
そうですね、なんかそこのプテラ...
Yeah, like the Pteranodon over there...
痛い痛い痛い
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
くそ、重いか
Damn, is it heavy?
おほー
Ohoo!
おい肉を寄越せ、くそ。
Hey, give me meat, damn it.
ねえか
Is there none?
来てくれてありがとうねー
Thanks for coming by~
ユウティラちゃーん
Yutyrannus-chan!
お、来た肉！
Oh, meat's here!
イエーイ
Yay!
ついでにプテラもテイムしとこ。さっき死んじゃったから。
I'll tame a Pteranodon too, since mine died earlier.
確かに
True.
ナイス
Nice.
なんか追ってたから、プテラテイムしときます。
It was chasing something, so I'll tame the Pteranodon.
ほー、デカっ！
Whoa, it's huge!
てかさ、ここさ、今思ったけどさ、これ金鉱石じゃない？
Wait, looking at this now, isn't this metal ore?
あ、そう、この辺鉱石めっちゃあって
Ah, yeah, there are so many ores around here,
だから、なんかここサブサブにしてて
so that's why I made this a sub-sub base,
あの作った時に
when I built it.
もはやもう何が本、本当か
At this point, I don't even know what's real...
分からないよ。どこの、何が拠点か分からんよな。
Where or what even is the base anymore?
ここをテイム場にしようかなって思ってました。
I was thinking of making this a taming spot.
いいね、いいね、いいね。
Nice, nice, nice.
ちょっともう金、鉱石ちょっと燃やしに行っちゃいまーす。
I'm gonna go smelt the ores now.
はい。
Okay.
やばい、また喉が渇いた。お水を取ってこなきゃ。
Oh no, I'm thirsty again. I need to get water.
一瞬トンデルに乗らせてください。お水を...
Let me ride Tonderu for a sec. Water...
はい。
Sure.
あ、水ここにありますよ。
Ah, water is right here.
喉がヤバい、ちょっと...
My throat is dying, wait...
イナ、こいつ何て名前つける？
Ina, what should we name this guy?
え？
Huh?
ユ、ユウティ...茶？
Yu- Yuti... cha?
ユウティ？
Yuti?
ユウティ
Yuti.
ユ...ウ...ティ...
Yu... u... ti...
ユウティ？
Yuti?
待って、違う、カ、カルノ来た！カルノ来た！
Wait, no, a Ca- Carnotaurus came! Carno came!
まずいまずいまずい！
Bad bad bad!
いってぇ！
Ouch!
トンデルーー！
Tonderuuu!
あ、いたいた。
Ah, there you are.
ヤバイヤバイ、お前これさ...
Oh no oh no, you...
やばい、みんなこれ攻撃になっちゃった。
Shoot, everyone's set to attacking now.
こ、こいつやらないと無理だ。
W- We have to take this guy down or we can't do anything.
うん。
Yeah.
やばい、ブロロンまずい。
Shoot, Brolon's in trouble.
出れるのかこいつはまず。
Can this guy even get out first?
ちょ、デブすぎて出ない！
Wait, it's too fat to get out!
やばい、これ出さないとまずいけど...
Shoot, we have to get it out, but...
やばいブロロン死ぬ、ブロロン死ぬ、ヤバイヤバイ。
Shoot, Brolon's gonna die! Brolon's gonna die! Bad bad!
あ、オッケー出た出た出た。
Ah, okay, it got out, got out, got out!
ナイスナイスナイス。
Nice nice nice.
よしよしよし、ちょっとユウティラはここでちょっと飼うか。
Alright alright, maybe we should raise the Yutyrannus here for a bit.
拠点に連れてってもいいかもな、このユウティラ。
Or maybe we could take this Yutyrannus to the base.
てかさ、共有の拠点に持っていって見せびらかそうぜ、これ。
I mean, let's take it to the shared base and show it off!
「すご、すごいやろ」っつって、これ。
Like, "Isn't it awesome?!"
マジで。
Seriously.
ユウティー
Yutiii
ユウティ？ほら、ユウティでしょ、これ。
Yuti? See, it is Yuti, right?
生肉...
Raw meat...
ユウティー
Yutiii
好き好き好き！
Love it love it love it!
完璧。
Perfect.
な、生肉ありませんか？
D- Do you have any raw meat?
あ、いっぱい...
Ah, lots of...
ここで気絶してるプテラに入れたい、入れてほしい。
I want to put it in the knocked-out Pteranodon here, please put it in.
あ、どこですか？あ。
Ah, where is it? Ah.
あ、ここ。
Ah, here.
こっち、こっちだ。いろはこっちだ。
Over here, it's over here. Iroha, over here.
あ。
Ah.
あ、痛い。
Ah, ow.
なんか、ハチ、ハチハチハチみたいな。ごめん、いろはがゴリラに見えた、ごめんけど。
Like, bee bee bee or something... Sorry, I thought Iroha looked like a gorilla, sorry.
野生のゴリラいると思って。
I thought there was a wild gorilla.
ち、違った。
My bad.
痛っ、痛っ。
Ow, ouch.
あのね、ここに、ここに眠ってる、このプテラ、この辺に...あれ？いない。いろは？
So, over here, sleeping here, this Pteranodon, around here... Huh? It's not here. Iroha?
お疲れ様です。
Good work.
あ、ここに眠ってる。
Ah, it's sleeping here.
ね、ユウティさ、任していい？
Hey, can I leave Yuti to you?
はい、もちろん、もちろん。
Yes, of course, of course.
うん。
Yeah.
ちょっとじゃあ原油とか取りに行ってミッション進めちゃうわ。
Then I'll go get some oil and progress the missions.
お願いします。
Please do.
はい、生肉入れましたー。
Yes, I put in the raw meat~
ナイス！
Nice!
うぇーい。
Yay.
でかっ！でかすぎだろ。
Huge! That's way too big.
とんでもないアルゲンかと思いきや...
Thought it was an insane Argentavis...
なんかユウティ入ってきた。
Somehow Yuti got in.
アルゲンの交配できる？できそう？
Can Argentavis breed? Does it seem doable?
なんかちょっと暑いので、あの、ちょっとその雪山辺りまで行って交配させた受精卵を持ってきたらいいのかなって感じですね。
It's a bit hot here, so I'm thinking we can go near the snowy mountains, breed them, and bring back the fertilized egg.
ああ。
Ah.
ただ、怖いからユウティ連れて行こうかなみたいな。
Though it's scary, so I might bring Yuti along.
うん。
Yeah.
いいね、いいね。
Sounds good, sounds good.
ね。
Right?
確かに。それレベリング的にも...
True. For leveling as well...
よしな...
All right then...
うーん、あれは何だろう？
Hmm, I wonder what that is?
あれかな。
Could that be it?
やばい、また水なくなった身体。
Oh no, my body is out of water again.
水、あ、あそこに...
Water, ah, over there...
あ、ちょっとまた飲ませてもらって、かつ...
Ah, let me drink some again, and also...
はい。
Yes.
水を補給しなければ。
I need to replenish my water.
必要だったらもう川に行きますよ。
If needed, I can just go to the river.
あ、本当ですか？じゃあちょっと1回...
Ah, really? Then let me just...
水筒全部中に入れるんで、行ってきてもらいつつ...
put all the waterskins in here, so you could go fill them up...
ちょっとマジで... ちょっと待って。
Wait, seriously... hold on a second.
キチン足りるか？
Do we have enough chitin?
え、あの、キチンっていう素材をイナ先輩持ってたら、この中に入れてほしいんですけど...
Um, if you have the chitin material, Ina-senpai, could you put it in here?
多分入れてるはずです。
I think I put it in.
センキュー！
Thank you!
これも飲んで、ちょっと渇きが...
I'll drink this too, my thirst is...
アルゲンタヴィス...
Argentavis...
あ、いけんのか。
Oh, we can make it?
センキュー。
Thank you.
アルゲンタヴィス...
Argentavis...
これ何？50...
What is this? 50...
あ、いけ...待って！アルゲンのやつ作れるやん！
Ah, wait! We can craft the Argentavis saddle!
おー！
Ooh!
ええっと、今何しようとしたっけなあ...ちょっと待ってよ。
Umm, what was I trying to do just now? Hold on a sec.
ええっと...
Let's see...
ええっと、ええっと、餌だ、餌、餌。
Let's see, let's see... food, food, food.
餌箱...
Feeding trough...
木材、繊維、わら。
Wood, fiber, thatch.
木材、繊維、わら。わら。
Wood, fiber, thatch. Thatch.
あ、来た！
Ah, here it is!
アルゲンのサドル1個作れた！
I crafted one Argentavis saddle!
おおー！
Ooh!
なんかたまたまいた主で...
Thanks to that alpha that happened to be there...
あれ？
Huh?
ただいまー！
I'm back!
おかえりー！
Welcome back!
ま、レベル50だけど、ワイバーンの卵をゲットしてきた！
Well, it's only level 50, but I got a Wyvern egg!
一旦戦力になるかなと思って、やっぱ。
Figured it would add to our combat power for now.
え、待って！
Wait, what?!
ナイス！こちらも有りますよ、ねえ！
Nice! We have one here too, you know!
ユウティラ捕まえた！
We captured a Yutyrannus!
何？！おおー！
What?! Woah!
最強じゃん！
That's the strongest!
最強じゃん！で、残念ながらケツァルコアさんはなかったです、ミッション。
That's awesome! And unfortunately, there was no Quetzalcoatlus mission.
違かった。もう...
It was different. Aw...
あ、ラバエレメンタルだっけ？
Ah, was it Lava Elemental?
ラバエレメンタルじゃないかって、文字数的に。
Based on the character count, it might be Lava Elemental.
へえー！
Ohh!
で、ワンチャン、ラバエレメンタルがあの、火山の洞窟のボスらしくて、
And apparently, the Lava Elemental might be the volcano cave boss,
ライトニングワイバーンで行けるんじゃないかみたいなのがコメントにあって...
and chat commented that maybe we could take it on with a Lightning Wyvern...
ほうほう。
I see, I see.
ほえー！すごい！
Woah! Amazing!
なんかしらないけど、めっちゃ戦力固まった？
I don't know how, but did our combat power suddenly get stacked?
ね、いい感じにはなってるから、
Right? Things are coming along nicely,
ワンチャン行けるか？どうだ？っていう感じですね。了解です。
so maybe we have a shot? Let's see how it goes. Got it.
なんかどっか行ってもいいんじゃないかな？どうなんだろう？
Maybe we could go somewhere? What do you think?
ね、行ってみるのはありそう。ま、サドル系ちょっと作って...
Yeah, it might be worth going. Well, let's craft some saddles first...
うん、サドルは欲しいかもね。
Yeah, having saddles would be good.
ユウティラのサドル検索するか...ユウ...
Let's search for the Yutyrannus saddle... Yu...
ユウティラは居所...
As for Yuty...
パイロテイムしたいんだよね。
I want to tame a Pyromane.
あ、パイロテイム...あ、確かに！パイロ...
Ah, tame a Pyromane... Ah, true! Pyromane...
みんなで、うん、みんなでちょっとパイロをテイムしに行ってもいいかもしれない。
Maybe all of us could go tame a Pyromane together.
どのみち明日いるでしょ、多分、やろうと思ったら。
Either way, we'll probably have them tomorrow if we want to do it.
そうだね、確かに。パイロ先行っちゃうか。
Yeah, for sure. Shall we go for Pyromanes first?
うん。
Yeah.
あ、ユウティラも真珠が必要なんですね。
Ah, Yutyrannus also needs pearls.
真珠めちゃめちゃトワ様が取ってきてくれてるから行けるはず。
Towa-sama gathered a ton of pearls for us, so we should be good.
ナイス！
Nice!
ユウティラサドル...最高最高！
Yuty saddle... awesome, awesome!
旋盤の中にあるで。
It's inside the Smithy.
誰このベッド？！何この斜めのベッド？！
Whose bed is this?! What's with this tilted bed?!
はい！イナ！無理無理無理！
Yes! Ina! No no no way!
嵐だろこれ！
It looks like a storm hit it!
なんだよ、いいじゃん！
What? It's fine!
やべえよ、汚ねえよ、これ！
It's terrible, this looks so messy!
いいよ、オシャンティーやん！
It's fine, it looks stylish!
オシャレじゃねえよ、バカ！
That is NOT stylish, you idiot!
なんだよこれ！
What the heck is this?!
みんな綺麗にさ、四角四角でやってんのにさ、斜めだこれ！
Everyone else placed theirs neatly square to the walls, but this one is diagonal!
マイクラだったらそんな設置...いいやん！
If this were Minecraft, placing it like that... It's fine!
アシンメトリーでいいじゃない！
Asymmetry is good, isn't it?!
ふざけんなー！
Cut the crap!
アシンメトリーじゃねえ、アシンメトリー...シンメトリーだろ、それ！
It's not asymmetry! Asymmetry... you mean symmetry!
シンメトリーでいいじゃない。
Symmetry is fine too.
え、これどうしたらいい？拾う...拾うでいいか。はい。
Uh, what should I do with this? Pick it up... I'll just pick it up. Okay.
拾える拾える。
You can pick it up.
あっしーのがカマキリ取ってくれたおかげで、ギリースーツが治る。
Thanks to Asshii catching mantises, I can repair my ghillie suit.
イナ先輩も1回拠点戻りますか？ユウティラ連れていくか、そっちにじゃあ。
Ina-senpai, are you heading back to base once too? Should we bring the Yuty over there then?
あ、じゃあ私もちょっとカプセルで持っていきます？
Ah, then should I bring it in a cryopod too?
1匹なんか持ってこようかな。
Maybe I'll bring one creature over.
そうですね、じゃあ連れ...入れて...
Yeah, then let's bring... put it in...
入れて、いつでも...あ、でも1匹ちょっとなんか持っていきます。
Put it in so anytime... Ah, but I'll bring one creature over.
いいよー。
Sounds good.
恐竜何がいい？クレストでもらったやつだったら...
What dino would be good? If it's one from the crates...
これと...
This and...
ええと、な、何だっけ名前？ええと...
Umm, wha- what was the name? Umm...
ユウティラじゃなくて、何て名前だったっけ？
Not the Yuty, what was its name again?
一番、クレートでもらえるやつ何だったっけ？
The one you get from the crates, what was it again?
クレートでもらえる...
The one from crates...
テリジノかな？
Maybe a Therizino?
テリジノも使えるはず。
A Therizino should be usable too.
じゃ、テリジノ持って来るか。
Then should we bring a Therizino?
ちょっと先行っててもらってもいい？
Could you go ahead for a bit?
オッケー。
Okay.
と、あの、あれ見- あれ見てくるわ。
And I'll... I'll go check on that.
え、何何？これバグっ-
Huh, what? Is this glitching...
あ、バグっちゃった。
Ah, it glitched out.
いいよ。
Sure.
一応予備プテラも連れてきましたー。
I brought a spare Ptera along just in case!
ナイスー。
Nice.
よしの。
Alright.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
俺は今たんぼ、そう、たんぼの様子見に行くんや。
I'm just going to check on the fields now, yeah.
てか麻酔銃欲しいかも。
Actually, I might want a tranq gun.
原油ポンプもう設置したんですよー。
I already set up the oil pump!
いいね、原油ポンプ設置できたならありがたやー。
Nice! If you set up the oil pump, that's a huge help.
うぃっ。
Alright.
おーい。あとは納品したらいいかな？
Hey. Should I just deliver the rest?
テリジノ...え、麻酔矢ってどっかなかったっけ？
Therizino... Wait, weren't there tranq arrows somewhere?
あ、麻酔あげれる。
Oh, I can give you some narcotics.
麻酔矢ね。
Tranq arrows, yeah.
薬剤か。
The medicine, huh.
と、あの、あれ...あ、やべ、ぶつけちゃった。
And that... Oh crap, I bumped into it.
あれ。
Huh.
55個だけ...別の拠点にちょっと売ってるはずです。取って持ってきます。
Just 55... they should be at the other base. I'll go get them and bring them over.
はーい、センキュー。
Okay, thank you.
55個だけ？
Just 55?
ポンプって1個しか設置しちゃいけないんだっけ？
Are we only allowed to place one pump?
いいよ。っていうわけではないけども。
You can. It's not like that, but...
うん、あの何か独占しちゃダメってだけで、別に1個以上ダメとかじゃない。
Yeah, it's just "don't monopolize it," not that you can't place more than one.
ここからが独占になるのか。
I wonder what counts as monopolizing from here.
よいしょ。あれ？
Ups... Huh?
あれ？
Huh?
ルーちゃんさ、昨日原油取ったのってさ...
Lu-chan, when you gathered oil yesterday...
うん。
Yeah?
あのー
Um...
お、クジラの死体からだっけ？
Oh, was it from the whale carcass?
そうだよー。
That's right.
クジラの死体って右上だったっけ？
Was the whale carcass in the top-right?
右上だよー。
It's in the top right.
うそ、消えた？は？ほら。
No way, did it disappear? Huh? Look.
ここに入れて作れるもの作るか。ユウティラ...
Let's put this in and make what we can. A Yutyra...
よいしょ。えっと...
Alright. Um...
インゴットそんなに必要なら...
If we need that many ingots...
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
繊維...
Fiber...
皮...
Hide...
旋盤の中にあるやつ全部もらって...
I'll take everything in the smithy/fabricator...
デフル...ス、セン...
Def-
はぁ。
Whew.
よいしょ、これで...風真先輩！
Alright, with this... Kazama-senpai!
はい！
Yes!
ここにユウティ...ユウティティ...ユウティラ...ティラなんちゃら、ユ- ユウティ出してもらっていいですか？
Could you bring out the Yuty... Yutyti... Yutyra... tyran-whatever, the Yuty here?
おー、いいね。
Oh, nice.
あ、はい！今戻りまーす。
Ah, okay! I'm coming back now.
乗れるのか、こいつ。
Can we ride this thing?
ちなみにパイロ右上におるわ。
By the way, the Pyro is up in the top-right.
砂漠のとこでしょ？
In the desert area, right?
うん、そう。普通におるわ。
Yeah, exactly. It's just roaming around normally.
うん、大量にいるよ。
Yeah, there's a ton of them.
これどう行くんだったっけー？
How did I get there again?
あ。よいしょ。
Ah. Up we go.
そしたらー
And then...
お、お、お、お、お、あー！
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, aah!
お？
Huh?
怖い！
Scary!
どうした？
What's wrong?
大丈夫？
You okay?
これどうしたらいい- これどうしたらいい？
What do I do with this... What should I do?
何をしてるんだい！
What are you doing?!
どうした？
What happened?
やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい...
Oh crap, oh crap, oh crap, oh crap, oh crap, oh crap...
どうしたのー？
What's going on?
やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい...
Oh crap, oh crap, oh crap, oh crap...
だ、大丈夫？あー、倒産したー！
A-Are you okay? Aah, bankruptcy!
何やってんのー？！
What are you doing?!
死んだ。
I died.
ござるー、何やってんのー！
Gozaru, what are you doing?!
ライトニングワイバーン！
Lightning Wyvern!
な、な、な、何事、ライトニングワイバーン？！
Wha- Wha- What's happening, a Lightning Wyvern?!
ござる？
Gozaru?
あ、ユウティここに...
Ah, the Yuty is here...
ユウティありがとー。
Thanks for the Yuty!
そばに行ってこっちのこの...どこでもいいでしょ。あ、でっけー、待って！
Go over here, anywhere is fine. Ah, it's huge, wait!
全部なくなった...
Everything's gone...
え？まぁ、ちょっと行ってきてくれ。
Huh? Well, go check it out.
何事、何事ー？！
What happened, what is happening?!
くっそー！
Damn it!
なんでだー。
Why...?
なぜなくなって...
Why did it disappear...
なぜなくなった？
Why did it disappear?
何があったんだ一体？！
What on earth happened?!
えー、すごーい！
Whoa, awesome!
まぁ色々あった。
Well, a lot happened.
色々、色々、色々ね？なるほどね。
A lot, a lot, lots of things, huh? I see.
攻撃力...
Attack power...
体力...体力か。体力に振って、
Health... health, huh. Putting points into health,
近接攻撃力を...
and melee damage...
テリジノ持っていきまーす。
I'm taking the Therizino!
はーい。
Okay.
あーい。
Alright.
あ、オッケー、オッケー。
Ah, okay, okay.
あ、お肉落ちてるかも。センキュー。そうだ、しまったら落ちるんだったな。
Ah, some meat might have dropped. Thank you. Right, it drops when you put it away.
これでー
With this...
あー、かわいい！
Ah, so cute!
でっかい恐竜！ユウティラ乗れました、これで。
Big dino! We can ride the Yutyra now with this.
おー、でっかーい！
Ooh, so big!
はい。
Yes.
みんなギリースーツって1人1個持ったよね？
Everyone got one ghillie suit each, right?
うん、持ったよ。
Yeah, I got one.
持ったー。あ、まだ持ってない。風真は無くすの怖くてまだあの中に入れてある。
Got mine. Ah, I don't have mine yet. I was scared of losing it, so I left it in there.
え、樽ん中？
In the barrel?
樽ん中。
In the barrel.
あ、オッケー、オッケー。
Ah, okay, okay.
え、全然使いたい- 取りに行くのに使ってください全然、もしあれだったら。
You can totally use it to go get your stuff, feel free if you need it.
いや、もう取りに行くとかではないから、もう大丈夫。
No, it's not even about going to get it anymore, so I'm fine.
取りに行くとかの以前の問題だから、もうね。
It's beyond just going to get it at this point, you know.
あ、そう...
Ah, I see...
奥にはすっきりしてるわけ
So the back is all cleared up.
あーなるほど
Ah, I see.
すっきり
All clear.
どこで落としたの？
Where did you drop it?
スッキリしてるわけよ
It's all cleared up, you see.
ん？
Hm?
「ん？」じゃないよ、どこで落としちゃったの？
Don't "Hm?" me! Where did you drop it?
イナ先輩！
Ina-senpai!
はい
Yes?
もう記憶喪失してんじゃん
You've already got amnesia!
どこでこれを...
Where did I... this...
どっかで... どっかではないな
Somewhere... Well, not just anywhere.
だか... 火山... 火山だよね？ さっき火山いたからね
So... the volcano, the volcano, right? We were at the volcano earlier.
火山ね
The volcano, yeah.
拾ってこれるか？ これワンチャン...
Can I pick it up? There's a chance...
どこ...
Where...
みんな今どこにいんの？
Where is everyone right now?
まだ拠点にいるよ
Still at the base.
仮拠点に
At the temporary base.
仮拠点の... お、ちょっとユウティラくんの尻尾邪魔やな
At the temp base... Oh, Yuty's tail is in the way.
降ります
I'll dismount.
どこ...
Where...
あ、くそ、下手くそだ！
Ah shoot, I suck at this!
えっと、ユウティラくんって何に振ったらいいんでしたっけ？
Um, what stats should I level up on Yuty again?
ユウティラくんは何優先だ？ 体力？ スタミナ？
What's the priority for Yuty? Health? Stamina?
一旦攻撃... 塞ぎました
For now, attack... Blocked it.
攻撃かな？
Attack, maybe?
これで... 着地しろ！ こいつめ！
With this... Land! You little...!
あ、石を取りたいんや
Ah, I want to gather stone.
スタミナか... スタミナのほうが... スタミナか体力か...
Stamina or... Stamina would be... Stamina or health...
ユウティラは体力。じゃあちょっと体力振っとこう
Yuty is health. Then I'll put some into health.
テリジノって何振ったらいい？
What should I level on the Therizino?
テリジノくん... ちょ、体力振っといた方がいいかな
Therizino-kun... Maybe put some points into health.
体力か
Health, huh?
うん
Yeah.
テリジノくん...
Therizino-kun...
よいしょ
Alright.
どっこー、ここは。間違えちゃったわ
Where is this... I went the wrong way.
やばい、掴めないこいつが
Oh no, I can't grab this guy.
スタミナもちょっと振っとこう
I'll put some points into stamina too.
近接振っとこうかな？
Should I put points into melee damage?
場所がよろしくない
The location isn't good.
あー強い！
Ah, so strong!
装備用意してよかったー
Glad I prepared gear!
ユッティ強い！
Yuty is strong!
あー、ついてちゃ... ついてきちゃってるね。赤ちゃんが
Ah, following... it's following along. The baby.
赤ちゃんが...
The baby...
あー赤ちゃんがよちよちしてる。おいで、おいで。ごめんよ、赤ちゃん
Ah, the baby is waddling. Come here, come here. Sorry, baby.
はあ、ばぶちゃん、ばぶちゃん
Haa, baby, baby.
ばぶちゃん何？ あなた何？ 何何？
What is it, baby? What do you want? What?
ばばばばぶ。お世話まだいらない？
Ba-ba-ba-babu. You don't need care yet?
汗を... お世話を...
Care... looking after it...
テリジノくん草食なんだ
Therizino is an herbivore.
草食動物の好物だけど食べるござるか？
It's an herbivore's favorite, but will it eat?
どうしたの？ 何？ 今みんな何してほしいの？
What's wrong? What? What do you want us to do now?
あ、だめだめ。黒いベリーダメ
Ah, no no. Black berries are no good.
え、黒いベリー行けたっけ？
Eh, could they eat black berries?
世話をしてもらいたがってる
It wants to be cared for.
そしたらどうしよう？ イナ先輩と... どうします？ もう何だっけ？ パイロ...
Then what should we do? With Ina-senpai... what should we do? Should we already... what was it? Pyro...
パイロ行っていいんじゃないか？
Isn't it fine to just go to Pyro?
行きます？
Shall we go?
何だ？
What is it?
あれだったら... この... まだ時間かかりそうだったら寒いとこ行って一瞬でパパッと産ませてきちゃおうかなと思って。アルゲンの子供
If so... if it'll still take time, I was thinking we could go to a cold place and hatch it real quick. The Argent baby.
イナ先輩と...
With Ina-senpai...
なんだ？
What is it?
あ、ほうか
Ah, I see.
うん
Yeah.
行ってくる？
Are you going?
ちょ、パパッと産ませてこようかな。有性卵あるから
I think I'll go hatch it real quick. Since I have a fertilized egg.
うん、うん
Yeah, yeah.
で、入れてこっちに帰ってきますわ。じゃ、イナ先輩、プテラでついてきてください
And then put it in a cryopod and come back. So Ina-senpai, please follow on your Ptera.
フォローミー、レッツゴー！
Follow me, let's go!
ユウティラもうちょい戦いたいな、ユウティラ。レベリングしたいよな
I want to fight a bit more with Yuty. I wanna level it up.
ナイスー！
Nice!
お前も戦いたいよな、ユウティラ
You wanna fight too, don't you, Yuty?
ナイスふー
Nice, whew.
うんちが落ちた。飯食え、飯食え。飯食え、飯食え
Poop dropped. Eat food, eat food. Eat food, eat food.
よいしょ
Alright.
えーっと
Umm...
こっちのね、ここ寒くて、イナ先輩。ここだったら生まれる気がしているんです
Over here, it's cold here, Ina-senpai. I feel like it'll hatch if we're here.
まだお世話はもうないかもしれん。ここ
It might not need any more care here.
だから、ちゃっちゃと産んで、モンスターボールに入れて連れて帰りましょう
So let's hatch it quick, put it in a Cryopod, and bring it back.
おお、はい
Oh, okay.
あとユウティラくん、レベリングしに行っか
And let's go level up Yuty-kun.
有性卵... これだ
Fertilized egg... Here it is.
ドンドン、ドーン！
Boom, boom, bam!
ちょうどいいだろう。あいつ倒せるかな？
This should be just right. Can I take that guy down?
あ、暑いって
Ah, it says it's too hot.
暑いらしいです、ここ
Apparently it's too hot here.
え、ここも暑い？
Eh, even here is too hot?
ここ暑い？ うそ
Here is too hot? No way.
この辺とかだったらどう？
How about around here?
おおー
Ooh.
あ、なんか上に強そうな人いる
Ah, there's someone looking scary up there.
うわあ！
Whoa!
よいしょ。マンモス？
Alright. A mammoth?
マンモス、マンモス、マンモス。ここどう？
Mammoth, mammoth, mammoth. How about here?
流石に涼しいやろ
It's surely cool enough here, right?
どう？
How is it?
ささささ寒い！
It's f-f-f-freezing!
寒い！
Freezing!
この、このメーターが... それやめて、本当にそれやめて。マジで
This, this meter is... Stop that, really stop that. Seriously.
これが... オッケー！
When this... Okay!
これさえ... 孵化できたら...
As long as we... can hatch this...
はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes.
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
いいやん
Looking good.
ふー
Phew.
とても早い
It's very fast.
ん？
Hm?
ねー
Yeah.
ん？ あれ？
Hm? Huh?
これエアコン入ってんのか？
Is an air conditioner in effect?
エアコン？ あ
Air conditioner? Ah.
できた！
It's done!
毛皮は...
The fur...
イエーイ！
Yay!
もう本当にそこ行くのやめて、本当に
Seriously, stop going over there, really.
飯食ってくれ
Please eat food.
よいしょ
Alright.
寒すぎるもん！ うわああ！
It's way too cold! Uwaaa!
止まれ！
Stop!
止まれ！ 凍る！
Stop! I'm gonna freeze!
なんだよマグマとかいうクソクソクソな地形は！クソがー！
What the heck is with this shitty terrain called magma?! Damn it!
マグマだもん...
It's magma after all...
しょうがないね、マグマだもん。
Can't be helped, it's magma after all.
待って、後ろにクマがいる。もうここしゃがんで...
Wait, there's a bear behind me. Just crouch here...
許さない！
I won't forgive this!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ちょ、本当にさ、もうこのクマお前、もう本当にクマやめて？
Seriously, this bear, come on... seriously stop it, bear!
もうしゃぐ...もうしゃぐ...
Crouching... crouching...
クマいる。あと、あともうちょっと...
There's a bear. Just, just a little bit more...
ちょっと、こっち来ちゃ... あったまったら、
Wait, it's coming over here... Once it's warmed up,
これに入れて帰ろう。
let's put it in this and head back.
飛んだ飛んだ飛んだ飛んだ。ナイスナイス。
It flew, it flew, it flew, it flew. Nice, nice.
今、待つ期...
Now, the waiting phase...
やばい、まずいまずい。
Uh oh, this is bad, this is bad.
こっち来るこっち来るこっち来る。ちょっと待って。
It's coming this way, coming this way! Hold on.
えーっと...
Um...
いや、もうちょっともうちょっともうちょっと...
No, just a little more, a little more...
ただこれ落としたらすくに歩くか。
But if I drop this, will it walk right away?
いや、もうちょっともうちょっともうちょっと。
No, just a little more, a little more.
ああ、イノシシほしいな。回復のやつ。
Ah, I want a wild boar. The healing one.
こんにちはー。
Hello~.
1匹は引っ張って... こんにちはー。
Tethering one of them... Hello~.
こんにちはー。
Hello~.
あ、生まれました！よし。
Ah, it was born! All right.
おかえりー。おかえり？おかえりなのかな？
Welcome back~. Welcome back? Is it "welcome back"?
そのうんちやめてね。
Stop with that poop.
ボールに入れて帰れる？中ってこれボールに入れて...
Can we put it in a ball and head back? Put this inside the ball...
ボール... 入って。うん、よいしょ。
Ball... get in. Yeah, alright.
こんにちはー。
Hello~.
はい！あ、あそこに道が...
Hi! Ah, there's a path over there...
あい、マジ？着きました！
Aye, really? I've arrived!
オッケー。入れた？入れた？
Okay. Did you put it in? Put it in?
あ、入れました！
Ah, I put it in!
戻ります？
Heading back?
よいしょ。戻ろう戻ろう。Let's go!
Alright. Let's head back, let's head back. Let's go!
ゴーバック！引っ込んでる。待って。
Go back! I'm stuck. Hold on.
あ、木が！木が閉じる！ゴミラス...
Ah, the trees! The trees are closing in! Garbage...
え？あ、ちょっと待って。
Eh? Ah, hold on.
よいしょ。あ、飛んで...
Up we go. Ah, flying...
え、またゼロからになった？
Eh, did it go back to zero again?
治安や... え、飛んだ...
The security is... Eh, it flew...
ユウティラテイムしました、なんかまぐれで。
I tamed a Yutyrannus, somehow by sheer luck.
お、やったー！また1匹？やったー。え？
Oh, yay! Another one? Yay. Eh?
あ、違う。今アキ先輩と話してます、これ。
Ah, no. I'm talking with Aki-senpai right now.
ああ、オッケーオッケー。びっくりした、びっくりした。
Ah, okay okay. That scared me, that scared me.
うわ、ゴミすぎこいつ。
Ugh, this guy is so trash.
罠... 罠なしのテイムに入ってしまったんです、あいつが。
It walked right into a... trap-less tame, that guy.
あ、なるほどね。不法侵入で捕まえた。
Ah, I see. Arrested for trespassing.
麻酔... 麻酔矢ほしい麻酔矢。
Tranq... I need tranq arrows, tranq arrows.
あ、オッケーオッケー、麻酔...
Ah, okay okay, tranq...
サンキュー。ごめん、ここに落とした。
Thank you. Sorry, I dropped it here.
どう？すごいそれ、もう本当にやめてくれないかな？
How is it? That's crazy, could you really not do that?
うぇ、頑張り... おお、すごい。
Whoa, hang in there... Oh, amazing.
あ、1個... ちょっと待ってくださいね。
Ah, one... Please wait a moment, okay?
ここじゃねえ。えっと...
Not here. Um...
お、よいしょ。あっち。
Oh, there we go. Over there.
とりあえず僕はいつでも行けますよ。
Anyway, I can go anytime.
いつでも？いつでも？
Anytime? Anytime?
よいしょ。
Alright.
よいしょ。アルゲン組が帰ってきたらかな？
Alright. Maybe when the Argent team gets back?
オッケー。
Okay.
えーっと、これと...
Um, this and...
火炎瓶、矢を... えー...
Fire arrows, arrows... um...
ちょっと待って。ごめんごめん、本当にごめんね、本当にごめんね。
Hold on. Sorry, sorry! Really sorry, really sorry!
許さない。
I won't forgive you.
大丈夫か？ドア。おお。
Is the door okay? Oh.
大丈夫ではある、一応。
It's okay, for now.
え、一応大丈夫である？オッケー。
Eh, it's okay for now? Okay.
えーっと、イナ先輩！はい！
Um, Ina-senpai! Yes!
イナ先輩って、ブリーディングミッションって達成してましたか？
Ina-senpai, did you complete the breeding mission?
あ、はいはい。
Ah, yes yes.
あ、じゃあイナ先輩に引っ張られてブリーディング達成になったのかな？
Ah, then did being tethered to Ina-senpai complete the breeding mission?
ござるじゃなくて、たぶん嵌れてたから、ワンチャン...
Not for Gozaru, but maybe because I was caught in it, there's a chance...
ブリーディング達成は、えっと、達成みたいなのは出なかったはず。
For the breeding completion, um, I don't think a "completed" message showed up.
はい、あの携帯電話みたいな、スマホみたいなやつでピピッてわかる感じですよね、たぶん達成。
Right, like on that mobile phone/smartphone thing, it beeps to let you know when it's completed, right?
そうそうそう。そうですよね。そう。
Exactly. Right? Yeah.
ワンチャンどっちなんだろう？
I wonder which one it is?
今わからず... ちょっと1回聞いてみた。生まれたけどござるには判定来てなかったので...
I didn't know just now... so I asked. It was born, but it didn't count for Gozaru...
イナ先輩に行っていればそれでいいんですけど...
If it went to Ina-senpai, that's fine, though...
交配ボタンを押した人だから...
Because it goes to whoever pressed the mating button...
ああ、でもござるだな交配ボタン。途中で変わっちゃったから、もしかしたら駄目だった可能性はある。
Ah, but Gozaru pressed the mating button. But since it changed midway, there's a chance it didn't work.
かもしれない。かもしれない。無事に帰って来れたー。
Might be. Might be. We made it back safely~!
おかえりー。ナイス、イナ先輩！
Welcome back~. Nice, Ina-senpai!
よし。ナイスー。おかえりー。おかえりー。
All right. Nice~. Welcome back~. Welcome back~.
で、ござるちょっとブリーディングよく分かってないんですけど、この辺で赤ちゃん出したらワンチャン...
And Gozaru doesn't really understand breeding well, but if we bring the baby out around here, maybe...
ワンチャンかな？ゲーム内ボイチャがオンかも、ござる。あ、本当ですか？
Maybe? In-game voice chat might be on, Gozaru. Ah, really?
うん。はい。
Yeah. Okay.
ここ、ここでいいじゃない？この... これもう行けんのか？
Here, isn't here fine? This... Can we go with this already?
あ、これだ。えっと、お世話票...
Ah, this is it. Um, care timer...
うんちがでっかい！うんちでっけえ。
The poop is huge! Poop is huge.
ユウティラのうんちでっかいね。
Yutyrannus poop is huge, isn't it.
ケアが必要になるまであと4分だ。
4 more minutes until it needs care.
よいしょ。
Alright.
やばい、生肉全然ないや。入れてあげなきゃ。
Oh no, there's no raw meat at all. I need to put some in for it.
ああ、アキ先輩と合体した。
Ah, I merged into Aki-senpai.
あっ、もしもーし。
Ah, hello?
はい、先ほどの問い合わせに対しての回答が返ってまいりましたのでお知らせ...
Yes, I received an answer to your earlier inquiry, so to let you know...
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you very much!
はい、えっと子供が生まれて、まぁ触って名前をつける時が判定ポイントです。
Yes. When the baby is born, petting it and naming it is the trigger point.
ああ、ありがとうございます！
Ah! Thank you very much!
なるほどね！
I see!
はーい、頑張ってねー。
All right, good luck!
はーい、センキューでーす！
Okay, thank you!
はーい。
Bye-bye.
よいしょ。
All right.
じゃあ名前つけるタイミングだから、名前つけタイミングってどこだ？
So it's when you name it... where do I name it, though?
あ、なんか生まれて、インプリントをするってメニューから...
Ah, once it's born, you do "Imprint" from the menu...
じゃあ名前つけられてるから...え、で、イナ先輩、これで達成はできてる？
It's named already, so... wait, Ina-senpai, did you complete it with this?
なんかスマートフォンみたいなところで...
Like in that smartphone-looking menu...
あ、できてます、はい。
Ah, yes, it's completed.
あ、じゃあオッケーですね！
Ah, then that's all good!
ほわー！
Whoa!
トワピー！
Towa-pi!
イナ先輩の分ができたから、これでブリーディングを...
Ina-senpai's is done, so with this, breeding...
オッケー。クリア？
Okay. Cleared?
うん、イナ先輩はクリアかもこれで。
Yeah, Ina-senpai's might be cleared with this.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
あ、オッケー！はーい。
Ah, okay! Great.
だから、ええっと...そうですね。
So, umm... let's see.
よいしょー。
Here we go.
ほな、じゃあこれでい-行ってみるか？
Well then, shall we try going like this?
行ってみるかー！
Shall we!
ちょっと、じゃあパイロメインをじゃあ...お世話が...
Wait, then the Pyromane... taking care of it...
えーっと...
Umm...
しろはーの、二重になってるよ、声。
Shiroha-no, your voice is echoing.
あ、ホントだ。
Ah, true.
B押してもろて。
Press B please.
あれ？こいつ...
Huh? This guy...
ほんまやで、ほんまやで。
Truly, truly.
死んじゃったのか？
Did it die?
ああ、もうちょっと...
Ah, just a little more...
よいしょ、ほい！
All right, there!
これで、なんか...
With this, like...
ブリーディング、イナ先輩、この...
For breeding, Ina-senpai, this...
はい。
Yes.
何だろう、カーソル合わせると、なんかケアみたいなやつがあって、
How do I say it, when you hover the cursor, there's like a care status,
今あと残り...2分ってなってるんですけど、
and right now it says 2 minutes remaining...
はい、2分。
Yes, 2 minutes.
うん。
Yeah.
必要になると、なんか頭の、この...
When it needs something, above its head...
許してください！マジ許してください！
Please forgive me! Seriously, please forgive me!
鳥の頭の上に...
above the bird's head...
うん。
Yeah.
何々してくれって出てくるんで、それをやってあげると、
it'll say to do something, and when you do that for it,
オッケー。
Okay.
お世話判定になって育ちます。
it counts as care and it'll grow.
おおー！
Ooh!
トワさん？大丈夫？生きてる？
Towa-san? Are you okay? Are you alive?
生きてる、生きてる！
I'm alive, I'm alive!
生きてる！全然大丈夫ではあるんだけど...
Alive! I'm totally fine, but...
パイロ行くよー！
Let's go for the Pyromane!
あ、行ってきていいよー。
Ah, feel free to head out!
ほに！
Alrighty!
後で合流するわ、もう家、あとちょっとで。
I'll join up later, I'm almost done with the house.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあイナ先輩ブリーディングしててもらって、じゃあ3人で行った...
Then we'll have Ina-senpai handle the breeding, and the three of us will go...
そうだね、一旦3人で行ってみるか。
Right, let's try going as a trio for now.
オッケー！
Okay!
いってらっしゃーい！
Have fun!
ブリーディングお願いしまーす！
Good luck with the breeding!
はーい！
Okay!
よいしょ。
All right.
ほな、じゃあアルゲン乗ってった方がいいですか？それともファボリー...あ、違う、プテラ乗って...
Well then, should I ride the Argent? Or the Fabri... ah no, ride the Ptera...
アルゲンかなー。
Probably Argent~
オッケー。
Okay.
うーん、待って、ワイバーン、君。
Hmm, wait, Wyvern, you.
ファブリーズじゃあ連れてくか、こいつ弱いけど。あいつはちょっと後で終わったらな。
I guess I'll take Febreze along, though this one's weak. That guy, I'll take after we finish.
オッケー。
Okay.
よいしょ、はい。ほな、じゃあ火山行ってみよー！
All right, there. Well then, let's head to the volcano!
行ってみましょう！
Let's do this!
えーっと、これはどうやって行けばいいやつだ？
Umm, how should we head over there?
乗り物乗って...でしょ、テレポで行きやすいよ。
Ride your mount and... teleport is easier to get there.
あ、テレポート、了解です。ちょっと水飲まなきゃ。
Ah, teleport, roger that. Need to drink some water first.
そうね。
Yeah.
えーっと...
Umm...
たたたたた...水飲んで...
Ta-ta-ta-ta... drink water...
よいしょ。
Oof.
物持ってくの置いてけって、小鳥に掴まったこと。
"Leave your items behind," like when you got grabbed by that bird.
コメント欄は心配性の人が多いんですから、まったく。
The chat has so many worriers, honestly!
あははは！
Ahahaha!
わかるよ。
I get it.
しょうがにゃいにゃあー！
Can't be helped, nya!
マジ、あたいも全てを失う覚悟で全部持って行ってるから。
Seriously, I also bring everything ready to lose it all.
しょうがにゃいにゃあ！どんだけ心配性なんですか。
Can't be helped, nya! Just how worried are you guys?
スリル...一世の猛者ですけど。
Thrill... but I'm a veteran warrior of the era.
スリルを味わおう、スリルを！
Let's enjoy the thrill, the thrill!
よいしょ。
Right.
めんどくさい！
Too much hassle!
心の中の心配性...おじさんが...
The worrywart old man in my heart is...
よいしょ、ほい、行けます！
All right, yes, ready to go!
体の中のおじさんが騒ぎ立てている。
The old man inside my body is making a fuss.
えーっと、ほなじゃあ着陸行けるか？
Umm, well then, can we land?
これは乗っていますか？
Are you riding this?
乗っ-乗ってる。
Ri-riding.
よし、行くぞ！
Alright, let's go!
とぅー！
Too!
お前らが邪魔！あたし飛んだし！こうやって被ってくんだなー。
You guys are in the way! I flew, and that's how we end up overlapping.
被ってくねー。待っとくわ。
Overlapping, yeah. I'll wait.
はーうー...
Sigh...
そうだねー。ちょっと早く退いてほしいな、こいつよー。
Yeah. I wish this guy would move out of the way soon.
こっちやー！
Over here!
はぁー。
*sigh*
いいよ。
All right.
えーっと、ほな火山に、レッツゴー！
Umm, well then, to the volcano, let's go!
Let's do it!
よし、行くぜ！
Alright, let's go!
オッケー。
Okay.
Let's do it.
んで、あれよね。だから水とギリギリ、なんか火山と生え際のところにいるパイロ...
And, that's right. So, the Pyromane near the water border, right at the volcano's edge...
そうだね、パイロがいいかもしれないね。
Right, that Pyromane might be best.
ほな、一旦海辺に行くか。
Well then, let's head to the seaside first.
そうやね。
Yeah.
おいしょ、しょ。
Oof, oof.
イエーーイ。
Yaaay.
このまま真っ直ぐ行って...
Head straight like this...
あの水際ね、ちょうど。
Right at the water's edge, exactly.
ね、行ってくれたら...
Yeah, if we go there...
もうちょっとゆっくりおいで、アルゲン
Come a bit slower, Argent.
あ、大丈夫です、大丈夫です。
Ah, it's okay, it's okay.
最悪プテラも持ってきてるんで、帰り荷物少なかったらプテラでも帰れます。
Worst case, I brought a Ptera, so if we have light cargo on the way back, we can return on it.
オッケー。
Okay.
一応そこにいるけどね、1匹。
There's one right over there, though.
連れてってみる？
Want to try leading it over?
まだ遠いか。遠いか。
Is it still too far? Too far, huh?
1回下見てみる？
Shall we check down below first?
もうちょい見てそう、見てから行くか。
Let's watch it a bit more before heading out.
この辺りにいたらめちゃめちゃ嬉しい。
It'd be awesome if it's around here.
あ、めっちゃいい！あ、いるいるいるいる！
Ah, that's great! Ah, there it is, there it is!
いました？
Did you find it?
一応1匹...
There's one...
ものすごい、あ！
It's super—ah!
あ、燃えてる、燃えてるやつね。
Ah, the burning one, right?
カラフルなやついるね、あっちに。
There's a colorful one over there.
あ、いる？
Oh, really?
うん。
Yeah.
あ、いるいるいる！ジンオウガみたいな色してるよ！
Ah, there it is! It's colored just like a Zinogre!
本当だ！ジンオウガいる！
You're right! It's a Zinogre!
ジンオウガ！
Zinogre!
ジンオウガやめてくださいよｗ
Please stop calling it Zinogre! lol
ジンオウガいる！
There's a Zinogre!
ハジキテやんｗ
That's a Zinogre!
え、あっち？
Wait, over there?
いやでもガチジンオウガだなこれｗ
Seriously though, this is a total Zinogre lol.
ちょっと誘えるかな、いけるかな。うわー！
I wonder if I can lure it over... whoa!
ジンオウガだ！あっち！
It's Zinogre! Over there!
燃えてます！
It's on fire!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
こっち来い、こっち来い！海辺に今...
Come here, come here! It's by the beach now...
海辺こっちだと...あいだよ海辺。
If it's the beach, it's over that way.
あ、いいねいいねいいね。
Ah, nice, nice, nice.
本当だ、ジンオウガだ！
For real, it's a Zinogre!
ジンオウガだろ？
Told you it's a Zinogre, right?
え、ここで...
Wait, here...?
ああああ！
Aaaah!
大丈夫？
You okay?
落ちた！
I fell!
大丈夫、プテラそのまま置いといていいよ浮いてるから。
Don't worry, you can leave the Ptera there, it's hovering.
で、それで攻撃をしなきゃいけない。
And then we need to attack it.
あ、キリンヤで...あれだ、下に降りちゃった。
Ah, on the Pyromane... it went down below.
えー！？
What?!
これどうしよう？プテラで攻撃できないよね。
What should we do? We can't attack with Ptera, right?
プテラで攻撃するしかないかも。
We might just have to attack with Ptera.
それか私あれテリジノ持ってきてるけど...
Or I brought a Therizino, though...
テリジノでも行けるならって感じかな。
If a Therizino works, maybe that'll do.
いや、キリンヤでちょっと浮かせて回復中です。
Well, I'm hovering with Pyromane and healing up.
テリジノ行くか？
Should we go with the Therizino?
倒さないででもテリジノっていける？
But can Therizino fight without killing it?
テリジノでもワンチャン行けるかもしれない...あ。
There's a chance it might work with Therizino... ah.
そっか自分足がないや、ごめん。
Oh right, I don't have a mount. Sorry.
どちらかプテラ、テレポーターまで連れてこれたりする？無理か。
Could either Ptera bring it to the teleporter? Maybe not.
今頑張って...ちょっと待ってくださいね。
I'm trying right now... hold on a second.
私タゲ取ってるからちょっと...
I'm drawing aggro, so just...
本当ですか？やべ、アルゲンの体力がなくなってしまって...
Really? Crap, my Argent is out of stamina...
このまま落とされました。え、なんかバグった？
And I got dropped. Huh, did it glitch?
I have the flyer...
ふーちゃんフラグ回収お疲れ様。
Thanks for fulfilling that flag, Fu-chan!
サンキュー！
Thank you!
1級フラグ建築士の方でしたか。
So you were a First-Class Flag Architect after all.
1級フラグ建築士だったってことか。
Guess I really am a First-Class Flag Architect.
A look.
やばい、登れなくてやばい。
Crap, I can't climb up, this is bad!
行くぞ！まだまだいけるぜ、こんなもん！
Let's go! I can still keep going, this is nothing!
ちょっと待っとくわ。
I'll wait a bit.
待って、なんか誰かの...エリートファミリ...
Wait, someone's... Elite Familia...
こっちか。
Is it over here?
誰か置いてったのかと思っちゃった。
I thought someone left it behind.
はだしでーでっかいー♪
Barefoot and big... ♪
こっちは来ないか。
It's not coming this way, huh?
タゲ取らないとでも。
We need to pull aggro, though.
こっちだ！登りたいのに登れない...
Over here! I want to climb up but I can't...
ヒットポイントでも...あーでもリコ上がっちゃうな。
Even with hit points... ah, but the torpor will rise.
私今取ってるから...
I'm holding aggro right now...
一定時間...まあ消えてるはず...
For a certain duration... well, it should wear off...
いろは、乗れそうだったら乗ってほしい、こいつ乗らないと...
Iroha, try to mount it if you can! We have to ride it or...
乗れない...来た来た来た！乗った！
I can't... here it comes! I got on!
いや、はまった！やばい！挟まり...
No, I'm stuck! Oh crap! It's wedged...
こいつこいつ、パイロンパイロン、こいつまだ乗れない、これ。
This one, Pyromane, we can't ride it yet.
体力半分以下じゃないと乗れないはず。
Its health has to be below half before we can ride it.
なるほど。
I see.
ちょっと待ってくださいね。
Please give me a second.
体力分かる？これ。
Can you see its health?
難しいね。でも体に血が滲み始めたら、もうだいぶ削れてる兆候かな。
It's tricky. But once blood starts showing on its body, that's usually a sign its health is low.
よいしょ。邪魔だな...
Up we go. This is in the way...
それまだずっと一人でヘイト取ってられそうですか？
Can you still keep holding the aggro by yourself?
まだ行ける。
I can still manage.
じゃあちょっと一旦...
Alright, then let me just...
あ、ごめん！倒しちゃった！
Ah, sorry! I killed it!
あ、倒しちゃった？オッケーオッケー。でも倒せるってことが分かったから大丈夫だ。
Ah, you killed it? Okay okay. At least now we know we can take it down, so it's fine!
オッケーだね。加減したら行けるわ。
Okay then. If we hold back, it'll work.
そうですね。
Right.
じゃあプテラを呼んで、呼んで追従で...
Then whistle the Ptera to follow...
屋根を連れて...
Bring the Argent...
あーれー！崖から落ちて死ぬー！
Noooo! I'm falling off the cliff, I'm gonna die!
あ、死なない。なんでだ？
Ah, I didn't die. How come?
助けてくれー！俺を殺してくれー！
Save me! Kill me already!
やばい、どこ行ったっけなぁ...
Oh no, where did it go again...?
よいしょ。
Up we go.
じゃあまたさっきの湖連れてきてくれたら私タンクやるから...
If you can bring it to that lake again, I'll tank it...
オッケー。
Okay.
で、減ったら誰か乗ってあれしてほしい。
And once its health drops, someone please mount it.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあ自分今からポータル行くからござるさん...多分自分が飛んだら分かるはず。
I'm heading to the portal now... Gozaru-san, you should be able to tell once I warp.
よいしょ。
Alright.
助かります。
That helps a lot.
休憩させつつ...
While letting them rest...
Maybe I should gather some stuff while I'm just here.
さっきのね、パイロ、レベル50弱だったから多分余裕だったんだよね。
That Pyromane earlier was under level 50, so it was probably an easy one.
あ、いるやん！待って、白髪のプテラいたっけ？いなくないか？
Ah, there it is! Wait, was there a white-haired Ptera? Isn't it gone?
あー、白髪のプテラいない。よいしょ。
Ah, no white-haired Ptera. Up we go.
近くの敵倒しとくか。
Guess I'll take out the nearby enemies.
やーっと。
Finally.
こっちかなー、この辺かなー...
Maybe this way... around here...?
ござるさん迷子。
Gozaru-san is lost.
迷子ー！
I'm lost!
そこにいて？ｗ
Stay right there, okay? lol
あ、飛んできたら分かるやつ？
Ah, the kind of spot you'll spot once you fly in?
あ、そうそうそう。その辺りに...
Ah, yeah yeah yeah. Around there...
と、安全地帯に行って...
And heading to the safe zone...
ちょっと待っとこ
Let me wait a bit.
よし。うむ。
Alright. Yep.
I'll stay around the base. えーっと...
I'll stay around the base. Um...
こっち 行き過ぎていたポータル
Over here... the portal I went too far past.
えーっと... Baby...
Um... Baby...
よしよし
There, there.
Baby doing okay.
え、パイロ吠えたら乗れるの？
Wait, can you ride the Pyromane once it roars?
火打石っていたんですか？
Did we need flint?
そういえば
Come to think of it...
来た！ここだ！ここだ！
Here it is! Right here! Here!
おー...
Oh...
どこー？
Where is it?
ここだよー、地図開いてー
Right here~ Open the map~
何色で...
What color...
早く来てー！来てー！
Hurry up and come here! Come on!
虫がいるのー？
Are there bugs?
あのー... 前が全く見えない！吹雪いてる
Um... I can't see forward at all! It's blizzardy!
パイロ乗った後にさ、敵倒さないといけないんだよね
After riding the Pyromane, you have to defeat enemies, right?
合流できます？
Can you join up?
そうそうそう。ま、近くにいるから大丈夫か
Yeah yeah yeah. Well, they're nearby, so it should be fine.
はい
Yes.
お待たせしております。一応合流行ける身体になりました。
Sorry to keep you waiting. My body is ready to meet up.
あ、オッケー。ありがとう。で、追従切ってもらえたら...
Ah, okay. Thank you. And if you could disable follow...
はい
Okay.
えーっと、これで着地。ありがとうー。
Um, landing now. Thank you~
乗れました？
Were you able to ride?
うん、乗れた、サンキュー！
Yeah, I got on, thank you!
はーい
Okay~
これでじゃあ合流しに行きやす。
Alright then, off to meet up with everyone!
合流って...
Meet up where...?
火山です。
At the volcano.
火山。あー、えっと... 火山。
Volcano. Ah, um... Volcano.
恐竜何連れてったら一番いいかな？
Which dino would be best to bring?
一応今タンクはできてるから...
For now we have a tank, so...
プテラで平気そうなの？
Is a Ptera fine?
テリジノでいける？
Can we go with a Therizino?
うん。さっき55倒せたから...
Yeah. We defeated a level 55 earlier, so...
うん。多分いけるんじゃないかなーと...
Yeah. I think it'll probably be fine...
あれ？待って。
Huh? Wait.
ミッションって、日記のミッションって別に終わりじゃなくて今すぐやっても達成になるってこと？
The missions... does it mean the journal missions don't end and completing them now still counts?
ね、今ね... なんか落ちてきたんで。ホントだ。
Yeah, right now... Something dropped. True.
えーっと、あれ？この辺で所持品落とさなかったっけ？
Um, huh? Didn't I drop my inventory around here?
水に落としちゃいましたかね？アイテム。
Did you drop them in the water maybe? The items.
アイテム... なんかこの辺だったような...
The items... I feel like they were around here...
あれ、アイテム岩のとこにあるよ。
Huh, the items are by the rock.
ありがたやー！これか。
Thank goodness! Is it this?
うわ、イラッとした！
Ugh, that's annoying!
あれ、ドアどこやったっけなー。
Huh, where did the door go again?
よいしょ。あーらー、行かないでー！
Up we go. Oh no, don't leave~!
追従が解除されてないでござるさん！
Follow hasn't been cancelled, Gozaru-san!
ちょっと待って...
Wait a second...
持ってかれましたー！
It got carried away~!
帰ってきた。
It's back.
調整、ちょっと待ってください。えーっと...
Adjusting, please hold on. Um...
着地にしたんだけどなー。あれ？
I set it to land, though... Huh?
えっとね、そのアルゲンに乗りながら解除ボタンを押してほしいかも。
Um, maybe try pressing the cancel button while riding that Argent.
追従解除ボタンを。
The unfollow button.
あ、なるほど。アルゲンに乗っかっちゃってんのか。
Ah, I see. It was riding on the Argent?
あ、でも来たっぽい、来たっぽい。来ました？オッケー。
Ah, but it seems to have come! Did it come? Okay.
So big.
お前どこ行くねん！ほんま。
Where are you going?! Seriously.
え、もう終わった？
Huh, is it already over?
あ、はい。
Ah, yes.
合流する？
Meet up?
あ、はい！
Ah, yes!
なんか皆のとこね、合流しちゃって大丈夫だよ。
Yeah, you can go ahead and meet up with everyone.
あ、了解です。
Ah, roger that.
火山のところにテレポートで...
Teleporting over to the volcano...
危ねえ、マジで。体燃えるところだった。
That was close, seriously. My body was about to catch fire.
うわー、ヘビだー！
Whoa, a snake!
いやー、騎乗解除やめてー！
Nooo, stop dismounting me!
すまーん！ヘビやって... うーん。
Sorry! Dealing with a snake... mmgh.
騎乗解除... 水に... やめてー！
Dismounted... Into the water... Stop it!
What the baby.
ありがたやー。
Thank goodness.
うわー！川霧だー！
Whoa! River fog!
いっぱい来るな、ここ。
A lot are coming here.
うーん...
Mmm...
そして再度原油を... 原油ー
And getting crude oil again... Crude oil~
え、オッケー。ま、一旦... 一応やるか。
Um, okay. Well, for now... Shall we give it a try?
ここにちょうど一匹いますわ。
There's exactly one right here.
あ、じゃあ... あ、ちょうど水の中入ってた、あいつ。
Ah, then... Ah, that one was right in the water.
あ、どこ？ここここ...
Ah, where? Right here...
イナちゃん、ごめん、ドアさ、違うとこテレポートしちゃうから...
Ina-chan, sorry, the door teleports somewhere else...
あ、これね？
Ah, this one?
オッケー。こっち連れてきてー。
Okay. Bring it over here~
いいよいいよ、こっちこっち... どうよ？
Sure sure, over here... How about that?
吠えたら... あ、ここじゃね？
Once it roars... Ah, isn't it here?
あ、ここじゃね？見失った。
Ah, isn't it here? I lost sight of it.
でも誰かに乗ってもらわないとなんだよね。
But we need someone to ride it.
あー、確かに。乗るか、ござるが。
Ah, true. I guess I'll ride it.
なんかこれ今自分がヘイト取っちゃってる？いや、そんなことねぇか。
Did I draw its aggro just now? No, probably not.
あ、吠えたかも。吠えたかも、乗れるかも。
Ah, it might have roared. It might have roared, you might be able to ride it.
あ、オッケーオッケー。行ってみる、行ってみる、行ってみる。
Ah, okay, okay. I'll go check, I'll go check.
追従切れない、追従ちょっと... 停止。
Can't cancel follow, follow is a bit... Stop.
乗れる？
Can you ride?
いや、騎乗出てこない。
No, the ride prompt isn't showing up.
もうちょい泳いでるからかな。オブジェのほう...
Maybe because it's swimming a bit more. Towards the structure...
いや、出てこないな。出てこないや、ごめん。
No, it's not showing up. It's not appearing, sorry.
うん。ごめんござる、もう一回連れてきて...
Yeah. Sorry Gozaru, bring it over one more time...
もらっていいか？
Can I take it?
ふっ ああ、確かに。1回行かなきゃダメか。やばい！
Ah, right. I have to go there once, don't I? Oh no!
す、全てが...
Ev-Everything is...
えって、ぐちゃぐちゃ...
Wait, it's a mess...
水中ダメなのかな？
Is underwater not allowed?
いや、まだかもね。
No, maybe not yet.
あ、まだだった？ ああ、ヘイト買っちゃった。やばい！
Ah, not yet? Ah, I drew aggro. Oh no!
すぐ乗らないと切れちゃうのか。
Does it run out if I don't get on immediately?
いてー！
Ow!
あらららら...
Oh dear, oh dear...
あ、足がなくなった。
Ah, I lost my mount.
ええと...
Um...
あでででででで...
Ow ow ow ow ow...
足が...
My mount...
うわー、ちょっと借りるか。
Whoa, I guess I'll borrow one.
申し訳... 絶対殺さないという気持ちで...
I'm so sorry... With the determination never to let it die...
プテラお借りしまー...
I'm borrowing a Ptera...
あ、でもそっか、サドルがないのか。
Ah, but wait, there's no saddle?
サドルあるんです？
Is there a saddle?
ああー、こりゃあちょっと終わったかもしれないです。ソーリー。
Aah, this might be the end for me. Sorry.
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
そっちに向かうための足がなくなっちゃって...
I lost my mount to head over your way...
私のプテラが！
My Ptera!
ちょ待って。
Wait a second.
俺のプテラ...
My Ptera...
ああ、寝袋置いとけばよかったな。
Ah, I should've placed a sleeping bag.
ええと、川基地...
Um, the River Base...
キミさんとBBBだったらいるけど...
There's Kimi-san and BBB, but...
あんま... ワンチャンそれでも...
Maybe... just maybe even with that...
乗ってって、トワの。
Take mine, Towa's.
いっぺん借りるか。ちょっと借りよ...
Should I borrow it once? Let me borrow it...
いいよ、借りてー。
Sure, go ahead and borrow it~
あ、あれどこどこ？ よいしょ。
Ah, where is it? Here we go.
これね、わしの適当につけた名前のプテラ。
This is my Ptera that I gave a random name to.
ちょ、ハマってる。
Wait, it's stuck.
おいしょ。
Hup.
なんちゃら、か、火山？
Something... vo-, Volcano?
火山だね。
Volcano, yeah.
これ大丈夫かな、そいつ？
Is that one going to be okay?
なんかスタック癖えんだよな。
It kinda looks stuck.
スタックしちゃってる？
Is it stuck?
てんじゅうもちょっとこの... そうそうそう借りちゃいます。よいしょ。
Let me just borrow this... yes yes yes, I'll borrow it. There we go.
あれ？ 原油って...
Huh? Crude oil...
どっかになかったっけなー。
Wasn't there some somewhere?
原油はすまねえながら旋盤で使っちゃった。
Sorry, but I used up the crude oil in the lathe.
こいつ倒さないとやばいな。
We gotta take this guy down or we're in trouble.
あ、でもあるわ。あ、ちょうどあるわ！行くわ、これで！
Ah, but there is some! Ah, there is some right here! I'm going with this!
え？
Eh?
これで...
With this...
ほいほい。なんでお前ここにいるんだよ。
Alright. Why are you even here?
今乗れるかな？
Can I ride it now?
こっちこっちこっち...
Over here, over here, over here...
テレポートのとこにでっかい恐竜がいる。
There's a huge dinosaur at the teleport spot.
イエー！
Yeah!
いやー！こっちこっちこっち...
Noo! Over here, over here, over here...
どうぞもう！ あかんあかんて！ 大丈夫か？
Please! No, no! Are you okay?
ん？
Hm?
イ、イキロが、イキロがヘイト買っちゃってるかも。こっちこっち、お前こっち来い！こっち来い！
I-Ikiro might have drawn aggro! This way, you come here! Come here!
え、マジ？
Eh, really?
そうそうそう、テレポートの近くのでっかい恐竜引きつけてるから、今のうちに！
Yeah yeah, I'm luring the huge dinosaur near the teleporter away, so go while you can!
お、やばいやばいやばい！
Oh, shoot, shoot, shoot!
こっち来て、こっち来て...
Come this way, come this way...
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
え、こいつ倒しとくか。
Eh, should we kill this guy?
イキロどこ行った？
Where did Ikiro go?
ありがたや、ありがたやー！
Thank you, thank you so much!
はいはい、今のうち今のうち...移動するなら今のうち。
Yes yes, while you can, while you can... if you're moving, do it now.
ファブちゃんの、でもね、綺麗やね、まだ生きてる。
Fabu-chan is... but you know, it's fine, it's still alive.
あ、ほんとに？ オッケー、今から飛びます。
Ah, really? Okay, I'm flying over now.
オッケー。
Okay.
生き残ったな、お前も。
You survived too, huh.
こう、よいしょ。
Like this, heave-ho.
やっぱここ危ねえよなぁ。
As expected, this place is dangerous.
ござるが死んだところが...あ、ここか。
Where Gozaru died was... ah, is it here?
よいしょ。
There we go.
マジすまねえ。
I'm really sorry.
遅い...
Slow...
トワちゃんありがとう。
Towa-chan, thank you.
いいよ、いいよ。
You're welcome.
やばいかも。
This might be bad.
じゃBBBに乗ろっか。
Let's get on BBB then.
ああー、これやばいな、ここ。
Aah, this is bad around here.
やばーい。
It's so bad.
よいしょ。
Hup.
ハードな...
Hardcore...
ねえ、なかなかハードなとこやな。ちょっと拠点が怖いな。さっきそいつに旋盤壊されたんだよね。
Yeah, this is quite a hardcore place. The base is scary. Earlier, my lathe got destroyed by that guy.
え、これ誰だ？
Eh, who's this?
グリフィン手に入れてるー！
Someone got a Griffin!
あ、原油200個じゃないか？
Ah, isn't it 200 crude oil?
あ、それか！
Ah, that's it!
うん。
Yeah.
ちょっとあれしとくか。
Let me do that.
原油を入れますよー。
Putting in the crude oil~
はーい。
Okaaay.
しまっとくか。
I should put it away.
キター！メガテリウムとグリフィン。
Here it is! Megatherium and Griffin.
全員持ってきてもらえるかい？なんなら。
Can you bring everyone over? If possible.
オッケー。
Okay.
6個だね。
That's 6, right.
あ、ありがとー。綺麗にいるー。助かったよー。
Ah, thank you! They're nicely in order. Saved us!
キミ出す？しまっとくわ。
Bring out Kimi? I'll put it away.
狡猾のアーティファクトなんだ、次。
Artifact of the Clever is next, huh.
じゃあ俺か？
So me next?
よいしょ。入れて...
Hup. Putting it in...
おいしょ。
Hup.
ダメだ。
No good.
ほいほい。
Right, right.
あれ？
Huh?
オッケー。
Okay.
ほい。
Here.
よいしょ。
Hup.
やばい、あそこまで行くのにまた飛ばなきゃいけないか。
Oh no, do I have to fly again to get over there?
BBBがしまえない。よいしょ。
I can't put BBB away. Hup.
しまっとくか。
I'll put it away.
ふぁーい、ありがたやー。
Okaaay, thank you so much~
はーいよー。
Sure thing~
おいしょ。
Hup.
あ、もうそろそろなのか。
Ah, it's almost time, huh.
そうだね、もうそろだね。
Yeah, pretty soon.
あ、プテラの間違えちゃった。
Ah, I got the wrong Ptera.
メガテリウムとグリフィンか。
Megatherium and Griffin, huh.
あ、大丈夫ですか、Botan先輩？
Ah, are you okay, Botan-senpai?
予備のプテラが一応ここに一匹...
There's a spare Ptera here just in case...
あ、私プテラ大丈夫だよ。
Ah, I'm good on Pteras.
大丈夫ですか。オッケーオッケー。
You're good? Okay, okay.
うん。
Yeah.
さあ...行くか、やるか？
Now then... shall we go? Shall we do this?
やるかー。
Let's do it.
2...
Two...
3...
Three...
4、5...
Four, five...
メガテリウムのサドルがある！
There's a Megatherium saddle!
6...
Six...
まずい、ちょっと待って。
Shoot, wait a second.
今ここで...今ここで手に入るの、世界で一番やばい。
Getting this right now, right here, is the most dangerous thing in the world.
やばい、襲われてる！
Oh no, I'm being attacked!
やめて、気絶値稼がれてる！助けてー！
Stop, my torpor is building up! Help!
メガテリウムのサドルは持ってるよ、私。
I already have a Megatherium saddle, by the way.
持ってる？助けてー！助けてー！
You have one? Help me! Help me!
あー、もうそこから離れ...離れなー！
Ah, just get away... get away from there!
って気絶してるんかい、お前！
Wait, you're already knocked out?!
大丈夫か。
You okay?
うわー！
Whoa!
あっちょちょちょちょ...
Wait, wait, wait...
一旦全員分の報酬獲得したからー
We've collected everyone's rewards for now, so...
うわー！
Whoa!
あ、ありがとう。これまずい？無事に抜けたかな？
Ah, thank you. Is this bad? Did we get out safely?
カメラー！
Camera!
いいよ。
All good.
やめろー！
Stop it!
いいね。
Nice.
うわー！
Whoa!
えっ、全員、それを引き連れ...
Wait, everyone, leading them...
も、戻る。帰ります、帰ります、帰ります。
I-I'm going back. Going back, going back, going back.
大丈夫っす。
All good.
ござるの荷物も拾えたりしますか？
Can you pick up Gozaru's gear too?
あ、
Ah,
行けるか？
Can you get it?
アルゲンが生きてれば鞄の中に全部突っ込んで...
If the Argen is alive, cram it all into the bag...
あ、オケオケオケ。じゃあ、イナの近くに下ろすわ。
Ah, okay okay. I'll drop it off near Ina, then.
大丈夫でございますか？
Are you doing alright?
はい。
Yes.
持ってきました、多分。
I brought it, I think.
助かります。
That helps a lot.
はい。
Yes.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
なんか知らない子入ってない、このお家の中に？
Isn't there someone we don't know inside this house?
いや、野生だよね？
Wait, that's wild, right?
オッケー。
Okay.
これみんなのプテラがここにめっちゃいるんだけど、これどうしたらいい？
There are so many of everyone's Pteras here, what should we do with them?
あ、持っていく、持っていく。
Ah, I'll take them, I'll take them.
持っていく？
Taking them?
うん。
Yeah.
お願いします。
Please do.
はいよー。この状態、帰るか。
Alrighty. Let's head back in this state.
I'm heavy.
そやね。
Yeah.
うん。一旦帰りましょう。
Yeah. Let's head back for now.
そんなにも...そやんな。
With that much baggage... yeah.
みんなちょっと着地しといてほしいね。
I'd like everyone to land for a bit.
よいしょ。
Alright.
えっとね、メガテリウムとグリフィンは冷蔵庫の中に入れといた。
Um, I put the Megatherium and Griffin into the fridge.
はいよー。
Got it.
一旦これ帰る？
Should we head back for now?
一旦帰っちゃってもいいかなー。
I guess we could head back for now.
オッケー。
Okay.
うん。
Yeah.
飛んでる、すごーい。
They're flying, amazing!
あ、待って、アルゲンもしかして...
Ah, wait, is the Argen by any chance...
え、メガテリウムサドル付けてくれてんだけど。
Wait, someone put a Megatherium saddle on it.
ありがたや。
Much appreciated.
お前...あ、待ってよ。本当だー！
You... Ah, wait. It's true!
元から付いてたんだっけか？
Was it on there from the start?
ついてたっけ？
Was it?
おー。
Oh.
オッケー。
Okay.
着いてるよ。
It's on there.
よいしょ。でっかー。
Up we go. Whoa, it's huge.
あ、オケオケオケオケ。
Ah, okay okay okay okay.
あれ？私のプテラどこ行った？
Huh? Where did my Ptera go?
あ、連れてっちゃってるかも、今。ファブリーズ？
Ah, I might be leading it right now. Febreze?
あ、ファブリーズ...
Ah, Febreze...
違う。
No.
自分たち...キンダス...あ、もう一緒、一緒だ。ごめんごめん、一緒に来ちゃってるわ。ごめんごめん。
Ours... Kindas... Ah, it's together! Sorry sorry, it came along with me. Sorry sorry.
キンダスさん？キンダスさんも一緒に来ちゃってたわ。ソーリーソーリー。
Kindas-san? Kindas-san came along too. Sorry, sorry.
すまんな。
My bad.
ほよ？
Hoyo?
おーい、カマキリやめろー！
Hey, mantis, knock it off!
キンダスどこ行った？
Where did Kindas go?
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
あ、メガテリってそうなんだ。
Ah, so that's how Megatheriums are.
あれ？キンダスいない？
Huh? Kindas isn't here?
めっちゃ遠くにいる。
It's super far away.
ん？どこだ？どこだどこだ？めっちゃ遠く...
Hm? Where? Where is it? Super far...
めっちゃ上にいる。めっちゃ上にいる。降りてきてもらおう。
It's way up high. It's way up high. Let's have it come down.
おーい！待ってよ。
Hey! Wait up.
はいはい、降りてきてもらった。
Alright, had it come down.
あ、オケオケオケ。
Ah, okay okay okay.
はい。ありがとう。
Yes. Thank you.
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー。はいはいはい。
Okay. Yes yes yes.
ほな。
Well then.
帰ろ。
Let's go back.
次はあれ...あれか。
Next is that... that thing?
ミッションじゃなくてあれか、イベントか？
Not the mission, but an event?
イベントあ...
Event, yeah...
そう、イベントがあるから、もう一旦帰るのやめて帰ろうかなと。
Right, since there's an event, I thought I'd stop and just head back.
オッケー。
Okay.
はい。
Yep.
まあ、アルゲンいるんだったら、アルゲン6匹いるんだったら、あの...行っちゃってもいいけどね、洞窟。
Well, if we have Argens, if we have 6 Argens, we could go to the cave, though.
メガテリいるなら正直メガテリで全然いい。
Honestly, if we have Megatheriums, Megatheriums are totally fine.
行けるはず。
We should be able to do it.
行ける行ける。
We can, we can.
アルゲンまだ...
Argens, not yet...
そんなに実はいないですよ。ユ-ユティラニに邪魔されて、そんなに実は...
Actually, we don't have that many. We got interrupted by a Yutyrannus, so not that many really...
あれ、アルゲンって交配させてないんだっけ？
Wait, haven't we bred the Argens?
交配させて、今出来上がったやつ一匹と...うん。
We bred them, so we have the one that's ready now, and... yeah.
昨日捕まえた3匹...
The three we caught yesterday...
匹...
birds...
お、じゃあ5匹いるじゃん。
Oh, then there are five of them.
な。
Yeah.
で、あとあと1匹捕まえれば...
And if we catch just one more...
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
って感じで...
like that...
その交配させた奴がメスで、
If the one you bred is female,
メスだったらその交配終わった子供と産ませたら...
you can breed her with the offspring...
うん。
Yeah.
いいんじゃないか？
Wouldn't that work?
多分、うん。
Probably, yeah.
あとあれだ、なんちゃらブリュー作らないと。
Also, I need to make that one brew thing.
あ、そうだ、メディカルブリューね。
Ah, right, Medical Brew.
欲しいな、かい、回復薬が欲しい。
I want some heal—healing potions.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
ほい。
Here we go.
あれ？メディカルブリューってどうやって作れたっけ？
Wait, how do you make Medical Brew again?
回復薬か。
Healing potions, huh.
メディカルブリューは料理鍋にティントベリーと麻酔薬入れたらOKなはず。
For Medical Brew, put Tintoberries and Narcotics into a Cooking Pot and it should work.
鍋作んないとじゃん。
So we need to make a Cooking Pot.
鍋、家の中かどっかなかったっけかな？置いたと思うんだけど。
Wasn't there a pot in the house or somewhere? I think I placed one.
あ、あるわ。
Ah, here it is.
晴れたじゃん。
It cleared up.
大量生産してほしい。
I want you to mass-produce it.
そう、でもティントベリーがそんなになくて...
Yeah, but I don't have that many Tintoberries...
ああ、じゃあ取るか。
Ah, guess I'll gather some.
ちょっと集めてもらわなきゃいけないかな？
Maybe I should have someone gather some?
ティントベリー400個あるけど。
I have 400 Tintoberries, though.
あ、じゃあそれ全部使っちゃってOK。
Ah, then feel free to use all of them.
赤いやつか、ティントベリーって。
Tintoberries are the red ones, right?
うん。
Yeah.
はーい。めっちゃ持ってるよ、確か私も。
Okay. I think I have a ton of them too.
えーっと、中継所かな？
Um, is it the relay base?
えーこれで...
Uh, with this...
うわ、虫が...
Whoa, the bugs...
うわー！やば！パイロ来てる！
Whoa! Crap! A Pyromane is here!
これ無理じゃない？
Isn't this impossible?!
うわー！これまずい！
Whoa! This is bad!
うわー！これ倒せるかな？倒せるかな？
Whoa! Can we defeat it? Can we defeat it?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
うわー！
Whoa!
一旦タゲ離れた方がいいかも。
Might be better to drop aggro for a moment.
お前これ誰にタゲってんだ？これ誰にタゲってんだ？
Who is it aggroed on? Who is it targeting?
ん？
Hm?
誰だろう？
Who is it?
あ、ファブリーズが！ファブリーズだ！あ、行った！
Ah, Febreze! It's Febreze! Ah, there it goes!
燃えてるー！
It's burning!
ファブリーズ！
Febreze!
お前ちょっと降りてこい、降りてこい、降りてこい。他のやつら降りてこい。
Hey, land down here! Land! The rest of you, land!
ファブリーズはサドルが付いていますが、まあ最悪...
Febreze has a saddle, but in the worst case...
うわー！ちょっちょっちょっちょっちょっちょっちょっ...
Whoa! Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait...
水筒か。
A canteen, huh.
遠くに離して...
Lead it far away...
うわー、なんかめっちゃ飛んでくる。
Whoa, there are so many flying over!
あー！ファブリーズがやられたー！
Ahh! Febreze was killed!
お前、こっちこっちこっちこっちこっちこっちこっち！
Hey, over here, here, here, here, here, here!
一旦ちょっと拠点から離れて...
Get away from the base for a second...
ハード拠点だ。
This is a hardcore base.
ああ、やばい！
Ah, crap!
お前死ぬか？キレイやね、お前死んじゃうか？キレイやね。
Are you gonna die? Kireiyane, are you gonna die?
ハード拠点...
Hardcore base...
キレイやね。お前死んじゃいそうだな、お前な。
Kireiyane. You look like you're gonna die.
うそ、ハード拠点。
No way, hardcore base.
うわー...
Ugh...
水の瓶はどこにしまったかな？
Where did I put the water jar?
お、いいね、土台。
Oh, nice foundation.
なんかどっかにしまったんだよなあ...
I know I put it away somewhere...
ワンチャンモンボに入れてテレポートの方がいいかも。
Maybe putting it in a Cryopod and teleporting is better.
ちょっと2匹いて厳しいかも。
There are two of them, so it might be tough.
きびちいな。
That is tough.
そう。
Yeah.
囮に行きましょうか？体しかできることないですけど。
Should I go be a decoy? I've only got my naked body, though.
待て、降りてくるか？
Wait, is it coming down?
どういうこっちゃねん、ここの拠点。
What is with this base?!
よしよしよし。
Okay, okay, okay.
すごいな。
This is wild.
あと1日しかいないから。
We're only here for one more day anyway.
確かに。
True.
うん。
Yeah.
金属はおいしいから、わざわざ出向かなくてもあるし。
Metal is plentiful here, and we don't even have to travel far for it.
鉄が美味しいから...
Yeah, the iron is great...
待て、水筒どこやったっけな？ああ、忘れたわ。
Wait, where did I put the canteen? Ah, I forgot.
お前！お前だ！お前だ、お前だ！お前だ、お前だ、お前だ！
Hey! It's you! You're the one! It's you, it's you!
え、ござるチェイスしちゃうんで、これ死んでるんで、もう体何もないんで...
Uh, Gozaru will distract them! I've died already, so I have nothing on me...
あ、ほんと？じゃあちょっと拠点から離してほしいかも。遠くに行ってほしい。うん、ありがとう。
Oh, really? Then could you lure them away from the base? Lead them far away. Yeah, thanks!
これで...
With this...
キレイやね！キレイやね、お前！お前...あ、やばい！
Kireiyane! Kireiyane, hey! You... Ah, shoot!
乗ってくれたらファストトラベルするよー。
Once you get on, I'll fast-travel!
キレイやねんが全然降りてこなくてさ。
Kireiyanen isn't landing at all!
やばい、もうちょっと1回飛ぶ。
Shoot, I'll just teleport right now.
OK, OK. やばいから1回飛ぶ。
OK, OK. It's dangerous, so I'm teleporting.
あ、よかった、よかった！お前、ちょっとこっち...
Ah, thank goodness! Hey, come over here...
飛んでるー！
It's flying!
1回飛んだ。ちょっとやばいから。
I teleported once. It was getting dangerous.
ありがとうございます。で、あとあれだ、プテラのサドル回収しに行かなきゃ。ござる、そいつに付けてたんだよな。
Thank you very much. And next, I have to go retrieve the Pteranodon saddle. Gozaru put it on that one, right?
これちょっとどうしようかな？
Wonder what I should do about this?
飛んでるー！よし。
Flying! All right.
ああ...
Ah...
一旦帰ってきた
I'm back for now.
イナさん
Ina-san.
狩ってる、やばい、やめて
It's attacking! Oh no, stop!
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
今、みんな大丈夫か？
Is everyone okay right now?
大丈夫か？
Is it alright?
テレポーターのところにパイロがずっといて、帰れないんだよね
A Pyro has been at the teleporter the whole time, so I can't return.
オッケー、じゃあちょっと待って
Okay, wait a second.
テレポート...あの、仮拠点の上のところ？
Teleport... you mean above the temporary base?
そう、あ、じゃなくて火山先、火山火山
Yeah, ah, actually at the volcano up ahead—volcano, volcano.
あ、火山先か
Ah, at the volcano.
そうそう、火山で帰れなくて今
Yeah, I'm stuck at the volcano right now.
ちょっと待ってよ、もう一回しまって
Wait a second, let me put it away once more.
取れました？
Did you get it?
あ、取れました
Ah, got it.
イナ先輩
Ina-senpai.
オッケーオッケー、ちょっと待って。離すわ、これで
Okay, okay, wait a sec. I'll lure it away with this.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
テレポートして帰ってもらって
Please teleport back.
あ、オッケーオッケー、テレポート
Ah, okay, okay, teleporting.
あ、行ける？行けそう？
Ah, can you make it? Does it look good?
オッケー
Okay.
飛べました
I warped back.
まだ...イナ行けるか？
Not yet... Ina, can you go?
あ、ええと...
Ah, um...
あ、トラベルします
Ah, I'll fast travel.
あ、降りちゃった
Ah, I dismounted.
ナイス！ナイス！ナイス！
Nice! Nice! Nice!
ナイス、行けた？
Nice, did you make it?
帰ってこれたー！
I made it back!
あ、よかったよかった。あ、よかった
Ah, thank goodness! Good.
アルゲンがあんなところにめっちゃ遠くに行っちゃったから
Because Argent flew so far away over there.
アルゲンいるよ、いるよ
Argent is here, it's right here.
あ、帰ってきたよアルゲン
Ah, Argent came back.
すみません、ちなみにファボリーズの死体って漁られたりしました？
Excuse me, by the way, did anyone loot Febreze's corpse?
ファボリーズは多分その拠点の近くにいるんだよね、多分
Febreze is probably near that base, I think.
死体が...なるほど。あ、サドルだけ回収しなきゃ、サドルが...
The corpse... I see. Ah, I need to at least recover the saddle...
待ってよ、サドルだけ回収しに...
Wait, to recover just the saddle...
あ、なんかめっちゃやばいやつが近くに...
Ah, there's a super dangerous thing nearby...
いる？拠点に？
It's there? At the base?
あ、そうですね
Ah, yes.
あ、あいつかまた！あのデカいやつか
Ah, that guy again! That huge one?
デカいやつです
It's the big guy.
デカいやつ
The big guy.
ええと...うわ、ちょっと
Um... whoa, wait.
ええ、もう！あ、やばいやばい
Geez, come on! Ah, oh no, oh no.
足がねえ
No legs.
あ、やばいやばい！一旦拠点から離れよう、拠点から離れよう
Ah, danger danger! Let's get away from the base, get away from the base.
遠くに行こう、遠く
Let's head far away, far away.
まずい、これ
This is bad.
まずい
Bad.
あ、ごめん、アルゲンもついてきちゃった
Ah, sorry, Argent followed along too.
これユティラで...食える？
With Yuty... can it eat it?
ユティラで行けるならユティラでやってほしいかも
If Yuty can handle it, I'd like you to fight with Yuty.
戦えるなら
If you can fight it.
戦えー！
Fight!
なんかこれ動かないんだけど。何このユティラ、動かない
Wait, this isn't moving. What's with this Yuty? It won't move.
は？何このユティラ？
Huh? What's with this Yuty?
これみんなヘイト取れた方がいいか？
Should we try to draw aggro for everyone?
引っかかってるか何かかな？
Is it stuck or something?
やばいよ、それ
That's dangerous!
よいしょ、間違えた
Oops, my bad.
イナのユティラも...よし
Ina's Yuty too... alright.
サドルなくなっちゃった...まぁいいか
The saddle is gone... Oh well.
なんでこのユティラ動かないんだ？
Why isn't this Yuty moving?
重傷最低限...
Minimum critical injury...
どのユティラだ？乗ってるやつ？
Which Yuty? The one you're riding?
あ、ユティもそもそも命令聞いてないよ
Ah, Yuty isn't listening to orders in the first place.
え、しまっちゃった？
Eh, did you put it away?
よいしょ
Up we go.
オッケー
Okay.
帰ってこれそう？行った方がいい？
Can you make it back? Should I go?
まずいな、これ
This is bad...
ちょっと待ってね。荷物預けて...
Wait a second. Let me store my items...
ま、この辺なくなってもいいか
Well, even if I lose this stuff, it's fine.
よいしょ
Alright.
行けるか？行ける？
Can you do it? Can you?
おお、頑張れー！
Ooh, good luck!
やばい、ゆーてぃー！
Oh no, Yuty!
オッケオッケオッケオッケ！
Okay okay okay okay!
今は他のやつ...
Now the others...
恐ろしいな。イキロ、イキロとか引っ張ってくんない？これ
That's terrifying. Can someone pull Ikiro over?
え、トワに追従になってるから、トワが追従切らないと無理かも
Eh, it's set to follow Towa, so unless Towa turns off follow, it might not work.
あ、そうだったっけ？
Ah, is that so?
うん、今ね、イキロはトワ追従...そうそう、オッケオッケオッケ
Yeah, right now Ikiro is following Towa... yeah, okay okay okay.
でもこいつ戦うになっちゃってるかな？
But is this guy set to attack?
やばい、やばい！
Oh no, oh no!
おとりにして無効にした。どこ？
I used it as a decoy and neutralized it. Where?
オッケーオッケー
Okay, okay.
どこだ？
Where is it?
オッケー、イキロ逃げました
Okay, Ikiro got away.
ナイス！逃げた？
Nice! It escaped?
みんなおる？
Is everyone here?
荷物取りに行ってる？
Are you going to get your items?
うーん、拠点のほうにでっかい恐竜がいて、そいつと今戦ってる
Um, there's a huge dinosaur by the base, and we're fighting it now.
あ、仮拠点？強すぎだろ
Ah, the temporary base? It's way too strong.
そうそう、仮拠点のほうです
Yeah, near the temporary base.
燃えた！
It burned!
生きてたー！ナイス！
It survived! Nice!
あーよかった、これでいけるか
Ah, thank goodness. Can we do this now?
で、これで...
And with this...
ユティラも...これ何が...何もないか
Yuty too... what does it have... nothing, huh?
生肉と皮か
Raw meat and hide.
ええと、これでござるさんのやつのサドルが取りに行けるかな？
Um, can we go get Gozaru-san's saddle with this?
あ、待って、ござるの自分の元の死体も取りに行かないとやばいかも
Ah wait, it might be bad if Gozaru doesn't go retrieve her original corpse too.
どこ、どこだ？元の死体
Where, where is it? The original corpse?
さっき一番最初で...
Earlier, at the very beginning...
あ、それはアルゲンの中に入ってる
Ah, that's inside Argent.
アルゲン1ですか？
Argent 1?
アルゲン1の中にない？そいつ連れて帰ってきたやつ
Isn't it inside Argent 1? The one we brought back.
あれ？入って...イナがどれに入れたかな？
Huh? It's not in... I wonder which one Ina put it in?
あ、私、私が持ってます！
Ah, I—I have it!
あ、持っていた！ありがとう！
Ah, you had it! Thank you!
オッケーオッケー、よかったよかった。助かりましたー！
Okay, okay, thank goodness! That saved me!
ほんならとりあえず...
Then for now...
ほんならこれでイベントがあるから行こっか
Then since there's an event now, shall we go?
ありがとうございます、行ってきます！
Thank you so much, off I go!
了解！助かりましたー！
Roger! Thanks for the help~!
一旦しま... いるもん、しまった方がいいかもな。
First, put away... Maybe I should store the stuff we need.
そうだね。
Yeah.
えっと... よいしょ。これかな？
Let's see... Yoisho. This one?
あ、白上のお荷物はまた後でこれ取りに行くか。
Ah, I'll go retrieve Shirakami's luggage later.
白上多分荷物置き去りだよな。
Shirakami probably left her stuff behind, right?
あー、よいしょ。
Ah, yoisho.
よっ、これで...
Yo, with this...
ほー、危ない。
Whew, that was close.
まに... 間に合わないよな？
We won't... won't make it in time, right?
あれ、っと...
Let's, see...
よいしょ。多分まに... いや、間に合うかこれ？行けるか？
Yoisho. Maybe in ti... No, can we make it in time? Can we go?
間に合うか？回す？
Will we make it? Spin it?
間に合った、危なかった。みんな行っちゃいなー。
Made it in time, that was close. Everyone go ahead~
おーい！
Oyyy!
ほい、よいしょ。
Hoi, yoisho.
めっちゃ荷物パンパンにさせてそうだったわ。
Looked like the inventory was totally stuffed.
荷物パンパン...
Inventory stuffed...
えーっと、海岸の方だっけ？
Let's see, was it towards the beach?
え、全部脱ぐんだっけ？
Wait, do we strip everything off?
イベント... なんかワープ先作ってくれたって言ってた気がするけど。
For the event... I think they said they made a warp destination for us.
あ、そうだ、そうだ。
Ah, right, right.
よいしょ、これかな？
Yoisho, is it this?
メディカルブリュー... あの...
Medical brew... um...
金属の鍋じゃないと無理っぽいな。
Seems impossible without a metal pot.
あと水を引っ張ってこないとキツいな。
And it's gonna be tough without piping in water.
革袋か何か水筒かなんか入れちゃって作るのは無理だった？
Was it not possible to make it by putting waterskins or canteens in?
これ足りないわ。相当大変、そのやり方だと。
It's not enough. That way is super tough.
あー、そうだね。革袋にいっぱい水入れて作ってたわ、一考。
Ah, yeah. I used to make it by filling tons of waterskins, just a thought.
そーっと... よいしょ。
Carefully... Yoisho.
あれ？ワープポイントどこだったっけ？
Huh? Where was the warp point again?
何これー？どこー？
What's this? Where is it?
ベイビー... 死んだかも？
The baby... might have died?
あ、ベイビー死んでしまった？
Ah, did the baby die?
多分...
Probably...
おふっ
Oof.
テレ... あれ？荷物ない？あれ？
Tele... Huh? No inventory? Huh?
オーマイガー
Oh my god.
あ、テレポートの近く... あー、テレポートの近くのほうか。
Ah, near the teleport... Ah, it's near the teleport.
じゃあここにサドルとかは入れておくかー。
Then I guess I'll leave saddles and stuff here.
わざわざあれかな...
I wonder if purposefully...
えーっと...
Let's see...
テレポの近く...
Near the telepo...
よっ
Yo.
あっ！死んでなくて大人になってた！
Ah! It didn't die, it grew into an adult!
あー！大人じゃん！
Ah! It's an adult!
よかった、よかった！よかったねー！
Thank goodness, thank goodness! That's great!
大人になってんだよね。
It became an adult, yeah.
大人になってた！
It grew up!
そっかー。ふぅ。
I see. Phew.
でも行けないんだけどこれ。
But I can't go with this.
荷物しまった時か。
Was it when we put the items away?
これイベント会場ってどこから行くの？
Where do you go to get to the event venue?
なんか... イベント会場... テレポーターから飛べるぐらいしか...
Like... to the event venue... all I know is you can teleport from the teleporter...
あった！
Found it!
あ、なるほど？
Ah, I see?
よいしょ。なんか一番下の欄に、無気力勢なんちゃらなんちゃらみたいなやつが書いて...
Yoisho. Like on the bottom row, it says something like "Apathy group blah blah blah"...
え、なんかワープでさ、テレポで行けないんだけど...
Wait, with the warp, I can't teleport though...
置いてっていいか、じゃあ。
Can I just leave my stuff behind then?
ワープのテレポができない？
You can't teleport to the warp?
無気力勢... お？
Apathy group... Oh?
ほな、置いてこ。な、何だここ？
Well then, let's leave it. Wh-What is this place?
体温低下...
Hypothermia...
もしかすると今混雑してるからかもね。
Maybe it's because it's crowded right now.
着いたけど...
I arrived, but...
うん、よいしょ。
Mm, yoisho.
にょいしょ。
Nyoisho.
手持ち全部置いてった方がいい？マジ？
Should I leave all my belongings behind? Really?
一旦置いてった方がいいかもね。
Maybe it's better to leave them behind for now.
オッケー、丸裸に...
Okay, stripped down naked...
よいしょ。
Yoisho.
あれ？こう来て...
Huh? Going this way...
死ぬかもしれんからってこと？
Is that because we might die?
うーん、一応ベッドタッチはあると思うけども。
Hmm, I think there are beds to respawn at, though.
うーん、でもこの辺なんかもう無くしてもいいなってものが結構...
Hmm, but there's a lot of stuff around here that I don't mind losing...
この障害物走中にお前らが死なないことを祈るぜ...
I pray you don't die during this obstacle course...
恐竜たちよ。
My dinosaurs.
こんな感じ？そっち。
Is it like this over there?
ね、ちょ、ぐちゃぐちゃになるけど、1回転送しようかな？
Hey, it's gonna be messy, but should I transfer them once?
えーっと、混ざっちゃってすみません状態です、ちょっと。
Let's see... Sorry, everything's mixed together, a little.
ね、10分前...
Yeah, 10 minutes before...
お、必ず拠点に置いて...
Oh, "Make sure to leave items at base"...
参加者景品あるんだったら行きたいなー。
If there are participation prizes, I want to go~
ねー！
Right~!
つかもうこの辺無くなってもいいまである。
Honestly, at this point I don't even care if I lose all this.
これで...
With this...
無くなってもいいならもういっそね。
If you don't mind losing it, might as well.
いっそね。
Might as well.
あ、水道ある。
Ah, there's running water.
わー、喉渇いてるわ。よいしょ。
Wah, I'm thirsty. Yoisho.
わーわーわー... これ飲めてるのか？
Wah wah wah... Am I drinking this?
飲め... 飲めてるのか？
Drink... Am I drinking it?
ああー！
Ahhh!
よし、これでワンポチって、あ、OK OK
Alright, just one click for this... Ah, okay, okay.
ういっし！
Alright!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
オッケー！
Okay!
これ1人1匹？あ、これ1人1棟ですか？
Is this one per person? Ah, is this one building per person?
はーい。ほうほうほう、馬。
Okay. I see, I see, a horse.
え、じゃあお前な！
Eh, then it's you!
これ持っちゃった、ここに。
I ended up holding this here.
よし。
Alright.
えーっと...
Let's see...
えっと、装備置き場...ああ。
Um, equipment storage... Ah.
うい。
Yeah.
ああ、みんな装備別に入れてんだね。
Ah, everyone puts their gear separately.
え、キロで障害物なんちゃら...
Eh, obstacles with kilometers or something...
うい、何色？
Yeah, what color?
お、シマウマじゃね？お前だけシマウマなんだが
Oh, isn't that a zebra? Why are you the only one with a zebra?
Cチーム、お肉。
Team C, meat.
ん？
Hmm?
レース用小動物...
Small animals for the race...
ちょっとお手洗い行ってきます！
I'm going to the restroom real quick!
はーい。
Okay.
お肉...
Meat...
あ、水道...水道。
Ah, water... water.
あ、これか。
Ah, this one.
オケオケオケ、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
あー、ステータスどうしようかなー
Ah, what should I do with the stats?
アビなければ、ええ、馬の...
If there are no abilities, um, the horse's...
ええ、どうします？
Um, what should we do?
スタミナ...
Stamina...
やはりこっちか？
Is it this after all?
うわわわわわ...
Whoa-whoa-whoa...
スタミナか？
Stamina?
今これで1万ぐらいの...
Right now with this, around 10,000...
いるー
It's here~
スタミナかなー
Stamina, I guess...
何がいいんだ、これ？
What's good for this?
もうスタミナじゃね？
Isn't stamina the way to go?
ただヒットポイントちょっと増やしとこないと怖い気がする。
Though I feel scared if I don't increase HP a little.
えっと、着...飛んでるし...
Um, wearing... and it's flying...
え、障害物...え？
Eh, obstacles... eh?
念には念を...
Just to be safe...
どうしようかなー
What should I do?
むずくね？
Isn't this tough?
どうするかなー
What should we do?
いや、これ体力上げたところでさ、回復しきらないよな。生肉ないし。
Even if you raise HP, it won't fully recover, right? Since there's no raw meat.
あ、馬だからベリーか。
Ah, since it's a horse, it's berries.
はい。
Yes.
なんとも言えなくない？これ。
Can't really tell, right?
生肉ないんだよな。
There's no raw meat, after all.
あり？
Huh?
焼き肉食え、食え。
Eat cooked meat, eat.
3000くらいまで上げて...
Raise it to around 3,000...
でもシマウマはまだ...
But the zebra is still...
どうなんだろうねー
I wonder how it is.
もうスタミナ全振りでいいんじゃない？
Wouldn't it be fine to just dump everything into stamina?
シマウマはある？
Do we have a zebra though?
もう全部...あ、あんま測らない...えへへ
Just all... Ah, it doesn't measure much... hehe.
水のエーム...
Water aim...
あの、イベントの所、どこですか？
Um, where is the event place?
愛着持って...
Have some attachment...
ミスったーーー！帰ってきたよー！
I messed up! I'm back!
馬？馬に？
Horse? To the horse?
何がいいかなー、馬の名前。
What would be good, for the horse's name?
爆速エリート。
Bakusoku Elite.
お前爆速被りしたわ、あかん。
You duplicated "Bakusoku", no good.
やばい、もう命名が...
Oh no, naming is already...
名前、何にしようかなー
What should I name it...
名前何にしようかなー
待って、あずちゃんのシマウマじゃなかった。
Wait, AZKi's wasn't a zebra.
シマウマ...
Zebra...
あずちゃんのシマウマ...
AZKi's zebra...
やっぱこれやな、レースって言ったらな。
It's gotta be this, when it comes to racing.
何？
What?
マッハ高根。
Mach Takane.
マッハ高根？
Mach Takane?
シマウマだ、シマウマ。
It's a zebra, a zebra.
シマシマ...
Stripes...
って何？
...is what?
あの、体力を上げたら馬さんが...
Um, if you raise HP, the horse...
少しにしましょうか？
Shall we keep it brief?
あ、えっとどこ...
Ah, wait, where...
でもお肉...
Still, the meat...
体力は、上げた分マックス値は上がるけど...
HP max increases by leveling it, but...
回復は... え、僕らはケーキしか...
as for healing... we only have Veggie Cakes...
あー
Ah...
野菜ケーキしか回復しないようになっておりまして...
They only recover with Sweet Veggie Cakes...
え、全員がお肉上げてた？はい、ということで回復することはできません。
Wait, did everyone give them meat? So they can't heal.
気付いてごめんな
Sorry for worrying you guys.
応援してる、応援！
I'm cheering for you, cheering!
でもさ、危険は...
But still, danger...
ないんじゃない？危険はないんじゃない？
Isn't there none? There's no danger.
ないでしょう、あ、確かに大丈夫か
Probably not. Ah, that's true, it should be fine.
うん、大丈夫か...
Yeah, it should be fine...
乗っからない限りは。終わった！
As long as you don't get trapped. Done!
はーい
Okay.
とりあえず体力... 体力振りまーすねー
For now, HP... I'll pump HP points, okay?
ドキドキ
Heart's pounding.
あ、体力減ってはいないので安心してくださいねー
Ah, their HP hasn't decreased, so don't worry!
ほらかの馬なんかボロボロじゃない？歴戦個体みたいな
Look, isn't that horse battered? Like a battle-scarred veteran.
いや本当、すげぇ、ボロボロ
No really, amazing, all battered.
パッカパッカ
Clippity-clop.
何で？変身中だ！
Why? It's transforming!
血が出てるよー！血が出てるよー！
It's bleeding! It's bleeding!
あ、出た
Ah, it is.
血が出てるよー！
It's bleeding!
なんか右クリックで後ろ蹴りできる
Apparently right-clicking lets you kick backwards.
嘘だ！ビシビシ、バチ！
No way! *whip whip, pow!*
何で練習してんだ、この馬。邪魔できるってことかな？
Why is this horse practicing? Does it mean we can sabotage?
邪魔できる？Cでもなんかヒヒーンってしてくれるよ
Sabotage? Pressing 'C' makes it neigh too.
C！ヒヒーン！
'C'! Neigh!
え、でもちょっと待って、参加する人これだけなの？
Wait a second, is this everyone participating?
なんか、Bチーム...
Like, Team B...
もしかして、他のみんなやってるのか？
Could the rest of them be doing it?
子役はさ、参加賞よりもさって言うところがあるかもしれない...
Maybe they care about more than just the participation prize...
いやいやいや、そんなー
No no no, no way.
うちのチームだけ全員参加してんの？
Is our team the only one all participating?
全員参加？うちのチームだけ？
All participating? Just our team?
全員参加で
All participating.
優勝狙いなので
Because we're aiming for victory.
はーい、それでは今馬に乗った人で、まだ準備してない人に案内しまーす！
Alright, for those on horses who haven't prepared yet, I'll explain!
はーい！
Okay!
はい、えーっと装備など失いたくないものを持ってきてしまっている人は、
If you brought equipment or items you don't want to lose,
それぞれの各チームに装備置き場があるので、その金庫の中に入れてくださーい。
there's gear storage for each team, so please put them inside the vaults.
囚われてるし。金庫？どれだっけ？
We're trapped in here. Vault? Which one was it?
はーい
Okay.
ちなみにこの馬が入ってたあのポットは入れちゃっていいんですか？装備のところに
By the way, can we put the cryopod the horse was in into the equipment vault?
あ、もらっちゃっても大丈夫ですよ
Ah, you can just keep that!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
I have no idea what's going on.
おー！
Oh!
ステータスは自由に振っていただいて構いません！
Feel free to allocate the stats however you like!
いっぱいなってきた
It's getting crowded.
え、体力を振った際に、え、血まみれになるんですが、
When you level up HP, it will look all bloody,
体力減ってるわけではないのでご安心くださーい！
but its HP hasn't decreased, so don't worry!
はーい
Okay!
ドラゴンの奴かっこいい
The dragon looks so cool.
目指すわ、優勝目指すわ！
I'm aiming for it, aiming for victory!
I thought so.
あとは壁際に冷蔵庫がありましてお肉が入ってますので、そこから食料と水を取ってください。
Also, there are refrigerators by the wall with meat, so please grab food and water from there.
みおちゃん無理しないでね！ありがとう！
Mio-chan, don't push yourself! Thank you!
酔いそう、あきちゃん！
I might get sick. Aki-chan!
レベルアップしていいの？
Can we level up?
うん、好きにステータス振って大丈夫！
Yeah, feel free to level up any stats!
ステータス好きに振っていいらしいよ！
They said we can distribute stats however we like!
ステータス振っていいのかな、で
So we can level up stats, then.
Ina, you can level up your dinosaur.
Ah, yeah. ほんとだ
Ah, yeah. True.
どうする？スタミナぶっぱするか？
What should I do? Dump it all into stamina?
もう始まるのかな？もうすぐ始まるよー！
Is it starting already? It's starting soon!
お集まりいただいた皆様、ご自分の各チームのメンバーで参加する予定だけどまだたどり着けてない人いるかいないか確認お願いしまーす！
Everyone gathered here, please check if there are team members planning to participate who haven't arrived yet!
Bチーム！Aチーム揃ってます！
Team B! Team A is all here!
参加したい、同じチームのメンバーでたどり着いてない人はいますかー？
Is there anyone from your team who wants to join but hasn't arrived yet?
えーっと、Bチームはいません！
Um, no one missing for Team B!
今来ましたー！みんな来てる
Just got here! Everyone's here.
Cチーム揃ってます！はーい！
Team C is all here! Okay!
うん！
Yup!
部屋の中揃ってるかな？もし今来てもオッケーです！
Is everyone in the room? It's fine even if you just arrived now!
あ、今来た人たち、ここの、え、Equusを一人一匹取ってもらって、好きにステータスを振ってください！
Ah, those who just arrived, take one Equus per person and allocate the stats however you like!
え、食料と水は後ろにあるので各自で補給してください！
Food and water are in the back, so please restock on your own!
めっちゃ跳ねる！はーい！
It jumps so high! Okay!
名前つけてもいいんだよー
You can give it a name too~
あれ、これ座るのかな？
Huh, does it sit down?
シマウマなツバちゃんたち名前つけてもいいんだよー
You can name the zebra-like ones too~
名前つけてるよ！
I am naming it!
はーい、それでは、21時になりましたので皆様！
Alright, it is now 21:00, everyone!
間に合わない... はーい！
Won't make it... Okay!
今からルール説明を行っていきたいので、声が聞こえる範囲にお越しくださーい！
I'll be explaining the rules now, so please come within hearing range!
大丈夫です！はーい！聞き取れる
All good! Okay! I can hear you.
それでは、あ、オッケーオッケー
Now then... Ah, okay, okay.
ルール説明させていただきます！
I will now explain the rules!
はーい！
Okay!
はーい
Okay.
はい。え、皆さんまず馬の準備大丈夫ですね？ステータスも振ってますか？
Alright. First, is everyone ready with their horses? Have you allocated your stat points?
はい / はーい / 大丈夫です
Yes. / Yep. / All good.
はい。えー装備や持ち物、失く、失いたくないもの
Okay. If you have any equipment or items you don't want to lose...
手前のスロットにも入ってるなど忘れ物があったら右の、え、装備置き場使ってください。
...or left in your hotbars, please use the gear storage on the right.
はーい / はい
Got it. / Okay.
はい、それでは、えー、ルール、レースの説明します。
Alright, now I'll explain the rules of the race.
はーい
Okay.
え、ピンク色のゲートがレースのルートに設置してあるので、
There are pink gates set up along the race route,
そこをくぐりながらゴールまで競い合ってください。
so please race towards the goal while passing through them.
はい / はーい
Okay. / Got it.
はい、ゲートは必ず通ってください。
Make sure you pass through every gate.
あーなるほどね / うんうん
Ah, I see. / Mhm.
Yep, follow the gate.
通らずにショートカットした場合は引き返してくぐり直してください。
If you take a shortcut without passing through, you must go back and pass through it.
Make sure you go through the gates, don't take shortcuts.
集会場の前に、え、白い床が敷いてあるピンクのゲートがゴールになります。
In front of the gathering area, the pink gate with a white floor will be the goal.
ほうほう。もう一回言って？もう一回、し、白い…？
Ooh. Say that again? One more time, wh-white...?
集会場前に白い床が敷いてあるピンクのゲートがあるので、そこがゴールポイントになってます。
In front of the gathering area, there's a pink gate with a white floor laid down, so that's the finish line.
なるほどね！ / あーなるほど。
I see! / Ah, gotcha.
はい、集会場目の前みたいな感じになってるので、おそらく分かるかと思います。
It's right in front of the gathering area, so I think it'll be obvious.
はーい。 / はい。
Okay. / Got it.
え、もしも途中で馬が死んでしまったり、自分が死んでしまっても…
Also, if your horse dies along the way, or if you die...
やばい、やばい。
Uh oh, that's bad.
2回まで復活できます。
You can respawn up to two times.
2回！ / 2 retries?
Two times! / 2 retries?
そんな危ないの？ / そんな死ぬんだ。
Is it that dangerous? / Wow, people die that much?
どうかな？
Who knows?
My horse is gonna die...
崖とかあるもんね。 / うん、崖もあるし。
There are cliffs and stuff. / Yeah, cliffs too.
はい。もし、えー、その復活したい場合ですね、復活する場合は集会場で一度復活してから
Yes. If you need to respawn, you respawn once at the gathering area,
テレポートでスタート地点まで戻ってきてください。
and then teleport back to the starting point.
えー！ / 大変だ。 / なるほど。
Whoa! / That sounds tough. / I see.
テレポートで戻ってきて…
Come back via teleport...
I mean, I guess it'll show where I died last, right?
あ、ちょっと待って。もしかしたらもうちょっと便利なところが開発間に合ってる可能性があるので、ちょっと一瞬確認していいですか？
Wait a second. A more convenient option might have been finished in time, so may I check for a second?
あ、なるほど。 / はーい。
Ah, I see. / Sure.
I just happened to be on the teleporter... Wait, someone teleported?
あ、わ、わ、わ！右クリック押しちゃいました！すみません！
Ah, whoa whoa whoa! I right-clicked! I'm sorry!
蹴られた？蹴られたわ。
Did you get kicked? You got kicked.
少々お待ちを。 / はーい。
Please hold on a moment. / Okay.
こぎぎじゃれられるのかな？ / じゃれるかもね。
Can you play with the pony? / Maybe you can.
なにこれ？ステータスやば！ / 暴れ馬がいます。暴れ馬。 / 暴れてるねー！
What is this? These stats are crazy! / There's a wild horse! A wild horse. / It's going wild!
暴れ馬。後脚が暴れてます。
Wild horse. Its hind legs are going crazy.
はい、失礼しましたー！
Alright, sorry about that!
無抵抗にした方がいいのかな？
Should we set them to passive?
ま、降りる場合は。
Well, if you get off.
はい、すみません。お待たせいたしました。もうちょっとでみんなが復帰しやすいところが開発間に合ったというところで…
Alright, sorry to keep you waiting. It turns out a more convenient respawn spot was ready just in time...
おー。
Ohh.
え、もしも死んでしまった場合は、えーと、集会場で復活するんですが…
So if you happen to die, you would normally respawn at the gathering area, but...
あ、違うわ。復活する際の場所が、えーと、集会場もしくはここのレース会場を選べるようになってます。
Ah, no. When respawning, you can now choose either the gathering area or this race venue.
おー！
Ooh!
なので、こちらの会場を選択してここに復帰してきてください。
So please select this venue to respawn right back here.
なるほど！ / はーい。
I see! / Okay.
もし間違って集会場とか行ってしまったらちょっとテレポーターまで行ってもらうか、自分で死んでもらって、ここに復帰する形でお願いします。
If you accidentally respawn at the gathering area, please either use the teleporter or die again to respawn here.
はーい。 / はい。
Okay. / Got it.
で、レースなんですが、5位の人まで、5位の人がゴールした時点でレースの集計を締め切ります。
As for the race, results will be locked in once the 5th place racer crosses the finish line.
へー。 / はい。
I see. / Okay.
そのアナウンス後、3分後に表彰式を行います。
3 minutes after that announcement, we'll hold the awards ceremony.
はい。 / ほい。
Okay. / Got it.
で、えー、ゴールできなかった方も参加賞がございます。
And even if you can't finish the race, there is a participation prize.
おー！ / ありがたい！
Ooh! / Awesome!
え、参加賞はゴール地点に参加賞の金庫を置いてありますので、それを1人1つ取って…
There is a vault with participation prizes at the goal, so please take one per person...
えー、めっちゃええやん！ / わーい、なんだろう？
Whoa, that's awesome! / Yay, what could it be?
はい。表彰式行いますがアナウンスする形で行いますので、そのままもうゴールして、まあ攻略に戻ってもらっても大丈夫です。
We will hold the award ceremony via announcement, so after finishing, you can head straight back to boss progression.
はーい。 / よーし。
Okay. / Alright.
なので、そのままで、5位の人で集計は終わってしまうんですが、その後レースを完走してもいいですし、そのままミッションに戻ってもらっても大丈夫です。
So after 5th place finishes, the tally ends, but you can still finish the course or just head back to missions.
はーい。 / はい。
Okay. / Yes.
1位から5位の人には賞品がありまして、えー、終わった後にアキロゼから私に行きます。
There are prizes for 1st through 5th place, which Akirose will deliver to me to hand out.
はーい。 / はい。
Okay. / Got it.
ということで、皆様準備は大丈夫でしょうか？
With that said, is everyone ready?
はーい！ / 質問です！
Yes! / Question!
はい、質問受け付けます。
Yes, taking questions.
馬の食べ物って空っぽのままですか？
Should the horse's food inventory stay empty?
はい、ありません。そのままでーす。
Yes, no food. Leave it as is.
わかりましたー！ / はーい。
Understood! / Okay.
とにかく走る。
Just gotta run.
すみませーん！
Excuse me!
はい。
Yes.
死んじゃった場合、馬はどうすれば？
If it dies, what should we do with the horse?
えーと、馬はですね、後ろの金庫に入ってるのから...
Um, as for the horses, from the vault behind...
新しく補充するみたいな...
Like replenishing a new one...
補充して、はい。
Replenish it, yes.
了解でーす。 / 了解です。 / はーい。
Understood. / Roger that. / Okay.
なので2回まで、そのような形で復帰してレースに戻ることができます。
So you can respawn like that and rejoin the race up to two times.
はーい。
Okay.
今多分血まみれになってる人は、えっと減ってるように感じるかもしれないんですが、
For those who look covered in blood right now, it might feel like their health is low,
基本的には、体力は減ってる...あ、増えた分、血まみれになってるだけで、
but basically, the health... ah, it's just bloody because its max HP increased.
最初から体力は減ってないので、安心してください。
The HP hasn't actually decreased from the start, so don't worry.
はーい。 / 分かった。
Okay. / Got it.
では間もなくレーススタートしていきますので、こちらの扉が、開きましたらスタートになります。
Well then, the race will start shortly, so once these doors open, that will be the start.
ええー！ / うわー！
Whoa--! / Wow!
Okay.
なんか最初に行き過ぎたらあれなんじゃない？
Isn't it bad if we rush out too far at the start?
行き過ぎ怖いな、これ。
Rushing too far is scary.
ドキドキだね。 / 頑張ろうぜ。 / 行くぜ！
My heart's racing. / Let's do our best. / Here we go!
レースを問題なく完走できた場合、最速でゴールできる可能性は、8分前後でゴールできるかと...
If you finish the race without issues, the fastest possible time to reach the goal would be around 8 minutes...
ええー？！ / 長ーい！
What?! / That's so long!
Fastest expected is like 8 minutes?
相当走るね。
We're going to run quite a bit.
それでは、レース...
Alright then, the race...
最速で8分。 / 行きましょう。
Fastest is 8 minutes. / Let's go.
スタート！
Start!
うわーー！ / 行けーー！
Whoaaa! / Goooo!
あ、ピンクのゲートあれだ。
Ah, there's the pink gate.
あれ？ / こっちじゃない？
Huh? / Isn't it this way?
めっちゃ... / きゃー！
It's so... / Eek!
A lot of people.
めっちゃダメだよー！ / 絶対行けるよ！絶対行けるよ！
That's no good! / We can definitely make it! Definitely make it!
草で見えなくなった！
I can't see because of the grass!
絶対行けるよ。
We can definitely make it.
Oh, it's where I spawned!
おやおや、お祭り。 / 引っかかってるぞ。
Uh oh, it's a festival. / People are getting stuck.
やばいこれ。 / あ、ラグがね。
This is bad. / Ah, the lag.
ラグもあるんだ。
There's lag too, huh.
8分か...
8 minutes, huh...
おお！
Oh!
めっちゃ跳べる！
It can jump so high!
こいつ足速すぎるだろ、こいつ。
This guy's way too fast!
あははは！
Hahaha!
えぐいえぐいえぐい！ / なんだこれ！
Insane, insane, insane! / What is this?!
うわーー！
Whoaaa!
先輩？！
Senpai?!
おっと...ここ？
Oops... Here?
え、どこ行けばいい？
Eh, where should I go?
この辺？
Around here?
Wait, should I go back to camp?
ここ？
Here?
Gathering point or the start?
ここ？
Here?
あ、ここか。
Ah, here.
誰かこっち向いてる人がいる。
Someone is looking over this way.
えーと、アミノ...
Um, Amino...
行ける行ける。
We can do this, we can do this.
回復してほしい...
I want it to heal...
HP...取っとくか。
HP... I should take it.
イエーイ。
Yay.
And then... oh.
ええーー
Ehhh--
これもう1回ステータス、配分しなきゃいけないのかな？
Do I need to allocate its stat points again?
テイク2？
Take 2?
More level up.
Is there like a way to access the tame inventory while riding? Do I always have to get off?
うーん... F?
Hmm... F?
なるほど。
I see.
ええ...
Ehh...
High jump over the water...
I want to assume that's how you kind of go about it, but...
I feel like I'm gonna die again.
うーん...
Hmm...
おっ
Oh.
ヤバイ！
Oh no!
ヤバイね！
It's bad!
ヤバイ！
Oh no!
キャーーー！
Kyaaah!
My horse...
いやー、もう無理でしょうー
Man, that's impossible!
詰まってると、あそこからもう出れないよね。
If it's stuck there, you can't even get out, right?
バグってる？
Is it bugged?
倒せそうな気もするけどなー
I feel like we could defeat it though...
なんかね、帰って別のことしたほうが... あ、おかしい
Like, maybe it's better to head back and do something else... Ah, wait.
I don't think HP is really, uh...
...gonna help much.
ええ...
Ehh...
え？あそこ普通慌てずって感じなのかなー？
Eh? Are you just supposed to stay calm through there?
あああああーーー！
Aaaaaah!
あはは、誰かが走って行ったぞ、今。
Ahaha, someone just ran past right now!
ヤバイ！あー良かった、美味しかった！オッケー！
Oh no! Ah, thank goodness, that was delicious! Okay!
美味しかった？
Delicious?
何も持ってないよね？
You're not carrying anything, right?
はい。
Yes.
まあまあ。
Well, okay.
Jump...
うーん... どこまで...
Hmm... I wonder how far...
...ジャンプか... できるか...
...I can jump...
お、ラグか？
Oh, is it lag?
うーん、いや...
Hmm, no...
あ、ジャンプして行けるけど...
Ah, I can jump through, but...
あ、こっちか。
Ah, this way?
ああ、どうしよう...
Ah, what should I do...
行ってみるか。
Let's give it a try.
お、回って行ってみよ...
Oh, let's try going around...
あ、痛たたたた...
Ah, ouch ouch ouch ouch...
抜けた！
I made it through!
HPちょっと少ないけど...
My HP is a bit low, though...
Terror bird
怖いよ
I'm scared.
え、怖い
Eh, scary.
うわっ
Whoa...
え、また 何かある
Huh, there's something again.
怖い
Scary.
ちょっと... 見よっか
Let me... take a look.
チャンスだ。ジャンプして、行け、行け行け行け！
Now's the chance. Jump, and go, go, go, go!
寒い、寒い
Cold, it's cold.
大丈夫
I'm okay...
Ah, I forgot to bring some meat.
なが... 長い...
So... long...
もう 何かある、怖い
There's something again, scary...
え、これ...
Huh, this...
The end?
間に合った？
Did I make it in time?
行けた？
Did I get through?
うわー！
Whoa!
あ、みんなポジション、えっと、ちょっと調べてみてくださいねー
Ah, everyone, please go ahead and check your positions, okay?
はーい
Okay!
間に合ったー！
I made it in time!
グラスをお取りくださーい
Please take the drink!
ありがとー。こんなボロボロ...
Thank you. I'm all battered...
オズミ先輩勝った？
Did Ozumi-senpai win?
やるやんけ
Nice job!
いや、みんなポンポンな、ボロボロ...
No, everyone's completely battered...
惜しいー！
So close!
壊れて、壊れた...
Broken, it broke...
生えてた
It healed.
思い直るんか？
Does it heal back?
どこかにしよ
Let's put it somewhere...
わ、これ参加賞か？
Whoa, is this a participation prize?
おー！参加賞！
Ohh! A participation prize!
参加賞あるんだ？
There's a participation prize?
参加賞ある！イノシシ？
There's a participation prize! A boar?
もうみんなお馬さんがズタボロだよ
Everyone's horse is totally battered.
ボロボロ。これイノシシかな？
Battered. Is this a boar?
ボロボロでしょう
Of course it's battered.
やってきたー！
I'm here!
あれ？窓？
Huh? A window?
はい、参加賞お受け取りください
Yes, please take your participation prize.
アルマ... アルマさんも？
Arma... Armas too?
どんこれ？どうやって回復...
What's this? How do you heal...
ドア閉めたのによー！
Even though I closed the door!
Is this the prize?
一応持って帰るか
Guess I'll take it back just in case.
Armadoggo.
これにて第1回うまレースを終了いたします。集計結果その後、1位から5位発表していきます。
With this, the 1st Horse Race has concluded! After tallying the results, I'll announce 1st through 5th place.
はーい！
Okay!
完走賞はないんですか？完走賞は？
Is there no prize for finishing the race? A finisher's prize?
完走賞は、参加賞となっております。
The finisher's prize is the participation prize.
えー！
Ehh?!
完走しなくても参加賞でございます。
Even if you didn't finish, you still get the participation prize.
知らなかったのにー！
And I didn't even know!
戻りー！
I'm back!
おかえりー！
Welcome back!
こいつ何だ？
What is this guy?
アルマ... アルマドッゴか
Arma... Armadoggo, huh.
犬！犬だよ、犬！
Dog! It's a dog, a dog!
すごかったねー、なんか
That was pretty wild.
なんかもらえた？
Did you get something?
最初のやつでみんなドコドコ死んでいったからね
Everyone was dropping dead all over the place right at the start.
かわいい！
Cute!
寝袋...
Sleeping bag...
寝袋を運んでくれる。へえー！
It carries a sleeping bag for you. Huh!
水？
Water?
This is supposed to be a...
はい、皆様、それではこちらにて乾杯の準備に移っていただきたいと思います！
Alright everyone, please get ready over here for a toast!
回復しないと無理だよ、乾杯
We can't toast unless we heal up.
え、じゃあキミ、ご飯はあれかな、あれかな？
So what do you eat? Is it that?
生肉？
Raw meat?
...集計結果の発表を...
...the announcement of the results...
はい、すごいレースだったね
Yeah, that was an amazing race.
誰が優勝したんだ？
Who won?
次は勝つ！
Next time I'll win!
まず5位から発表させて...
First, let me announce 5th place...
いや、次はゴールしたいな！
No, next time I just want to cross the finish line!
次はゴールしたい！
I want to reach the goal next time!
はい！
Alright!
お、すごい！4位だ！
Oh, awesome! 4th place!
あ、4位だ！おめでとう！
Ah, 4th place! Congrats!
クリスピー？
Crispy?
クリスピーリオネです
It's a Crispy Rione.
クリスピリーって何だろう？
What is a Crispy Rione?
どうなる？
What does it do?
一体何だったんだろ...
What on earth was that...
はい、こちらの上位入賞者の方たちには、アキのほうから直接そちらのお荷物にお渡しにいきます。
Yes, for the top place winners, I will go directly and put them into your inventories.
あ、あそこにいたんだ
Ah, they were over there.
続きまして、第2位の発表です。
Moving on, the announcement for 2nd place.
パイロテイム行くか、先に洞窟行くかどっちする？
Should we tame a Pyromane or go to the cave first?
あー、パイロも欲しいけどもー！
Ah, I want a Pyromane too, though!
ぺこらー！
Pekora!
洞窟かな、洞窟行っちゃうか。洞窟行くか。
Maybe the cave? Let's go to the cave. Cave it is.
ユキフクロウって、このARKの世界、ユキフクロウっていたんでしたっけ？となっております。
Snow Owls... are there Snow Owls in this ARK world? It seems so.
水もらいに行こう。あ、いる！すげー！
Let's go get water. Ah, there are! Awesome!
そして、今回の...
And for this race...
ここだったんだ、ラグナロクにいるんだったっけ？いつも。どうなんだろう。
They're here? Aren't they on Ragnarok usually? I wonder.
優勝は、大空スバルー！
The winner is... Oozora Subaru!
おー！
Oohh!
ユキフクロウいるんかな？どうなんだろ。
Are there Snow Owls? I wonder.
しゅばしゅばしゅば！しゅばしゅば！
Shuba shuba shuba! Shuba shuba!
非常に何にでも使える、ボス戦でも使える...
It's extremely useful for everything, even in boss battles...
ぺこちゃんところがサドメ捕まえてたからね。
Peko-chan's group caught a Shadowmane, after all.
捕まえたのが報酬になるのかなんなのか。
I wonder if what we caught is the prize or what.
あ、サドメじゃねえ、ちがうちがう、パイロ。水取ってきます。
Ah, not a Shadowmane, wait no, Pyromane. Going to grab water.
はいよー。
Alright.
えー、参加賞を受け取り済みの方は、こちらのピンクから1人1つ取って帰ってください。
Um, those who already received their participation prize, please take one from this pink vault and head back.
これからも引き続きロゼキャんARK、ミッション攻略楽しんでください！
Please continue to enjoy RoseCan ARK and taking on missions!
はーい！ありがとうー！
Okay! Thank you!
メガテリウム、一旦グリフィンもらっとこ。
Megatherium... I'll grab a Griffin for now.
キャンプ装備ってどこにあるんだ？
Where's the camping gear?
うん、すごい。
Yeah, awesome.
おっしゃ、マナガルム！
All right, Managarmr!
マナガルム今なんか報酬だった？もしかして。
Was a Managarmr just a prize by any chance?
ここにあるよな。すごっ！
It's right here. Whoa!
確かにありがとー！
Indeed, thank you!
Anya!
とんでもないやつゲットしたやん。
You got something incredible.
あ、オッケー！了解！
Ah, okay! Got it!
一旦なんかいったん...
For now, some...
マナガルム強いからな。
Managarmr is strong, after all.
やばい、声、声聞こえない。
Oh no, I can't hear your voice.
I can hear you.
I just have too many voices in my head.
オッケー。
Okay.
ちょっと待ってね。
Wait a second.
私の方が聞こえてないかも。
Maybe it's me who can't hear.
ぺこちゃん？
Peko-chan?
Anyaaaa!
あのさ、ペンがさ、恐竜拠点できたらしいからさ。
Hey, Pen apparently finished the dino base, so...
Can hear people clearly.
ちょっと森行って、ラコスと一緒に行ってさ、あの新拠点にさ、穴開けて...
I went into the forest with Racos, and to that new base, we made a hole...
ええー？
Ehh?!
すいませーん、お願いしまーす。
Excuse me, please!
1個、1個...
One, just one...
あれ？ムーナ、箱すー！
Huh? Moona, box!
ムーナ？
Moona?
えーとね、From now... eh...
Um, from now... eh...
Hey.
Alright.
It's time for me to go back to my tame.
ちょっと待ってね。
Wait a second.
あ、でも穴掘るぐらいはそんなに遠くないんだけど。
Ah, but digging a hole isn't that far off.
なんか、心臓の近くに穴開けてくださいって言われてるので。
They told me to dig a hole near the heart.
Silent communication.
心臓の近く？
Near the heart?
うん。
Yeah.
えと、うさぎに...穴どこに開ければ...
Um, to the rabbit... where should I dig the hole...
もらいに行くか。
Guess I'll go get it.
Good luck Anya.
わかんない。
I don't know.
I forgot what we were doing, to be honest.
あそこ行ける？
Can we go over there?
あそこ行けるよ
We can go over there.
教えて、どこだー？
Tell me, where is it?
Farewell, Adia.
で、今ね、ベエちゃんと一緒に行こうとしてんのかな？
Are they trying to go together with Bae-chan now?
Can we go to the dino place, where we put down the bed?
Okay.
よいしょ。ここだね。
Up we go. Here it is.
あ、本当だ！かなでー！かなでいるー？
Ah, it's true! Kanade! Kanade, are you here?
いいじゃん！
Sounds good!
やったー！
Yay!
戻りましたー
We're back~
おかえりー
Welcome back~
でもマジでさあ、ボタンの途中のさあ
But seriously, in the middle of Botan's...
ジャンプすると体力減るぞみたいな
Like, "If you jump, your health will decrease."
あれめっちゃナイスアシストだったわ
That was such a nice assist.
でしょ？あの平地でジャンプしないと、高所でジャンプすると着地ダメージが
Right? If you don't jump on flat ground, jumping from high places gives landing damage...
そう、着地ダメージがね、意外と入っちゃって
Yeah, you take surprisingly a lot of fall damage.
ねえ！気がついてなかったわ、それ！
Right?! I hadn't realized that!
危ねえ！助かったわー！危ね危ね
That was close! That saved us! So close, so close.
で、洞窟行こうかなーって
So, I'm thinking of heading to a cave.
そう、攻略
Yeah, to explore it.
何の...あの服、服着ると言うか、服じゃなくて...えっと恐竜
What... like wearing gear, or not gear... um, dinosaurs.
あ、恐竜？何がいいかなーて
Ah, dinosaurs? Wondering what would be good.
えーと、全然そういえばミッションを多分こなせてないんだよね
Um, come to think of it, I really haven't completed any missions.
あ、ちょっとあれしよう
Ah, let me do that quick.
ミッションこなせてない。全然埋めてなくてやばい
Haven't done missions. It's bad that I haven't cleared any.
埋まなきゃ、子育てしなきゃ
Gotta clear them, gotta do breeding...
自分のやつどこあったっけ？
Where was my stuff again?
えっと、どれを出すんだっけ？
Um, which one was I taking out?
ちょっと集会場行きます
I'll head to the meeting area for a bit.
はーい
Okay~
で、まあ、グリフィンかメガテリか...
Well, Griffin or Megatherium...
あ、メガッ、使えるのメガテリか。まあ言うても全然
Ah, Mega-, the usable one is Megatherium. Well, even so...
洞窟、無理、テリジノか。テリジノで行けるんじゃないかなと思ってるが無理？
For the cave... no, Therizino? I was thinking we could go with Therizino, but is it impossible?
行けそうだけどね。みんなで出せば行けんじゃない？
Seems doable though. Shouldn't we be fine if everyone brings one?
かなーと。うんうん
I think so. Yeah, yeah.
どの、どのやつ？一番最初のやつ？
Which, which one? The very first one?
えっと、肉食だっけ、行こうって言ってたのは
Um, the Carnivore cave, was that the one we talked about going to?
イナの、犬が
Ina's... dog...
あの狡猾のアーティファクト取りに行く話のあれ？
The one about getting the Artifact of the Clever?
そうそうそうそう！
Yes, yes, exactly!
とりあえず飛べるやつと
For now, a flying one and...
飛べるやつと、まあプテラとかでもいいし、飛べるやつと一匹なんか戦えるやつ持ってけばいいんじゃないかな
A flying one—like a Ptera is fine—and one fighting dino should be good to bring, I think.
だよね。プテラ大丈夫か。一旦それ
Right. Is Ptera okay? For now, I'll...
追従、追従するか
Set to follow, should I make it follow?
ならメガテリさん連れてくか
Then I'll bring Megatherium-san along.
来ないな
He won't come.
狭すぎて来れない
It's too narrow for him to come through!
うちの犬が
Our dog...
後ろばっかだな
He's just backing up.
これ追従か何かで外出てこれない？
Can't he get outside with follow or something?
えーと、あ、行ける、行ける行ける
Umm... Ah, he can, he can make it.
There! Good dog.
こっちまでとりあえず行っちゃってー
Head over this way for now~
で、洞窟が、えーと肉食の洞窟がどこにあるんだっけかな？
And where was the Carnivore cave again?
スクショのあれじゃないかな？
Isn't it on that screenshot?
あの、何だっけ？座標のとこ？
Um, what was it? Where the coordinates are?
どこだっけ、待って座標座標、えーと
Where was it... wait, coordinates, coordinates, um...
あれ、私鉄の斧...あったあった
Huh, my metal axe... Ah, found it.
どこだっけ？あれ？
Where was it? Huh?
肉食の洞窟はねー、うーん、なんかどっか貼ってくれてたっけ？
The Carnivore cave is... hmm, did someone post it somewhere?
貼ってる
It's posted.
座標54の52
Coordinates 54, 52.
50...割と近いんだ
50... It's relatively close.
ごめん、なんか...
Sorry, something...
お疲れ様ですー
Good work everyone~
ごめん誰かが何かの、ワイバーンを殴っている。ごめん、自分か？
Sorry, someone or something is hitting a wyvern. Wait, is that me?
なば？
What?
誰かの犬が！誰かの犬が暴れてます！
Someone's dog! Someone's dog is going wild!
あ、トワ様ごめん
Ah, Towa-sama, sorry!
誰かの犬が攻撃してます、めちゃめちゃ！まずいまずい！
Someone's dog is attacking like crazy! Not good, not good!
無抵抗、無抵抗にしてほしい！
Passive, please set it to passive!
無抵抗？
Passive?
ごめんごめんごめん！
Sorry, sorry, sorry!
はい、オッケー！
Yes, okay!
先輩方どうでしたか？ビビ、今から参加させてもらいます。お疲れ様ですー
Seniors, how did it go? Vivi will be joining now. Good work everyone~
お疲れ様ー
Good work~
死ぬ、死ぬ、死ぬ！
I'm dying, dying, dying!
あ、ユウティラ持ってるの忘れてました。ユウティラ出すとこ
Ah, I forgot I had a Yuty on me. Place to take Yuty out...
今から洞窟に行こうっていう感じでーす
We're just about to head to a cave now~
え、ビビ行けんのかなー
Eh, can Vivi come along?
行ける行ける
You can, you can!
ちょっと待って、ワイバーンが...ワイバーンが攻撃されちゃってるわ
Wait a minute, the wyvern... The wyvern is getting attacked!
おーい、ワイバーンくーん！
Hey, Wyvern-kun!
もしもし。ワイバーン
Hello? Wyvern.
テリジノが
Therizino is...
だ、大丈夫かな？
I-Is it okay?
うん、オッケー
Yeah, okay.
あれ？なんかあんなとこに建物ありましたっけ？
Huh? Was there always a building over there?
あれ、しまえない、まあいっか
Huh, I can't put it away. Oh well.
お隣さんできた？もしかして
Did we get a neighbor? By any chance?
お隣さんいるよ
There is a neighbor.
え、お隣さんいんの？
Wait, we have neighbors?
いるよ、近くに。川下ったとこ目の前に
Yeah, nearby. Right in front, down the river.
本当だ！
It's true!
お隣さんいます
There's a neighbor.
いや、逆に何か分散されて助かるわ
Honestly, having things spread out helps.
ねえ
Yeah.
ティラノ、ティラノ結構来るからさ
Because Rexes come around quite a bit, haha.
デカいやつ来るからね。ありがたや。
Big ones come often. Much appreciated.
えーっと、原始的コンパニオンのキャンプ装備？何これ？
Umm, Primitive Companion Camp Equipment? What's this?
これは犬につけるっぽい？
Seems like this is equipped on dogs?
犬につけて...
Equip it on a dog...
アルマドッゴ。ほい。ほい。
Armadoggo. Here. There.
そう。なんか、コンパニオンモードにすると、ユニークな性能を引き出せる
Yeah. Apparently, if you switch to Companion Mode, it draws out unique abilities.
だって
It says.
元々ついてるこの犬に、なんだ？余りか。しまっとくか。
On this dog that was already here... what is it? An extra? Should I store it?
何になるんだろうね、コンパニオンって。ね。
Wonder what companions do. Yeah.
よいしょ
Alright.
とりあえず54、52だから一応近っちゃ近いよ。
Anyway, it's 54, 52, so it's relatively close.
あ、じゃあ、行くか。
Ah, then shall we go?
用意して行けばいいですか？
Should I get ready and head over?
今から？
Right now?
うん、今からこっちのあの...
Yeah, from now to our...
仮拠点の方？
The temporary base?
仮拠点の方だね、来てもらえたら。
Yeah, the temporary base, if you could come over.
仮拠点の方、はい、分かりました。
The temporary base, yes, got it.
靴下履いて。
Put on socks.
あれ、9時からのイベントどうでしたか？
By the way, how was the event from 9 o'clock?
なんと、トワが...
Surprisingly, Towa...
はい！
Yes!
勝ちましたねー！
won!
勝ちましたね！
She won!
I got to put my clothes on.
すごーい！
Amazing!
ナイスナイス！いいですね！
Nice, nice! That's great!
服どこに入れたっけ？覚えてない...
Where did I put my clothes? I don't remember...
私も役に立ちたいぞ
I want to be useful too!
何を？
With what?
あ、いやいや、あの、自分の服どこに入れたか覚えてない...
Ah, no no, um, I don't remember where I put my clothes...
服、えっと...
Clothes, um...
どうしたんだ？
What happened?
いや、多分、自分...
No, probably my...
あ、いつものあの、ゲーム会場じゃない？
Ah, wasn't it at that usual event venue?
ゲーム会場のCチームのチェスト？
The C-Team chest at the event venue?
イナ先輩のギリーは仮拠点のベッド...
Ina-senpai's ghillie suit is at the temporary base bed...
じゃあ、ギリー、ギリー、ギリーで行こっか！
Then ghillie, ghillie, let's go in ghillie!
服、無くても大丈夫だ。
Even without clothes, it's fine.
お腹減った
I'm hungry.
トワのね、ギリーが、てか服作ってないんだろうな。服作んないとあれか。
Towa's ghillie... well, she probably hasn't crafted clothes. If she doesn't craft clothes, then...
革の装備とか作っちゃったら？
How about just crafting leather gear?
うん。
Yeah.
ね。すっぽんぽん。
Right. Butt naked.
Ark, please.
よいしょ
Alright.
えっと仮拠点、あれどこやっけ？ま、迷子...
Um, the temporary base, where was it again? I-I'm lost...
水晶となんとかってところ。
The place called Crystal-something.
かな？テレポーターの。
I think? On the teleporter.
水青？水青ってとこですね。
Water Blue? Water Blue, that place, right.
あ、行きます！
Ah, I'll go!
向こうにずっと犬が追従してますよ、ちょっと。
The dog has been following you the whole time over there, wait.
移動...
Moving...
トワー！犬が邪魔で出れないよ！
Towa! The dog is in the way and I can't get out!
ちょっと待って。ワンちゃん！
Wait a second. Doggie!
ああ、いいよ。
Ah, it's fine.
ワンちゃんが裏行っちゃった。待って。
Doggie went around back. Wait.
え、ワンちゃん捕まえたんですか？
Eh, did you tame a doggie?
ワンちゃんね、参加賞でもらえたんだよね。
Yeah, we got the doggie as a participation prize.
そう。
Yeah.
お、なんだなんだなんだ... トワ、トワ、トワ！
Oh, what what what... Towa, Towa, Towa!
あーごめんごめんごめん！
Ah, sorry sorry sorry!
全員入っちゃったなんか！表、なんだこれ...
Everyone got crammed in! Front, what is this...
あ、ソーリーソーリー
Ah, sorry, sorry.
トワに...
To Towa...
そっちに、そっちに...
Over there, over there...
ちょっちょっちょ、ちょっと...
Wait wait wait, hold on...
離れて、離れて...
Move away, move away...
お天気悪いな、わるる。
The weather is bad, so bad.
よし。
Alright.
うわ。
Whoa.
Ark, please.
全員停止？
All stop?
これ犬もらったけど...
We got this dog, but...
あれだな。
You know...
よしよし、えーっと...
Okay okay, umm...
使いかた調べないとわかんないから。
I won't know how to use it unless I look it up.
そうだね。
Yeah.
大変だな、これ。
This is tough.
なんかすごいでっかいのいる！
There's a super huge one here!
おーい、ごっちょー！
Hey, thanks for the treat!
あ、すばる先輩だ。
Ah, it's Subaru-senpai.
はい。
Yes.
こんにちは！
Hello!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
すごーい、すごーい！
Amazing, amazing!
これ...
This...
え？祥平？
Eh? Shouhei?
出た。ゼッペリン？
There it is. Zeppelin?
気になる、気になる。
I'm curious, I'm curious.
ん？
Hm?
あのー
Um...
なんだ？
What's that?
これ？
This?
あれれ？
Huh?
出た？
Did it spawn?
なんだ、なんだ？
What is it, what is it?
あ、行ってもいいかな？
Ah, can I go?
おや？
Oh?
あ。
Ah.
あ、寒い
Ah, it's cold.
寒いか
Is it cold?
寒い、サムサム
It's cold, so chilly!
大丈夫です
I'm fine.
ああ、戻った
Ah, I'm back.
いやあ
Whew...
美味しそう、ゼッペリン
The Zeppelin sounds delicious.
おやつみたい
Sounds like a snack.
誰かご飯ください！
Someone please give me food!
ビビ12歳…ご飯ください！誰かいませんか？
Bibi, 12 years old... Please give me food! Isn't anyone there?
服着て
Put some clothes on.
ちょっと待ってね
Hold on a second.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much!
大丈夫かな？
Are you good?
いただきます
Thank you for the food!
おでこ？何これ？
Forehead? What's this?
あ、やば、踏まれた
Ah, shoot, I got stepped on.
何これー？！
What is this?!
恐竜じゃない？
Isn't it a dinosaur?
え、乗れる！何これー？！
Wait, you can ride it! What is this?!
文明進んでる！
Civilization is advancing!
え？
Huh?
え、すごーい！ねえ！
Woah, awesome! Look!
ねえ
Look.
ガソリン？
Gasoline?
ガソリンかー
Gasoline, huh...
大変な…なんなのかこれ？
Is this... something serious?
えー？！大変よろしくそうなものが
Eh?! There's something really nice here...
これ、えー？
This, huh?
え、しまえないってこと？
Wait, does that mean we can't put it away?
あ、そうなんよ
Ah, that's right.
笑った
That made me laugh!
ちょっと、ちょっと待ってね、ちょっと待ってよ
Wait, wait a second, hold on.
え、ガソリンは…私に来てくれる…？ちょっとお待ちくださいね
Uh, the gasoline... could you bring it to me...? Please wait a moment.
キタキタ！ガソリン！
Here it comes! Gasoline!
お待たせ
Sorry to keep you waiting.
イエーイ！空飛びたい！
Yay! I want to fly in the sky!
ハイオク満タンでおねがいします
Fill 'er up with premium, please!
レギュラーじゃなくてハイオク？
Premium instead of regular?
ハイオクがいいんだ？
Premium is better?
なんでハイオクなんだ？
Why premium?
あんまり関係ないけどね、ハイオクもレギュラーも
It doesn't really matter much though, whether it's premium or regular.
そうなんや
Is that so?
いや、車の車種によって違うってだけで
No, it just depends on the car model.
へえ、無免許やからわからんかった
Oh, I don't have a driver's license, so I had no idea.
無免許言うな
Don't say "no license"!
無免許
No license...
よかった、フリー支給で。ガソリン自費でやったら結構大変だった
Good thing it's provided for free. If we had to pay for gasoline ourselves, it would've been rough.
ですねー
Totally.
え、ビビこの間にちょっと装備揃え…何が必要ですか、ぼたん先輩？
Um, while they're doing that, Bibi should gear up... What do I need, Botan-senpai?
とりあえず服着て
Put some clothes on first.
はい。えー、ご飯持って、飛べる子で行くのがいいのかな？
Okay. Um, bring food, and maybe it's best to go with a flying dino?
はい
Yes.
飛べる子…ビビの、あれ、死んでないか？ビビの恐竜たちは。生きてるか？
A flying dino... Wait, aren't Bibi's dinosaurs dead? Are they alive?
ここに誰かが入れてるはずです
Someone should have put them in here.
賢い子だ、生きてた！
What smart creatures, they're alive!
イキロ？誰やこれ。あ！
"Ikiro"? Who is this? Ah!
ウサギさんだ
It's rabbit-san.
ビビの…あ、プテラ、プテラがいる、プテラが
Bibi's... Ah, Ptera! A Pteranodon is here!
あ、よかったー！ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank goodness! Thank you so much!
プテラ
Ptera.
ビビのプテラ、はい
Bibi's Ptera, here.
ありがとうございます！やったー！ボウガン入ってる！
Thank you so much! Yay! There's a crossbow in here!
ちょ、ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って、何、何、何？
W-Wait, wait a sec, what, what, what?
ガソリン、ガソリン来たよ、ガソリン
Gasoline, the gasoline is here, gasoline.
ガソリン満タン承知いたしましたー
Understood, full tank of gasoline coming right up!
ガソリン、今ここに投げますので、お使いください
I'll drop the gasoline right here, so please use it.
取っちゃった。こちらどうぞ
I picked it up by accident. Here you go.
入れるぞー
Putting it in!
はい、どうぞー
Yes, go ahead!
では、お楽しみを
Well then, enjoy!
ありがとうございます！おおー！
Thank you very much! Oohhh!
アキロゼ先輩、すげえ
Akirose-senpai, that's amazing!
いいな、ビビもほしい
That's so cool, Bibi wants one too.
ドラゴン
Dragon.
一応Discordに戻そう、えーっと
Let's switch back to Discord for now, um...
Discordに戻した
Switched back to Discord.
肉もうちょっと持つか
Should I grab a bit more meat?
インベントリじゃね？
In the inventory, right?
おおー！飛んだー！
Ooh! It flew!
おおー！飛んでる！浮いてる！
Ooh! It's flying! It's floating!
浮いてる
It's floating!
でかい！
It's huge!
かっこいいー！
So cool!
あれじゃない？あれと一緒じゃない？
Isn't it like that? Isn't it the same as that?
スペース押したら降りるとかじゃないの？
Wouldn't pressing Space make you descend or something?
おおー！すごい、かっこいい！
Woah! Incredible, so cool!
あ、いいね、いいね
Ah, nice, nice!
うわー！おおー！
Woah! Ooh!
飛びたい、飛びたい！
I want to fly, I want to fly!
めっちゃ揺れるやん
It sways like crazy!
運転うまい？運転
Are they good at steering it?
ビビも運転したいなあ
Bibi wants to steer it too!
いいねー
Nice!
墜落させちゃうよん
I'll make it crash!
それトワの賞品だから！
That's Towa's prize, you know!
お前たち勝手に…本人をさ
You guys are just taking... the owner herself...
差し置いて乗ってるから
...is being left behind while you're riding it!
え、乗っていいですか？トワ様差し置いて
Eh, can I ride it? Leaving Towa-sama behind?
乗っちゃおう
Let's ride this.
どうぞどうぞ
Go ahead, go ahead.
いいんかい
You sure you're okay with that?
まあ懐広いからね
Well, I'm very open-minded.
自分で言うかい
Saying that about yourself?
ねー
Right?
そこは広いからね
That part of me is broad.
自分で言わんのよ、そういうのは
You shouldn't say that about yourself!
とりあえず行きますか？
Anyway, shall we head out?
そうだね
Sounds good.
はーい
Okaaay.
行きますか。まあ、それには乗っていかないよね？
Shall we? Well, we won't be riding that, right?
それには乗っていかないかな
I guess we won't be riding that.
なんかプテラとか...空中でいける恐竜一匹持ってって...
Bring like a Ptera... one flying dino...
アルゲンとかプテラとか
like an Argent or a Ptera.
あとはその、地上で戦えるやつ一匹持ってって、って感じかな
And then bring one that can fight on the ground, I think.
冷蔵庫の中にね、メガテリウムが一応いるから
There's a Megatherium in the cryofridge,
洞窟内でちょっと戦えるか分かんないけども、それオススメかな
so not sure if it can fight inside caves, but I recommend it.
メガテリウム...
Megatherium...
あ、こいつか
Ah, this one?
よいしょ。ビビちゃん
All right. Bibi-chan,
拠点襲われて、本真屋では死にました
our base got raided, so it died in Honmaya.
本真屋ではいなくなりました
It was lost in Honmaya.
え？本真屋でいなくなったの？
Huh? It got lost in Honmaya?
うん
Yeah.
えええー！
Eeeeh?!
本真屋でしまってなかったから
Because we didn't store it away in Honmaya.
ああー、なんでやねん！
Aaargh, why?!
なんでやねん、本真屋で...
Why at Honmaya, of all places...
だからビビはいったんそのミイラと、冷蔵庫の中に...
So Bibi, for now, take that mummy, and in this fridge...
はい
Yes.
メガテリウムっていうのがいるから、それ一匹持って行ったらいいかな
there's a Megatherium, so you should bring one.
で、イナはユティラでもいいかもね
And Ina, you could go with Yutyrannus.
ユティラ...私がユティラ？
Yuty... I'll take Yuty?
ユティ...
Yuty...
そうそうそう、これイナのユティだから、イナはユティに乗って戦う感じかな
Yeah, this is Ina's Yuty, so you can ride it and fight.
ああー、ユティラ、どこに書いてあるんだ？
Ah, Yutyrannus... Where is it written?
ビビはメガテリウムな
Bibi gets Megatherium.
あ、ビビはメガテリウム？
Ah, Bibi gets Megatherium?
メガテリウムな。そうそうそう
Megatherium, yeah. Exactly.
メガ...これだ
Mega... Here it is.
これで焚き火...あ、でもご飯、つけ...
With this, the campfire... Ah, but food...
よいしょ
All right.
お、何？
Oh, what's this?
お肉が...火をつけて...
Meat... Light the fire...
お肉28個あったら足りますか？
Will 28 pieces of meat be enough?
どうかなー、もうちょっとあったらいいかも
I wonder... Might be better to have a bit more.
もうちょっと、はい
A bit more, okay.
水筒どっかにやっちゃったー
I lost my canteen somewhere~
よいしょ
All right.
なんでプテラなんか捕まったー！
Why did my Pteranodon get caught?!
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
すいません、さっき流されてましたｗ
Sorry, it got swept away earlier lol.
あ、びっくりした、びっくりした！
Ah, that scared me!
なんか急に...
Suddenly out of nowhere...
いなくなっちゃって、自分のプテラ。「どこ行ったん？」で作りましたー
My Pteranodon disappeared. Wondered where it went, so I crafted this!
繊維と皮...
Fiber and hide...
やばい、これ63...
Oh no, this is 63...
イナ準備大丈夫なら行っちゃいますか？
Ina, if you're ready, shall we go?
はい。ちょっと、お水だけ...
Yes. Just give me a second for water...
でも水、しまえないんだけど
Wait, I can't store water.
もう置いてったら？
Why not just leave it?
もう...まあいいか、もう
Yeah... Whatever, it's fine.
はーい
Okay~
アルゲン乗らせてもらおう、ちょっと
Let me ride the Argentavis for a bit.
プテラの...なくなっちゃったんですよね？多分
The Pteranodon... It's gone, right? Probably.
回収してないから1時間経っちゃいましたよね
Since nobody retrieved it, an hour has passed, right?
多分...諦めるか
Probably... Guess I'll give up on it.
あ、じゃあイナちゃん、モンボに入れられるかな？
Ah, Ina-chan, can you put it in a Cryopod?
ボールに。ユティラ
Into the ball. The Yuty.
あ、えっと...
Ah, umm...
はいはい。ある？うん
Okay, okay. Got one? Yeah.
よいしょ
All right.
それは持っていこう
Let's bring that.
洞窟じゃちょっとデカすぎる可能性もあるが、まあ行こう
It might be too big for a cave, but let's go.
えっ、座標が...
Umm, the coordinates are...
54、52
54, 52.
54の52
54の52...覚えたんだ
54, 52... Got it memorized.
誰かについて行く！そんな遠くないよ
I'll just follow someone! It's not that far.
54の52...みんなについて行きます
54, 52... I'll follow everyone.
見れないから
Since I can't look at the map.
飛べ！はい
Fly! Okay.
54の52。よいしょ
54, 52. All right.
文字が出るんだ、こうやって
The text shows up like this.
ほんなら、こっちや！みんな行くぞー！
Alright, this way! Let's go, everyone!
はーい！ついて行きます
Okaaay! Following you!
ビビ...ちょっと待って、遅っ！みんな早っ、えっ？
Bibi... Wait, so slow! Everyone's so fast, huh?
アイテムかな？
Is it items?
重量かな？重量が重くて...重量オーバーの可能性ありますね、確かに
Weight, maybe? It's heavy... Could definitely be overweight.
ね、このへんちゃライドも言うて
Yeah, even so...
お前重いもの持ってきたな！皮持ってきちゃったバカタレ！
You brought heavy stuff! You brought hides with you, you dummy!
同じく持ってきちゃった、バカタレって感じ。バカタレ
Same here, brought them too... Total idiot. Idiot.
54.9、52.9
54.9, 52.9.
52...
じゃ止まるなら上から入ろう
If we're stopping, let's enter from above.
みんなが行ったあと合流するから、先中入っててもいいし、降りなければ
I'll meet up after everyone goes, so you can go in first as long as you don't dismount.
よいしょ
All right.
あれ、ビビこれ牡丹先輩について行ってます？大丈夫？
Wait, Bibi, are you following Botan-senpai? Everything good?
うん、大丈夫だよ
Yeah, I'm good.
オッケーオッケー、大丈夫。待って、洞窟内って飛行禁止じゃなかったっけ？
Okay okay, good. Wait, wasn't flying banned in caves?
この辺じゃねえの？この辺の下とかじゃねえの？多分
Isn't it around here? Under around here, maybe?
ああ、言うて入れてる...助けどね。バカバカ
Ah, we can enter... Idiot, idiot.
あれってなんかミッションじゃなかったんですか？このクレートってアイテムとるの
Wasn't that a mission? Getting items from this crate.
あ、それミッションだね。取っていいよ
Ah, that is a mission. Go ahead and take it.
あ！間違えた、間違えた、間違えた。
Ah! Wrong button, wrong button, wrong button.
クレートー...
The crate...
F な、F。
Press F, F.
クレートって個人ミッションでしたっけ？
Are supply crates individual missions?
あ、個人ミッション。
Ah, individual missions.
あ、じゃあ他の奴取った方がいいや。
Ah, then someone else should take it.
まだ進んでないや、でござる。
I haven't made progress on it yet, de gozaru.
こっちも進んでなーい。
Mine hasn't progressed either.
クレート取ったらいいやで。
You can go ahead and grab it.
取れました。
Got it.
お、なんだこれ？
Oh, what's this? All...
時間が足りないゲームだ、これ。
There's never enough time in this game.
全部取っていいのか？
Can I take all of it?
ここじゃねえかな？で、違うか。違うわ。
Is it around here? No, guess not. Nope.
なんか川に多分あると思うんだよな。
I feel like it's probably by the river.
入り口があるんだよな、多分な。
There should be an entrance somewhere around here, probably.
そうそうそうそう。
Right, right, right, right.
洞窟の穴があると思うけど。
I think there's a cave opening.
フブキさんだ。
It's Fubuki-san.
そう、ちょっとボタン先輩見失いました、ビビ。
Yeah, I kind of lost sight of Botan-senpai, Bibi.
あ、今はね、洞窟の穴探してほしい。
Ah, right now I want you to look for the cave opening.
洞窟の穴、了解。
The cave opening, roger that.
下に入り口とかかな？滝っぽいよね。
Maybe the entrance is down below? It looks like a waterfall.
滝壺の中飛び込んでいったら洞窟説を唱え、飛び込む。
Proposing the theory that diving into the waterfall basin leads to a cave, I dive!
はいはいはい。まあ、あるよね。
Right, right. Well, that's a classic.
な...何もない。
N-Nothing's here.
なかったね。
Nothing there, huh?
ないね。
Nope, nothing.
はずれた。
Guessed wrong.
ここらへん？ここらへんかな？
Around here? Maybe around here?
らしい。この辺りらしい。
Apparently. Apparently it's around here.
この辺りか？
Around here?
うわ、今雨降ってる。パイロ捕獲できそう。
Whoa, it's raining right now. We might be able to tame a Pyromane.
雨、雨。えー、どこだ？
Rain, rain. Uhh, where is it?
ほー、どこだー？この辺？
Hmm, where is it? Around here?
59...
いやー！うさぎさん来た！
Eek! A rabbit came!
54.9、52.9。
54.9, 52.9.
んー？んー、どこだ？
Hmm? Where is it?
ん？ここか？違うか。
Hm? Here? No?
52.9？
52.9?
ほう。
I see.
52...
52、55.9、52.9...
52, 55.9, 52.9...
52.9とは書いてるけどね、画像貼って書いてくれてるやつ。
52.9 is what it says on the screenshot they posted, though.
もうちょっと横じゃ...
Isn't it a bit more to the side...
どこだ？この辺だな。この黄色い光が...
Where is it? Around here. This yellow light...
黄色いクレートかな？黄色クレート...
Is that a yellow supply crate? A yellow crate...
黄色クレートに向かおう、じゃあ。
Let's head toward the yellow crate then.
この、この辺？この辺のどこか？
This... around here? Somewhere around here?
ボタン先輩発見。
Found Botan-senpai.
これが入り口じゃないもんな。この辺の下らへんなのか？
This isn't the entrance. Is it around the bottom of this area?
上下はでも分かんないんだよね。
We don't know the elevation, though.
確かにね。
That's true.
ふーむ。だから下の方かなって思ったんだけど。
Hmm. That's why I thought it might be down below.
ねえ、下にありそうですよね。
Right, it seems likely to be at the bottom.
え、これ滝の裏とかにねえか、ワンチャン。滝入れるとかない？
Wait, maybe behind the waterfall, possibly? Can we go inside the waterfall?
滝突っ込んだんですけど、見つけらんなくて。
I rammed into the waterfall, but couldn't find anything.
城を目印にだって。城を目印に、下の沼地の壁って書いてあんな。
It says "Use the castle as a landmark. The wall by the swamp down below."
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
城？
A castle?
Castle?
城なんかあります？
Is there a castle or something?
城？この辺に城？
A castle? A castle around here?
え、どこだ？お城？
Eh, where? A castle?
ちょっと高ーく飛ぶか。
Let me fly a bit higher.
城っていうか、あっち側に緑色の光ってるやつありますけど、あれですかね？あれが城？
Rather than a castle, there's a glowing green thing over there. Could it be that? Is that the castle?
いや、あれじゃないだろう。
No, that's probably not it.
これじゃないですよね、多分。
It's probably not this, right?
え、この世界って建物あるんですか？城みたいな、そんな。
Wait, are there buildings in this world? Like a castle, something like that?
あ、これ城？あ、違う。これ誰かのアルゲンのあれか、罠か。トラップ？
Ah, is this the castle? Ah, no. Is this someone's Argent trap? A trap?
あー、それ昨日捕まえたやつかも。
Ah, that might be where they caught one yesterday.
あ、捕まえたやつか。
Ah, where they caught one.
え、城ってどこだ？
Eh, where is the castle?
あ、ここにまた黄色いクレート落ちてきたよ。誰か取ったらいいんじゃない？
Ah, another yellow crate dropped here. Shouldn't someone take it?
黄色い、あ、取る！クレートミッションで取っちゃいな。
Yellow... ah, I'll take it! Grab it for the crate mission.
左上...
Top left...
あ、こんにちはー。
Ah, hello.
あ、トワタロウ。まつり先輩いたわ。
Ah, Towatarou. Matsuri-senpai is here.
あら。
Oh my.
じゃあ...
Then...
僕の画像載せた。ん？
I posted my picture. Hm?
ここらへんじゃないくなくない？
Isn't it like, not around here?
ん？
Hm?
え、マジでどこ？え、違う？これ洞窟じゃないんだよね。
Wait, where seriously is it? Wait, no? This isn't a cave, right?
これは滝裏なんだよな。
This is behind the waterfall, right.
そうなんだよな。え、そもそも違う？もしかして。そんな？
It is. Wait, is it completely wrong in the first place? Could it be? Really?
そもそも左上って調べたら書いてあるけど、どうなんだろう？
When I looked it up, it said top-left, but I wonder...
うーん？
Hmm?
待って、僕たち...
Wait, for us...
座標が、待って、座標が？緯度が？
The coordinates, wait, the coordinates? The latitude?
僕たちは行きたい場所はですね、肉食の洞窟ですね。
The place we want to go is the Carnivore Cave.
肉食の洞窟。
The Carnivore Cave.
この多分、貼ってくれてる画像の、その...
Probably in the screenshot that was posted...
みんなに渡されてる画像の座標が違くない？
Aren't the coordinates on the image shared with everyone wrong?
そもそも間違ってる、これ？
Is it wrong to begin with?
あ、違ってる？
Ah, it's wrong?
なんかあのサイトで調べたら、全然違うとこになった。
When I checked on that site, it showed a completely different place.
え、マジで？
Wait, seriously?
肉食の洞窟はマップ上だよって言われてる。
They're saying the Carnivore Cave is at the top of the map.
左上なんだよね。
It's in the top left, yeah.
じゃあこの資料が違うってことか。
So that means this reference sheet is wrong?
ちょっとそのネットに基づいて行ってみますか。
Shall we try going based on the internet?
じゃネットに基づいて行こう。
Let's go based on the internet then.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
ネットに基づくと、えっと...まずは...
Based on the internet, um... first...
ワープかな？
A warp?
うん、ワープか。オッケー。
Yeah, a warp? Okay.
一回ワープしましょう。
Let's warp once.
そうだね、一旦拠点に戻ろう。
Yeah, let's head back to base for now.
なんか攻撃されてる！生きろがめっちゃ攻撃されてる！
Something's being attacked! Ikiro is taking a ton of hits!
えー、生きれないじゃん！
Eh, he can't survive then!
死なないで！
Don't die!
死ぬな！
危ない、危ない。
Watch out, watch out.
お、アルゲント...
Oh, an Argent...
危ない、危ない。
Watch out, watch out.
ふざけやがって。
How dare you...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫でした。
I was fine.
よかった。
Good.
いいよ。ほんならじゃあテレポーター行きやしょう。
All right. Then let's head to the teleporter.
ほーい。
Okay~
よいしょ、よいしょ。ほい。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Up we go.
テラバ！テラバで行っちゃおう。
Teleba! Let's go using Teleba.
あ、いてててて。みんなでやるとヤバイな。
Ah, ow ow ow ow. It's crazy when we all do it together.
任せる。アルゲン任せる。
Leaving it to you. Leaving the Argent to you.
はい。
Okay.
ヴィーラ狭い...
Viira is tight...
あっち行け。
Go away.
ナイス。
Nice.
あっち行け。あっち行け。
Go away. Go away.
ちょっと届いてない？ちょっと届いてない。
Is it not quite reaching? It's not reaching.
足短いんで。
Its legs are short.
一回飛んじゃってから入るぜ。
I'll fly up once before going in.
うん。
Yeah.
よいしょ。
There we go.
あ、ごめんね、ごめんね。降りられない。降りられなかった。
Ah, sorry, sorry. I can't dismount. I couldn't get off.
えーっと、降りてるけど...
Umm, I'm off, but...
ナイスー。
Nice~
乗っかってる？テレポート。
Are you on? The teleport.
はーい。また誰か飛んできた？
Okay~ Did someone fly over again?
どうぞ。
Go ahead.
なんか左上だから、えっと、ここ、これかな？
Since it's on the top left, um, here, maybe this one?
ジャングルだね。
It's the jungle.
あ、取り残された！
Ah, I got left behind!
あ、肉食洞窟ってあるやん。テレポート先に。
Ah, there's Carnivore Cave as a teleport destination.
あ、本当だ！ワンチャン...
Ah, it's true! Maybe...
あれ、どこに行きましたか？ビビだけひとり取り残された。
Huh, where did everyone go? Only Bibi was left behind all alone.
あ、何かね、肉食の洞窟って名前が付いてるみたいですよ、テレポーターに。
Ah, looks like it's named 'Carnivore Cave' on the teleporter.
肉食の洞窟？
Carnivore Cave?
うん。
Yeah.
ちょっと探してみるわ。
I'll look for it.
お願いします。
Please do.
非常に雨降っていて視界が悪いです。
It's raining heavily, so visibility is very poor.
視界悪いね。ビテラもね。
Visibility is bad. Bitera too.
え、ビテラだけどこ...？
Eh, where did Bitera go...?
ビテラだけ行ってしまったね。ビビがテレポーターから出ちゃってたんだったかな？
Only Bitera went ahead. Did Bibi step off the teleporter?
あちゃー。来た。えっと...
Oh dear. Arrived. Umm...
ここ、あるかな？あ、どけ。来た。
Is it here? Ah, move. Arrived.
で、ビテラどこだ？
And where is Bitera?
えっ、ビビいないよ？
Eh, Bibi isn't here?
あれ、ビビおる？これどこだ？
Huh, Bibi is here? Where is this?
ビビ？
Bibi?
ビテラはもうこっち来てるよ。
Bitera is already over here.
肉食の洞窟にテレポートしました。
I teleported to Carnivore Cave.
いや多分違うとこにいる。いや、ここジャングルだ。
No, probably somewhere else. Wait, this is the jungle.
え、ここジャングル？ここジャングルだ！違うわ、ここじゃない。
Eh, this is jungle? This is jungle! No, not here.
そもそもここじゃないかも。
This might not even be the place.
あ、そこじゃない？
Ah, not there?
うん。ビビそこ居ていいよ。
Yeah. Bibi, you can stay there.
あ、良かった。
Ah, thank goodness.
あ、そっちか。ちょっと待って、オッケー。
Ah, over there? Wait a sec, okay.
いいよ。みんな隣いるわ、確かに。ビビの。オッケー。
All right. Everyone is right next to Bibi indeed. Okay.
こちらよー。よいしょ。
Over here~ Up we go.
そっち行きまーす。
Heading over there~
はい。一旦テレポしちゃってもいいかな、これ？
Okay. Is it okay if I just teleport now?
テレポしちゃっていいよ。
Yeah, go ahead and teleport.
えーっと、肉食の洞窟？
Umm, Carnivore Cave?
うん。はい。
Yeah. Yes.
おいしょ。こっちか。あ、来た来た来た。ありがとうございます。
Heave-ho. This way? Ah, here they come! Thank you very much.
お、ちょちょちょちょ。うい。オッケー。一旦またテレポーターから浮いて。
Whoa, whoa whoa whoa. Whew. Okay, float up off the teleporter again.
いいよ。ビテラー。ビテラ埋まってない？それ。
Okay. Bitera~ Isn't Bitera stuck inside that?
目の前。あ、目の前いた。
Right in front. Ah, right in front.
目の前や。目の前だね。あ、これか。
It's right in front. Right in front, yeah. Ah, is it this?
で、ここで手に入れるのがアーティファクトだよね？
And what we get here is the artifact, right?
そうだね、そうだね。ワンチャンこのままみんな飛んで行けないかな、奥まで。
Yeah, that's right. Wonder if we can all just fly all the way inside?
飛んで行けそうだけどね。一回行ってみる？
Looks like we could fly in, though. Want to try once?
どう、来た？
How is it, did you make it?
あ、るるるるる、はいはい。こっちこっち、ここだよもう。
Ah, rurururu, yes yes. Over here, right here already.
よいしょ。あ、そこか。ありがと、ありがと。
Heave-ho. Ah, there? Thanks, thanks.
もう目の前。で、これでもう奥まで行ったらあるかな？
Right in front. And will it be there if we go all the way in?
行きましょうか。
Shall we go?
うん。行きます。
Yeah. Let's go.
洞窟？洞窟... 洞窟ですね。
A cave? A cave... It is a cave.
うわー、面白い！青、めっちゃ青いな。
Whoa, interesting! Blue, it's super blue.
ね。で、狡猾のアーティファクトっていうやつを取る。
Yeah. And we get the Artifact of the Clever.
そうそうそう、一番奥まで行けたら多分あるはず。
Right right right, if we go all the way to the deepest part it should be there.
はい。あ、でもまあ結構ずっと飛んで行けそうな感じはしてますけどね。
Yes. Ah, but it feels like we can pretty much fly all the way.
ね。うおー、でも広い。え？
Yeah. Whoa, but it's huge. Huh?
これ右と左どっち行ってる？
Which way are you going, right or left?
あ、左行ってみた、今。
Ah, I just tried going left.
3人右行ってるよね？
Three people are going right, right?
右行き止まりだったな。
Right was a dead end.
自分左行ける。あ、左結構広いよ。左結構広い。
I can go left. Ah, left is pretty wide. Left is pretty wide.
広い？嘘、見えなかっただけ？
Wide? Really, could I just not see it?
トワ様についていってる。オッケーオッケー、一旦このまま真っ直ぐ行ってみてる。
Following Towa-sama. Okay okay, trying to head straight for now.
じゃあ、こっち左行ってみようかな。
Then maybe I'll try going left here.
ビビも左行ってます。
Bibi is going left too.
これみんなで手分けした方がいい？もうみんなで手分けしたっていい。
Should we split up for this? We can totally split up.
えー、ビビ一人で怖いな。
Eh, Bibi is scared alone.
あれ？これ、もしかして... 別のとこ出ちゃった？
Huh? Did I maybe... end up somewhere else?
なんか違いそうですよね、こっち側。このフブキ先輩もいるところ。
Feels like it's the wrong way over here, where Fubuki-senpai is too.
これさ、別のチームもいるかも。え？
Wait, another team might be here too. Eh?
あれ？その相手どうするんだっけ？
Huh? What do we do if we run into them?
いや、分かんないけど...
Well, I don't know, but...
え、ここ洞窟か？
Wait, is this a cave?
ここ洞窟じゃないか？
Isn't this a cave?
洞窟なのか？
Is it a cave?
なんか絶妙だよね、この判定名的には。
It's kind of vague in terms of the zone detection.
違うよ。なんだここ、どこ行けばいいんだ？
No. What is this place? Where should I go?
待ってていいやつなの？
Are we supposed to wait here?
迷子の迷子の こねこちゃん
Lost, lost, little lost kitten...
迷子だね。一歩こっち行ってみるけど
We're lost. I'll try heading this way though.
分かりづらいじゃん...
It's so hard to tell...
ガスが舞ってるのかな？ガスガスのガス。
Is gas floating around? Gassy gas.
でもめっちゃ紫になってるはず。
But it's supposed to be bright purple.
めっちゃ分かりやすいと思う、めっちゃ宝物みたいな感じの。
It should be really easy to spot, like a treasure.
確かに、発光してるから。
True, since it's glowing.
これダンジョンなの？そもそもこれってダンジョン？
Is this a dungeon? To begin with, is this a dungeon?
あ、でもなんかピンクの苔見えた。
Ah, but I saw some pink moss.
ピンクのやつ...ダンジョンじゃないならいいんじゃないかって思ったけど。
The pink stuff... If it's not a dungeon, I thought that'd be fine though.
青...あ、キノコか。
Blue... Ah, mushrooms?
あ、青キノコだ！青キノコ来たよ。
Ah, blue mushrooms! Here are blue mushrooms.
なにこれ？
What's this?
このピンクのやつ有機ポリマーだ。ちょっと待って。
This pink stuff is Organic Polymer. Wait a sec.
あ、そうだ！取っていいですか？
Ah, that's right! Can I harvest it?
送ってくれてたやつだ。
It's the stuff you sent earlier.
あ、そうそうそう。
Ah, yeah yeah yeah.
あ、取れない。取れません、なにこれ。
Ah, I can't harvest it. Can't get it, what is this?
見つけたかも！
I think I found it!
あ、ナイスー！
Ah, nice!
これあれだ、上行ったら出口だ。
This is it, if you go up it's the exit.
これかな？
Is this it?
なんか2個あるはずだけど。
There should be two of them though.
これじゃないですか？
Isn't it this?
あ、あった！これ免疫のアーティファクトってやつだでも。
Ah, there it is! But this is the Artifact of the Immune.
あ、じゃあ狡猾じゃないわ。狡猾もあるはず。
Ah, then it's not the Clever. There should be Clever too.
でも持ってっていいよ。
But you can take that one with you.
うん、持って帰る、持って帰る。
Yeah, I'll take it back, take it back.
じゃあこっちにしよう。
Let's head this way then.
迷子、迷子、迷子... これ上行くと外に出れそう。
Lost, lost, lost... If you go up here, you can get outside.
そうだね。あ、ログ出た、よかった。
Yeah. Ah, the log popped up, great.
免疫のアーティファクトの出口だったんだ。
So it was the exit for the Artifact of the Immune.
そうだね、この今フブキ先輩と風真がいたとこ。
Yeah, where Fubuki-senpai and Kazama were just now.
ああ、ってことか。
Ah, so that's what it was.
多分そういうことなんだと。
That's probably what it is.
こっち行ってみるかな、ここ探そう。
Maybe I'll try going this way. Let's search here.
色々迷路です。迷路だ。
It's totally a maze. It's a maze.
とんでもないことになってますわ。
It's turned into quite a situation.
やべ、迷子。
Oh crap, I'm lost.
もう迷子ですわ。
Completely lost now.
クソ迷子。オーマイガー。
Super lost. Oh my god.
もうみんなと離れている。
I'm already separated from everyone.
いや、でかい。広い。
Man, it's huge. Vast.
でかいし広い、やばい。
It's huge and vast, crazy.
でかい、広い、やばい。
Huge, vast, crazy.
でもなんか他の人見えないから、被ってないんじゃないか？
But since I can't see anyone else, maybe we're not overlapping?
ね。
Right.
いないかも。さっきなんかテリジノみたいの落ちてたんだよな。
Maybe not. Earlier I saw something like a Therizino fallen down.
すごい。ありえん黄色いとこは見つけたけど、これはなんだ？
Incredible. I found an impossibly yellow place, but what is this?
なにこれ？
What's this?
わからんまげ。
Beats me.
えっと... スタミナ回復。
Um... Stamina recovery.
左、左。
Left, left.
迷い...
Lost...
お？あ、重い、重い。オベリスク...
Oh? Ah, it's heavy, heavy. Obelisk...
なんだここ？
What is this place?
付いていく。イナ先輩いくよー。
Following you. Ina-senpai, let's go~
はーい。あ、これポリマーか。
Okay. Ah, is this Polymer?
こっちか。確かに。
This way? Indeed.
あ、なんか出てきた。
Ah, came out somewhere.
ごめん、トワねえ、ちょっとガンガン行っちゃってるわ。二人ごめんね。
Sorry, Towa-nee, I'm kind of charging ahead. Sorry, you two.
大丈夫です。
I'm totally fine.
オッケー。見えなくなったら言って。
Okay. Tell me if you lose sight of me.
はーい。
Okay.
お城のところに出てきちゃった。
I ended up coming out by the castle.
いや、自分はまだ下いろんな道探してるんですけど...
Well, I'm still searching various paths below though...
上にちょいちょい出れるところがあって...
There are spots here and there where you can pop out on top...
そうだよね。出れるとこあるよね。
Right. There are places where you can exit.
プテラのね、スタミナ気をつけてね。
Watch your Ptera's stamina, okay?
はーい。
Okay.
一旦ここで休んで。スタミナなくなる。
Rest here for a moment. Running out of stamina.
大変だ。これクリスタルか。違うの。
That's tough. Is this crystal? No.
本当にね、ピンク色でボワボワボワーってオーラ入ってるアイテムがあるはず。
There should really be an item with a billowing pink aura.
そう、誰かはいるんだけど、ここが果たして洞窟扱いなのかが分かんない。
Yeah, someone is here, but I don't know if this even counts as a cave.
多分洞窟扱いだと思う。
I think it counts as a cave.
じゃあ待たないといけないってこと。でも何やってるか分かんないんだよね、結局。
So that means we have to wait. But we don't know what they're doing after all.
いても。
Even if they're there.
探してるのかな？あ、あそこがポータルか。あ、違うか。ポータルじゃない。
Wonder if they're searching? Ah, is that the portal? Ah, no, it's not a portal.
誰かの家か、ここ。
Is this someone's house?
あ、なんかチームの家だ、ここ。
Ah, it's a team base here.
おー、へえ。
Oh, huh.
あれ、なんか狡猾が必要なんだよね？
Wait, we need the Clever, right?
そうそう、狡猾。
Yeah, Clever.
で、さっき免疫は見つけた。
And earlier I found the Immune.
オッケー。免疫？うん。
Okay. Immune? / Yeah.
なんかそれってさ、水色のところら辺に免疫あった？
Was the Immune near the light-blue area?
水色の奥だね。
Past the light-blue area, yeah.
じゃあ紫系のとこ進めば一本だけど、もう中入っちゃったから、ちょっとわかんないんだけど。
Then if you follow the purple area it's a single path, but since I already went inside, I'm not really sure.
ちょっと紫っぽいとこ進んでみるか。水色が狡猾じゃなくて免疫だから...
Maybe I'll try following the purple-ish area. Since light blue was Immune and not Clever...
水色が免疫？
Light blue is Immune?
そう、なんかアーティファクトっていう...
Yeah, like the artifact...
はい。
Right.
なんかアクセサリー、何ていうの、オブジェクト？
...kind of accessory, or what do you call it, object?
そうだね、オブジェクトがあるんだよね。あ、グリフォンだ。
Right, there are objects. Ah, a Griffin.
はーい。
Okay.
なんか今、こんこよとか、はじめちゃんとかもいたけど、見つけてないって言ってました。
Konkoyo and Hajime-chan were here earlier too, but they said they hadn't found it.
なるほど。
I see.
まだじゃあ誰か入っちゃってて、リポップ待ちとかなのかな？
So someone went in earlier, and maybe we're waiting for it to respawn?
もしかすると。トロフィー、トロフィー。
Perhaps. Trophy, trophy.
あとはね、こんな感じっすね。ごめんなさい、ごめんなさい。
The rest is like this. Sorry, sorry!
何々？怖い、怖い。
What is it? Scary, scary.
キモキモ虫がいるから気をつけて。ね。
Watch out for the gross bugs. / Yeah.
見たことない生き物いっぱいいる、ここ。
There are tons of creatures here I've never seen before.
そうなの。
Yeah.
ここね、結構強いんだよね。なんかレベリングする...
The enemies here are pretty strong. People come to level up...
洞窟側、結構いい...
The cave side is pretty good...
レベリングに最適な洞窟かな？
Is this cave optimal for leveling?
そう、敵が強い。
Yeah, the enemies are strong.
出れる？だけど。
Can we get out though?
うわ、クモいた！スパイダー。
Whoa, there was a spider! Spider.
ええと...
Umm...
え、こっちじゃない？
Wait, isn't it this way?
完全に...あ、あっち側か。
Completely... Ah, it's on that side?
スパイダーいるやん、スパイダー。
Look, there's a spider! Spider.
下なのか上のほうなのか、どっちなんだろう？
Is it down below or up above? Which one is it?
にゃー、湧いてないのか、なんなのか。
Unyaa... are they not spawning, or what?
どっちだ？
Which way?
もうちょっとこっち...
A little more this way...
イナ先輩いますか？
Ina-senpai, are you there?
これ多分戻ってきてるんだよな、これ。
This is probably looping back...
えー、迷子になったかも...
Ehh, I might have gotten lost...
オッケー。他のチーム見つかった？
Okay. Did you find the other team?
あ、誰かいる。
Ah, someone's here.
他のチームいた？
Was the other team there?
迷子、迷子～
Lost, lost~
ほな、オッケーです。
Then, that's okay.
むむむむ...
Mmm-mmm-mmm...
あ、ビビやばい、スタミナ...
Ah, Bibi, watch out, your stamina...
ないんだったらリポップ待ちの...
If there are none, we wait for respawn...
黄緑色のキノコが近くにあれば、その近くにあるらしい。
If there are yellowish-green mushrooms nearby, apparently it's near there.
なんだここ。なんか私、変なとこ抜けた、これもしや。
What is this place? Did I pass through somewhere weird?
黄緑色のキノコ...これ？
Yellowish-green mushrooms... this?
一応黄緑はあるけどのう...
There is yellow-green, but...
お、俺、俺大丈夫これ？
Am I... am I okay here?
ちょ、次元の狭間、次元の狭間...
Wait, gap between dimensions, gap between dimensions...
次元の狭間？
Gap between dimensions?
とりあえずちょっと出口探すか。
For now, let's look for an exit.
はい。一旦ね。
Yes. For now.
天井吹き抜けてたら分かりやすいかも。
If the ceiling has an opening, it might be easy to tell.
天井吹き抜けで結構出れそうなとこはありましたね。
There were places with open ceilings where it seemed we could get out.
あれ？テレポ...
Huh? The teleport...
テレポはこのへんなんだけどな。
The teleport is around here, though.
これじゃない？天井吹き抜けで出れ...
Isn't this it? Getting out through the open ceiling...
うわ、ほんまや、なんかある！何、黄緑ありますよ、キノコ！
Whoa, really, there's something! There are yellow-green mushrooms!
ね？ / これなに？
Right? / What's this?
BGM さ、なんかいる。
The BGM... there's something here.
なんかいる、なんかいる、やだ。
There's something, there's something, no thanks.
あれ？これは入れるのだろうか。
Huh? Can I enter this?
一旦上に出てこれたら...
If I can get out to the top...
上に出たらなんか異空間だった。
When I went up, it was some kind of alternate dimension.
いや、抜け道っぽいけど...
Well, it looks like a shortcut, but...
異空間に出た？え？
Came out into an alternate dimension? Huh?
出れないや、これ。
I can't get out of here.
上抜け出れないねー。
Can't escape through the top, huh.
頑張って出口を探すんだ！
Do your best to find the exit!
身体がでかいからと思ったけど...
I thought it was because my body was too big, but...
ちょ待って、下に降りたいんだけど...
Wait a sec, I want to go down...
なによ。痛っ、痛っ、痛っ！助けて！
What the... Ouch, ouch, ouch! Help!
あ、誰かが下にいる。
Ah, someone's down below.
虫たかってる！虫たかってるって、ヒツレ。
Bugs are swarming! I'm swarmed by bugs!
え、ここどこ？
Eh, where is this?
うわーい、虫ビビ！ここどこ？
Yay, bug Bibi! Where is this?
いやちょっと、なんかマップから出てるっぽい...
Wait, it looks like I've fallen outside the map...
あ、トワ様とはぐれた。トワ様ー！どこだ？
Ah, I lost Towa-sama. Towa-sama! Where are you?
裏っぽいとこ来ちゃった。ちょっと待ってね。
I came out of bounds. Wait a moment.
ふふっ、虫にたかられてるビビ！
Hehe, Bibi is swarmed by bugs!
虫臭くなっちゃう！たかられてるやん。
I'll start smelling like bugs! You're swarmed!
一旦...
For now...
今、いたやん。
You were just there.
ここ...
Here...
ここね、多分変なとこ来ちゃった。
Here, I think we ended up in a weird place.
そうよね。
Right?
あれ？ちょ、ビビ一人で入れない？なるほどね。
Huh? Wait, Bibi can't enter alone? I see.
行けるかな？裏画面行きて草。
Can we go? 'Went out of bounds lol'.
みんな来てるじゃん！
Everyone's coming here!
みんな来てて草。 / みんな来てる？
'Everyone came over lol.' / Everyone's here?
これ、もしかすると他のチームもここ探してるっぽいから、湧いてない可能性なのでは？
Could it be that because other teams are searching here, they might not be spawning?
リポップ待ちの可能性はちょっと出てきましたね。
The possibility of waiting for a respawn has come up.
これ上抜けたら抜けれるのかな？
If I go out through the top, can I escape?
あ、抜けれないな。
Ah, can't get out.
抜けれなかった。
Couldn't get out.
なんか、あ、あ、ああー！バグって！
Wait, ah, ah, ahhh! It's bugging out!
水？え？どこ？
Water? Eh? Where?
どっかわかんない！
I don't know where!
え？どこだ？
Eh? Where is it?
なんかこの辺にテレポーターがあるっぽいですけど...
It looks like there's a teleporter around here, but...
なんか水の中に入っ...えっ？！出れない！
I went into water... eh?! Can't get out!
これは...テレポ見せかけやな。
This is... just a fake teleport.
やばい、みんなが！やばい！大丈夫か？
Oh no, everyone! Oh no! Are you okay?
どこ、どこなんだろう？
Where... where is it?
ビビ、迷子になって虫にたかられて、どうしよう！
Bibi got lost and swarmed by bugs, what to do!
ね、迷子になる...
Yeah, getting lost...
えっと、とりあえず移動しまくって、天井抜けれるとこ探すしかないと思う。
Umm, for now, I think our only option is to keep moving and look for a spot to slip through the ceiling.
天井でも結構抜けれないかも。行けそうかな？
Even through the ceiling, might not get out. Does it look doable?
天井は触らないほうがいいです、今ちょっと。
You shouldn't touch the ceiling right now.
そのほうがいいね。触んないほうがいいよ、天井。
That's better. Better not touch the ceiling.
分かりました。
Understood.
なんかバグる？バグってます。
Is it glitching? It's glitching.
バグってる。
It's glitched.
めっちゃ泳いでます。でも出れない。
I'm swimming like crazy. But can't get out.
出口が見つからない。
Can't find the exit.
あ、出ようとすると、なんかガクガクする感じなのかな？
Ah, when you try to get out, does it jitter?
そうね。
Yeah.
なんかブロッキングされてる感じしますね。
Feels like it's being blocked.
ね。
Right.
ああ、なるほど、引っ掛かっちゃってるのか。
Ah, I see, so it's getting caught.
バリアブロックみたいな感じで、なんかすっごい...
Like a barrier block, it's really...
そうそうそう。
Yeah, exactly.
なんかちょっと待ってて、アキ先輩が...
Wait a bit, Aki-senpai is...
これ多分、一旦落ちてから、補填してもらおう。
Maybe after falling through once, we'll get compensated.
え、なんか下に行ったら...戻...いや、でもバグってる、また。
Eh, when I went down... return... no, but it's bugging out again.
まだバグってるか。やっぱり一旦待機でいいかもね。
Still bugged, huh. Guess waiting for now might be best.
一旦待機。
Wait for now.
ちょっと高いところで待機...
Waiting somewhere high up...
じゃあもう一生テレポ探して迷子になってるわ。オッケー。
Then I'll just be searching for teleports forever and getting lost. Okay.
どうしよう、集会場スポーンして...
What should I do, spawn at the meeting place...
ふんふん。
Mm-hmm.
これ...
This...
おおー！
Whoa!
一旦...
For now...
はい。
Yes.
アキちゃんに...ええ、言うか。
Should I... yeah, tell Aki-chan?
やばい。
Oh no.
お、これビビも言ったほうがいいですか？うわっ！
Oh, should Bibi say something too? Whoa!
プテラ死ぬな、これ
My Ptera's gonna die at this rate.
全員やってくれんのかな、言ったら一応
I wonder if they'll do it for everyone if we ask.
多分全員やってくれるはず
They should do it for all of us, probably.
はーい
Okay.
一旦待ちで
Let's wait for now.
待とう。あ、赤...
Let's wait. Ah, red...
光ってる、あの、白いところに
When I went to that shining,
来たら、戻れました、マップに
white area, I got back on the map.
戻れた？
You got back?
嘘！
No way!
ナイス
Nice!
どこかは
I don't know
ナイス、ナイス
Nice, nice!
分かんないですけど
where I am, though.
出れたなら良かった、良かった
Glad you made it out, that's great.
ねー
Yeah.
まっすぐ出れて
I got out by going straight.
良かった
That's a relief.
出れたかな？またバグってる？
Did I get out? Am I glitched again?
アキちゃんのところ行ってくるわ
I'll head over to Aki-chan.
はーい
Okay.
アキ先輩来るから待ってて
Aki-senpai is coming, so just wait.
待つわ、オッケー
I'll wait, okay.
うん
Yeah.
はーい
Okay.
そういうのなんだけどな
That's how it is, but...
いや、またバグってる
No, it's glitched again.
いや、今もね、ちょっと待った方がワンチャンいいかもしれない
Yeah, it might be better to just wait a bit right now.
そうですね、ここで待ちます
Right, I'll wait here.
なんか調査してくれてるって言うから、ちょっと待ってて、ゆっくり
They said they're investigating it, so just wait patiently.
はーい
Okay.
あんま分かんないですけど、普通ってこういう洞窟って上からひょひょって抜けられるものなんですか？
I'm not sure, but can you normally just slip out of caves like this from the top?
どうなんだろう？
I wonder.
多分抜けられ...抜け穴はあると思うけどな。入り口...
I think... there are exits, but... the entrance...
洞窟？
Cave?
指定の入り口以外のちょっと
If you try to slip out from somewhere other than
「あ、ここ抜けれそうだな」ってとこから抜けるとダメっぽいね
the designated entrance, it seems to bug out.
あ、そうなんだ。大きい穴開いてるとこじゃなきゃダメなのか
Ah, I see. So it has to be a wide-open hole, then.
あ、そうそうそう。割と抜けれそうだったんだけどね
Yeah, exactly. It looked totally escapable, though.
もっと上か、これ？
Is it further up?
へぇー、そうなんだ
I see, interesting.
あ、テリジノたちいる
Ah, there are Therizinosaurs.
開いてるとこ見当たんないぞ、これ以外
I don't see any other openings besides this.
あー
Ahh...
バグっちゃってる3人以外は、あの、安全なところで洞窟出られたら...
Aside from the three who are bugged, if you can get out of the cave somewhere safe...
うん
Yeah.
痛い痛い痛い痛い痛い痛い痛い！
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
痛っ！やばい、また虫に...痛い痛い痛い！
Ow! Oh no, the bugs again... Ow, ow, ow!
虫！虫に気をつけて！
Bugs! Watch out for bugs!
やばいやばい、食べられちゃう
Oh no, oh no, I'm gonna get eaten!
無視したら？無視したら？
What if you ignore them?
虫は無視？
Ignore the bugs?
さ、寒い。あ、なんか急に...
C-cold. Ah, suddenly...
寒っ
Cold!
あ、出口辿り着きました、カバさん
Ah, I reached the exit, Kaba-san.
あ、良かった良かった
Ah, that's great.
あ、良かった
Ah, thank goodness.
カバは辿り着いたけど...
Kaba made it, but...
いつも死んでばっかり
Always dying...
自分全然辿り着けないから
I can't reach it at all...
はーい！
Yes!
はい、さっきのスタックの件なんですけど
Okay, regarding the stuck issue from earlier:
順次、えっと、スタックしていた地点の近くにテレポート対応を順次しておりますので
We're teleporting people near where you got stuck one by one,
よろしくお願いします
so please sit tight.
あ、アキちゃん！ありがとう！
Ah, Aki-chan! Thank you!
はいはーい。私死んで装備全ロスしました、異空間
Okay. I died and lost all my gear in hyperspace.
異空間にあって取りに行けなさそう？その近くでは見えないってこと？
It's in hyperspace so you can't retrieve it? You mean you can't see it nearby?
えーとね、なんか変なとこにワープしちゃって、池の、ん？
Well, I warped to a weird place, and in a pond... or
海の中か何か、池の中か何かでもう溺れ死んで、どこに死んだか分かんない
in the ocean or something, I drowned to death, so I don't know where I died.
あ、わため先輩が死んだ
Ah, Watame-senpai died.
ちょっと確認しますね
Let me check on that.
はい、お願いします
Yes, please.
はい
Okay.
貴様ー！
You bastard--!
アキ先輩、あと、トワちゃんのプテラも、その、スタック飛んじゃって...
Aki-senpai, Towa-chan's Ptera also flew off from the glitch...
亡くなっちゃった？
Did it die?
洞窟の中でスタックしちゃって、もう死ぬしかなくて死んじゃったって感じだね
It got stuck inside the cave, had no choice but to die, and ended up dying.
了解。ちょっと確認します
Understood. I'll check on it.
トワもここで復活して、恐竜とかね
Towa will respawn here too, along with the dinos.
怖かったですねー
That was scary.
すみません、ビビはただの迷子なんです。スタックしてない、ただの迷子
Excuse me, Bibi is just lost. Not stuck, just completely lost!
ビビは...
Bibi is...
飛んでるから絶対出られるからね
You're flying, so you can definitely make it out.
ビビはただの迷子
Bibi is just lost.
ビビちゃんマップ開いてさ、緯度経度どこにいるか分かります？マップの下に書いてあるんですけど
Bibi-chan, open your map, can you see your latitude and longitude? It's written at the bottom.
あ、緯度が
Ah, latitude is
あれかな、私の装備
Is that my gear over there?
20.6
はいはいはい
Right, right.
経度が43.6です
Longitude is 43.6.
行ける！緯度が17になるように帰ってきたら、
You can make it! If you head back so the latitude reaches 17,
多分帰ってこれる
you can probably make it back.
今出口にいて17ぐらいで...17助かる、17助かる、こっちゃ
I'm at the exit, around 17... 17 helps, 17 helps, this way.
17の42で帰れます
You can return at 17, 42.
17の42？うわぁ、ビビ地図読めないよぉ
17, 42? Uwah, Bibi can't read maps!
え、でもここにワープ...ここにワープされても私何にもできないんだけど、どうしたらいいんだ、これ
Wait, even if I get warped here, I can't do anything without gear, what should I do?
下に...
Down below...
いや、でも恐竜とかもちょっと見てくれてるんじゃない？
Well, maybe they're looking into the dinosaurs too?
じゃあ、ここで待機すればいいか
Then I guess I should just wait here.
うん
Yeah.
17の40ならこっち...
If it's 17, 40, then this way...
そう、フブちゃん達のところと合流するね
Yeah, you'll meet up with Fubu-chan and the others.
最初の出口は結構青いですね
The first exit is pretty blue.
あ、いいよ
Ah, okay.
最後だけ一瞬青くて、途中までは赤かったりしたんで
Only the very end was briefly blue; it was red for part of the way.
もう下手に動くのやめとこ
I'll stop moving around carelessly.
こっち...一本道だけ進もうかな
This way... maybe I'll just follow the straight path.
あ、アカムシいますね
Ah, there are red worms.
ピラニアがうじゃうじゃだ
Piranhas are swarming everywhere.
え、この辺？
Wait, around here?
道思い出してきたわ。この辺だ
I'm starting to remember the path. It's around here.
合流できたわ
I managed to regroup!
あ、これだ！あった！やっと見つけた！
Ah, this is it! It's here! I finally found it!
え、行き止まり？
Eh? A dead end?
アーティファクト取った？
Did you get the artifact?
いや、ごめん、違っ...ただ迷子になってた、外で
No, sorry, wrong... I was just lost outside.
あ、了解了解
Ah, roger roger!
アーティファクト探します
I'll look for the artifact.
あ、てか、フブちゃんさ、ちょっとここで待って、ここで待って
Ah, by the way, Fubu-chan, wait here for a sec, wait here.
いいよ、ここね？
Okay, right here?
えーっと、ちょっと言うわ
Umm... I'll tell you.
あの、指示するから、それに沿って行ってほしい
I'll give you directions, so please follow them.
あ、オッケーオッケー、了解了解。まっすぐ行くよ、とりあえず。じゃあ
Ah, okay okay, got it. I'll go straight for now, then.
あれ、これ...
Wait, is this...
遺産探しついでにじゃあ行くか。ござるの護衛でアルゲンいるから
Shall we head out while searching for your items? We have an Argentavis escorting Gozaru, so...
あ、アルゲンで...
Ah, on the Argent...
あ、これ...待って、他のチームいるんですけど、他のチームに連れてってもらうのアリですか？
Ah, wait... there's another team here. Is it okay to have them take me?
他のチーム探してるんじゃないか？
Aren't they searching for the items too?
うん、アイテム。えー？
Yeah, the items. Huh?
だったら待っといた方がいいかもね
In that case, it might be better to wait.
まっすぐ進む...まっすぐ進む...
Go straight... go straight...
あ、進んでます、進んでます
Ah, I'm heading forward, I'm heading forward.
はい、こちらアキロゼです。ぼたんちゃん、失ったのって何の恐竜だった？
Yes, this is Akirose. Botan-chan, what kind of dinosaur did you lose?
ええとね...
Well...
迷子...迷子
Lost child... lost child.
プテラと、あの何だっけ？
A Ptera and... what was it again?
メガドロンみたいな
Something like Megalodon...
メガ...メガテリウム？
Mega... Megatherium?
メガテリ、メガテリ。この2体
Megatheri, Megatheri. Those two.
1回下行っちゃうね
I'll head down once.
前回死亡地点は一応出ているよ
The last death marker is showing up though.
あ、マップ座標言っていい？死んだ場所
Ah, can I give you the map coordinates? Where I died.
オッケー
Okay.
死んだ場所の座標がね、経度21.9で...
The coordinates where I died are... longitude 21.9...
あ、緯度が21.9、経度41.9
Ah, latitude is 21.9, longitude 41.9.
41.9...
ちょっとそれで伝えてみまーす
I'll try passing that along.
はい。の、多分ね、川の中で死んでるね
Yes. And, it's probably in the river where I died.
ちょっと確認するねー
I'll go check.
はい、お願いしまーす
Okay, please do!
あ、テリジノか！まあいいか。伝わってるだろう
Ah, it was a Therizino! Oh well, they probably understood.
伝わっとるからいい
They understood, so it's all good.
しばしお待ち...
Please wait a moment...
伝わる伝わる。大丈夫、大丈夫
They'll get it. It's fine, it's fine.
はい、えっとアキロゼです。ぼたんちゃん、テリジノは伝わっていて、テレポートが今でもその場だと何も持ってない状態だと思うんだけど
Yes, this is Akirose. Botan-chan, they understood Therizino. But if they teleport you to the spot now, you won't have any items...
1回戻してほしい場所ある？とりあえず
is there a place you want to be sent back to first?
あの、集会場でいいかな、とりあえず
Um, the meeting place is fine for now.
オッケー。じゃあ一旦そこの集会場に送らせてもらうね
Okay. Then I'll have them send you to the meeting place first.
はーい、オッケー。はーい
Alright, okay. / Okay.
何か見えてる...
Hehe, something is visible...
え、大丈夫ですか？ししろん
Eh, are you alright, Shishiron?
大丈夫だよ。あ、何？全然大丈夫だよ。死んだところでなも、こいつ捨て身行けるから
I'm fine. Ah, what? I'm totally fine. Even if I died there, this guy can go reckless.
何でもいけます？これ
Can he do anything?
みんなの場所に行くのがいいかな...
I wonder if I should go to where everyone is...
あ、いいよ、全然行ってきて。私あの、復活待ちしてるから大丈夫だよ。うん
Ah, go right ahead. Feel free to go. I'm waiting to respawn, so I'm fine. Yeah.
どこ行けばいいのか分からない...
I don't know where I should go...
みんなね、あ、みんなね、チームVC2にいるから、2に行くと大丈夫だよ
Everyone's in Team VC 2, so if you go to 2 you'll be fine.
はい、おっけーです。いいよーん
Okay, got it! / Okey-doke.
迷宮...はい
The labyrinth... okay.
みんな今どこですか？アキロゼさん
Where is everyone right now, Akirose-san?
今、入り口
Right now at the entrance.
入り口...ちょっと探してみます
The entrance... I'll try looking for it.
えっとね、マップ、緯度が17かな
Well, on the map, latitude is around 17 maybe?
うん、17の42ぐらい目指して帰ると帰れる
Yeah, if you head towards around 17, 42 to return, you can get back.
ごめんね、イナちゃん。いえいえ
Sorry, Ina-chan! / No problem at all!
行けるか？
Can you make it?
ちょっとアルジェントのところですか？
Is it near the Argentavis?
あ、そうだね。アルジェントのとこあたりで
Ah, right. Around the Argentavis area.
行くよ、じゃあ。はい
Let's go then. / Okay.
えっと、赤い...赤いキノコか？いいよ
Um, red... red mushroom? / Go ahead.
ここ赤いキノコです。で、ここ左右に分かれるところ
Here is the red mushroom. And here is where it splits left and right.
えっと...
Um...
でも下...え？
Down below though... Huh?
そしたら左に行くって書いてあるけどね
Then it says to go left though.
はい、左。左進みます。あ、ここか
Yes, left. Heading left. / Ah, here?
で、ここから敵が出てきます。で、ここでちょっと広い空間で、えっと...
And enemies will appear from here. And here is a slightly wide open space, and...
あ、待って
Ah, wait.
ん？行っちゃ...あ、待って、このキノコ...ん？ちょっと待ってね
Hm? You went... Ah, wait, this mushroom... Hm? Hold on a sec.
はいはい
Sure, sure.
戻ります
Going back.
分かんない
I don't know...
よいしょ。この辺りから敵生物...ちょっと待って。まっすぐ進んで...
Oof. Hostile creatures from around here... Wait a second. Go straight...
えっと、最初の...最初の分かれ道...
Um, the first... the first fork in the road...
最初の分かれ道を...
The first fork in the road...
左の坂を進むって書いてあるけど、なんかさ、見てるの違うんだけど
It says to go up the slope on the left, but somehow, what I'm looking at seems different.
坂ないですよね
There's no slope, right?
あれかな？入口が違うんか？
Could it be that? Is the entrance different?
か、あの、これASAの洞窟だから、あの、旧ARKの洞窟と、もしかして違うのか？
Or, um, this is an ASA cave, so could it be different from the old ARK caves?
関係ない？ASAラグナロクって書いてあるんだけどな
Doesn't matter? It says ASA Ragnarok though.
待って、塔のところまで戻りよう、じゃあ。青いキノコがあるから
Wait, let's go back to the tower then. There's a blue mushroom there.
これが坂じゃない？ここ
Isn't this the slope? Here.
これがね、坂になってる。あー、うんうんうん...
Yeah, this becomes a slope. / Ah, yeah yeah yeah...
ここ坂です、ここ坂です
This is a slope, this is a slope.
ここ？ここをまず左もしかして？
Here? First turn left here, maybe?
ここ坂です
This is a slope.
どう?
How is it?
坂上って... ん?
Go up the slope... hm?
分かれ道を正面にしてもらって...
Face the fork in the road straight ahead...
分かれ道、分かれ道ここかな? こう?
Fork in the road... is the fork here? Like this?
あ、それ左じゃない?
Ah, isn't that to the left?
それ左っぽいんじゃない? / ここ左でオッケー?
Doesn't that look like left? / Left here, okay?
ここを間を左? はいはい。
Left between here? Okay, okay.
で、広いとこ出ます。多分。
And you'll come out to an open area. Probably.
あ、引っかかる、引っかかる、引っかかる。
Ah, getting stuck, getting stuck, getting stuck.
あ、広いとこ出た?
Ah, did you come out to an open area?
うん、広いとこ出た。
Yeah, came out to an open area.
で、まっすぐでいいのかな?
And is going straight fine?
まっすぐ行っ... た、一本道だね、うん。 / うん。
Go straight... it's a single path, yeah. / Yeah.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
で、まっすぐ行って、そこを...
Then go straight, and there...
行き止まりだから右かな?
It's a dead end, so right?
右、うん、そこは大丈夫。
Right, yeah, that's fine.
うん。右行って...
Yeah. Go right...
うん。
Yeah.
ここは左、まっすぐか左...
Here is left... straight or left...
ここまっすぐか左...
Here straight or left...
待ってね。
Hold on.
あ、ちょっと待って、敵が...
Ah, wait, enemies...
あ、こいつか。
Ah, this guy.
うん。
Yeah.
まっすぐか左です。
Straight or left.
やばい、これね、ちょっとわかんないわ。
Oh boy, this, I don't really know.
なんかちょっと違うんだよな。
It feels a bit different somehow.
左行ってみるか。
Let's try going left.
205レベだ、強え。
Level 205, so strong.
言うてここ一本道だから、結局はこの広い空間にやってきちゃうんだよな。
That said, this is a single path, so you end up at this open space anyway.
あー。
Ah...
うん。
Yeah.
なんかぐるっと一周するだけっぽいな、なんか。
Feels like it just loops around in a circle or something.
そうだよね、多分ね。ね。
Right, probably. Yeah.
うん。
Yeah.
なんかぐるっと一周して帰ってこれちゃうわ。
You just loop all the way around and end up back here.
うん。
Yeah.
むずすぎだろ。
This is way too hard.
ちょっと行ってみるわ、トワも。
I'll try going too.
うん。
Yeah.
こう行って、こう行って...
Go this way, go this way...
イナ先輩救出でござる行こうかな。あ。
Maybe I should go rescue Ina-senpai de gozaru. Ah.
オッケー。出ました?
Okay. Did you get out?
ここ左だよな?
It's left here, right?
1回ちょっと、イナ先輩、う、上、あ、下... 1回もう1個下に...
Wait a sec, Ina-senpai, u-up, ah, down... Go down one more level...
入り口が違うんかな?
Maybe the entrance is different?
行って...
Go...
あ、いや、ん? ここだな。こう行って...
Ah, no, hm? It's here. Go like this...
ここにあったりとか、もしかして?
Could it be around here, maybe?
イナ先輩、無事下に来れますか?
Ina-senpai, can you come down safely?
あ、うん。
Ah, yeah.
あ、いたわ! いたいたいた!
Ah, there she is! Found you!
どこだよ!
Where are you?!
いた?
You saw me?
いた、イナ先輩いた。そしたらね、イナ先輩...
Found you, found Ina-senpai. Then, Ina-senpai...
こっちの...
over this way...
おいで、おいで、おいで。
Come here, come here, come here.
ここが一応出口だから、ここにいとけば間違いないかも。
This is the exit, so if you stay here you should be fine.
もう青いほうがあった?
Did you already find the blue area?
この、あそこテレポーター目の前なんで。
This... over there is right in front of the teleporter.
うん。
Yeah.
ここにいてもらえれば安全かと。
If you stay here, it should be safe.
ここで待つ?
Wait here?
うん、ちょっとBibiさん見に行きます。
Yeah, I'll go check on Bibi-san.
オッケー。
Okay.
よし。
Alright.
どこだここ?
Where is this?
行けそう?
Think you can make it?
ん〜
Hmm...
いや、すんごい難しいじゃないの、これ。
Man, isn't this super hard?
広いよね、すごく。
It's really spacious.
広いね。
It is spacious.
めっちゃ広い。
Super spacious.
だからどうしたものか。
So what to do...
これ戻ってきたな。
I'm back here again.
ちょっとお手洗い行ってきます。
I'm going to run to the restroom.
いってらー。
Take care~
いってらっしゃい。
Take care.
こっち、ここ、こことか、ここ...
Over here, here, around here, here...
ここは違う...
Not here...
ここは違う。ここ一方通行だったよね?
Not here. This was a one-way path, right?
あ、じゃあこっち、さっき、さっきこっち来たんだっけ?
Ah, then here... did I come this way earlier?
さっきこっちで休んだから、こっちなんだよ。
Earlier I rested over here, so it's this way.
んで、こっちですもんな。
And then this way, right.
んで、ここ...
And then here...
むちゃくちゃ広いとこ出たわ。
I came out to a crazy huge area.
そうそう、めちゃくちゃ広いとこあるんですわ。
Right, right, there's a super huge area.
めちゃくちゃ広いとこから、なんかあれなんかな?
From the super huge area, is it like...
分かれたりすんの?
does it branch off or something?
ここから...
From here...
はーん。
Haa...
とりあえずここだよね。ここでさっきこっちに行ったらあって、アーティファクトがね。
Anyway, it's here, right? Earlier when I went this way from here, the artifact was there.
おー、すごいぞこれ!
Ooh, this is amazing!
こっちに行ったらアーティファクト発見。
If you go this way, you find the artifact.
うーん...
Hmm...
おー...
Oh...
うーん...
Hmm...
まあ...
Well...
地道に探索だな、これ。
We just gotta search patiently, huh.
地道に探索なのか、
Whether we just need to search patiently,
もう取られちゃってリポップ待ちなのか、どっちかがちょっとわかんない...
or if it's already been taken and we're waiting for a respawn, I'm not really sure...
確かに
Indeed.
分からないのがちょっとあれかね
Not knowing is a bit tricky, isn't it?
そうだね
Yeah.
うー、あの、上？
Hmm, up above there?
休んだ場所に一回戻... オッケー、休んだ場所に一回戻りやす。
Back to where we rested... Okay, I'll head back once to where we rested.
来ない？
Not coming?
休んだ場所...
Where we rested...
この、あ、ちょちょちょちょ、引っかかっちゃっ...
This... Ah, wait wait wait, got caught...
壁際に向かって
Head along the wall.
よいしょ
There we go.
お？
Oh?
その上、その上
Above that, above that.
広いところまであってて
The wide open spot was right, but...
ここ？ここから？
Here? From here?
I think we're trying to get the artifact.
んで、白樺見えれば場所的に一番近いらしい。ここ？
And if you can see the birch tree, it's supposedly the closest spot. Here?
嘘？
Really?
うん。
Yeah.
Hello.
緑キノコの、あっ
The green mushroom's, ah...
It's uh, it's a bit...
と、言うか言うと、フブちゃん。あ、違うわ、いろはだったわ。
Or rather, Fubu-chan... Ah, wait, no, that was Iroha.
うん。
Yeah.
お？
Oh?
あったかも！
I might've found it!
え、マジ？
Wait, really?
これ、ああ、これだ！多分これだ！
This... Ah, this is it! It's probably this!
あった？
Found it?
お、見つけました？
Oh, did you find it?
あったー！
Found it!
マジかよ！やったー！きたー！
No way! Yay! Here we go!
ナイッスー！
Niiice!
良かったー！なるほど！ありがトスコンブ！感謝ー！
Thank goodness! I see! Thanks a lot! Appreciate it!
感謝感謝！
Thanks, thanks!
オケオケ。
Okay, okay.
お茶の出口ですか？
Is it the Ocha tea exit?
帰ろう、帰ろう帰ろう。
Let's head back, let's head back.
よいしょ、じゃあここ、ここから... オッケーオッケー帰り道は分かる。
Alright, then here, from here... Okay okay, I know the way back.
ナイスー！
Nice!
良かったー！
Thank goodness!
あ、降りちゃった降りちゃった降りちゃったよ。バカバカバカ。
Ah, I dismounted, I accidentally got off! Idiot idiot idiot.
よいしょ。
Alright.
ふー。ああ良かったー、これで。
Phew. Ah, thank goodness, with this...
ミッション一個クリア。
One mission cleared.
ナイスです。あっちは肉をゲットしたし、ナイスだね。
Nice! We got meat on our end too, so nice!
そしたら、メディカルブリューで、もしかしてライトニングワイバーン行ける？
In that case, with Medical Brew, could we maybe go for the Lightning Wyvern?
メディカルブリューがまだ作れてないかなー。
I don't think we've made Medical Brew yet, though.
メリ、メディカルブリュー作りたいね。
Medi... We should make some Medical Brew.
あ、違う違う違う、こっちこっちこっちこっち。
Ah, wait no no no, this way this way this way.
こっちこっちこっち。あ、なんか誰かいる。
This way this way this way. Oh, someone's here.
あっ。
Ah.
誰かいる。誰かいるー。
Someone's here. Someone's here!
あれ？今誰かいた？
Huh? Was someone just there?
出口きつ！重っ！
The exit is rough! So laggy!
あれ？気のせい？
Huh? Was it my imagination?
今出口近くいるよ。行った方がいい？
I'm near the exit right now. Should I go?
あ、大丈夫。今なん、なんか人が歩い、あっ
Ah, it's fine. Someone just walk—ah
誰かいるー
Someone's here!
マイクがあれか、入ってないからか。
Is their mic, like, not on?
ヤッホーヤッホー
Yoo-hoo, yoo-hoo!
よいしょ。
There we go.
運営さんか？それとも。
Is it management? Or...
運営さんか、運営さんが置いてくれたのかもしかして？
Management, maybe management placed it for us?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
やっぱなんかリポップする前に運営さんが置いてくれるらすっぽいで、これね。
Looks like management places them before they respawn naturally, apparently.
あー。
Ah.
あ、へー！
Oh, huh!
うん。
Yeah.
なるほどね。運営さんが設置してくれるんだ。
I see. So management sets it up for us.
感謝。
Grateful.
よしよし、帰ります帰ります帰ります。
Alright, heading back heading back heading back.
ほんならあとあれか、パ、パイロ？
Then after that, what was it... Py... Pyro?
パイロ
Pyro
パイロメインも欲しいよな。
We want a Pyromane too, huh.
よいしょ。火山に行ってまた...
Alright. Head to the volcano again...
よいしょ。
There we go.
あ、こっちこっちこっちこっち、あ、違う違う違う、こっち行って
Ah, this way this way this way... ah wait no no no, go here...
こっちへ行って、こっち...
Go here, and this way...
あ、全然違う。
Ah, completely wrong.
戻ろ、戻ろ。
Let's head back, let's head back.
戻りましょう。
Let's head back.
うん。
Yeah.
ええと、川があって...
Um, there's a river...
ふー...
Phew...
いや、マジで良かったな。
Man, I'm really glad we found it.
広すぎた！
It was way too huge!
本当広すぎた。こっちだこっちだ。
Seriously way too huge. This way, this way.
まさかラグナロクの... 広いんだなぁ。
Man, Ragnarok's... It really is so vast.
めちゃめちゃ広いね。
It really is super huge.
半端なかった。
It was insane.
やばいね。
It's crazy.
恐ろしいくらい広かったな。
It was terrifyingly huge.
うん。
Yeah.
おいおいおいおい。
Hey hey hey hey.
よし。ま、でももう洞窟って行くあれ無いか？
Alright. But do we have any reason to go into the cave anymore?
ボスチャレの時に、何がいるのか調べないとあれかもね。
When we challenge the boss, we might need to check what we need.
帰ってきましたー。
I'm baaack.
あ、ナイスー！
Ah, nice!
おかえりなさーい。
Welcome baaack.
オケオケー。ただいまー。あ、すごいテレポート、ラグ...
Okay okay. I'm back. Ah, such crazy teleporting lag...
イナちゃんはどこだ？
Where's Ina-chan?
あ、ここです。
Ah, over here.
よし、テレポーターの
Alright, the teleporter...
帰ろ帰ろ
Let's head back, head back.
よし
Alright.
オッケー
Okay.
い、ほな行きやす
Alright, here we go.
はーい
Okay.
おっしょ
Oof.
ふぅー
Phew.
オッケー
Okay.
よっしょ
Alright.
ふぅー
Whew.
じゃ上に戻ろっかな、VC
Should I head back up in VC?
はーい、よし
Okay, alright.
ただいまー
I'm back!
ただいまー！
Welcome back!
見つけてきたよー、あったあった
I found it! Found it, found it!
ナイスー！ナイスナイスー！
Nice! Nice, nice!
やばい、上に出なきゃいけないところが分かんなくなっちゃった、ちょっと待って
Oh no, I forgot where I need to go up to get out. Wait a second.
えっと
Let's see...
やっぱ迷いますよね
You really get lost, don't you?
迷うよね
Totally get lost.
もう迷うー
I'm totally lost...
あ、そうか、これ集会場にアーティファクト飾れるのか
Ah, right, you can display artifacts at the gathering area?
あ、そうそうそう、集会場に...
Ah, yeah yeah yeah, at the gathering area...
えっと、どうすんだっけこれ、納品しに行くのか
Um, what do we do with this again? Go deliver it?
ここもずっと迷ってるの
I've been lost here the whole time too.
納品、えーっと
Deliver... let's see...
集会場に、テレポの上に、入る、ところがあったんですけど...
At the gathering area, above the teleporter, there was an entrance, but...
そういえばさ、マンモスー
By the way, about the mammoths...
あ、そうだマンモスも行きたいって言ってたね
Ah right, you said you wanted to go for mammoths too.
マンモスも行きたいね
Yeah, I wanna go for mammoths too.
太鼓を叩くやつ
The ones that beat the drum.
とんでもないんだけど相手
They're crazy opponents, though.
すごー超進んでて、びっくりん
You've progressed so much, I'm amazed!
えー？
Really?
ねえ、めちゃめちゃ進んでる...あ、来た！
Right? Progressing super fast... Ah, here!
チームアーティファクト、でも全種類納品するってあるぞ
Team artifact... but it says "Deliver all artifact types"!
それは多分、すごい最終ミッション的なやつじゃない？
Isn't that probably like the ultimate final mission?
あ、これ2つ納品してくれたのかな、今
Ah, did someone just turn in two of them?
お、すごい！上がってる！
Oh, awesome! It went up!
おいしょ、出れた？
Oof, did I get out?
あれ？なんか、なんかアーティファクトのところ来ちゃった
Huh? I ended up at the artifact place somehow.
な、なんだこれ？ビリビリしてる、ビリビリ
Wh-What is this? It's zapping, zapping!
運営さんが来てる、あれ、違う
An admin is coming... Wait, no.
なんか、間違えてアーティファクトに来た模様、出口が分からん
Seems like I came to the artifact by mistake, I don't know where the exit is!
ごめんなさい、ビビが巻き込んだから
I'm sorry, because Bibi dragged you in...
いや、大丈夫！帰ってきてしまったよ、我が家
No, it's okay! I ended up back home!
これはしゃーないな
Can't be helped.
ござる先輩も引きずり込んでしまった沼に、迷子という沼に
I dragged Gozaru-senpai into the swamp too, the swamp of being lost.
やばいぞー
Oh no!
えっとな、このミッションの
Let's see, of these missions...
えーっと、昨日ちゃんと覚えてたんだけどな
Um, I remembered it properly yesterday, though...
麦わら勢ミッションじゃなくて
Not the Straw Hat crew mission,
ござる先輩が消えたところ？
where Gozaru-senpai disappeared?
そう、ござる先輩が消えたところが
Yeah, where Gozaru-senpai disappeared...
はい
Yes.
えっとね、あ、ビビちょっと今体力が無いかもです、どっか止まりたいです
Um, ah, Bibi might have low stamina right now, I want to stop somewhere.
あ、この辺に止まろう、よし
Ah, let's land around here, okay.
応急処置しましょう
Let's do emergency treatment.
はい
Yes.
あれ、もしかして...止まった
Wait, could it be... Landed.
よかった、危なっ
Thank goodness, that was close!
あれ？
Huh?
ミッションはもしかして...間違えた
Could the mission be... Misclicked.
1つ回復できそう？
Think you can recover one?
はい、回復します
Yes, recovering now.
オッケー、ちょー
Okay, let's see...
この免疫が1個ってことか。上に入ってった中が分かんなくなっちゃってね
So that means one Immune artifact. I lost track of the inside going up.
どっかからこう上にスポッて入る場所があるんだけど
There's a place where you slip right into the top, but...
はい
Yes.
その、上にスポッて入る場所を見失ってしまって...
I lost track of that place where you slip right into the top...
スポット？
Spot?
そうそう、えっと、入る場所がね...
Yeah yeah, um, the entrance is...
これかつてチームミッションだったよね？チームミッション...
This used to be a team mission, right? Team mission...
あーどうしよう
Ah, what should we do...
どうしましょう
What should we do?
あ、なるほど、ポイントが30ポイントってことか
Ah, I see! The points are 30 points!
そうやね
That's right.
あーなるほどなるほどね
Ah, I see, I see.
チームでね
As a team.
チームで30ポイント貰えてるってことか、オッケー
So we got 30 points as a team, okay.
やばい、同じところを回ってる気がするけど、景色が全然変わんないから覚えられない
Oh no, I feel like I'm going in circles, but the scenery doesn't change at all so I can't memorize it!
えっとな、ござる画面共有してもらえたら多分いけるかも。一旦ボイチャ2行こ？
Um, if Gozaru can screenshare we can probably make it. Let's go to VC 2 for a bit?
オッケー、ちょっと待ってくださいね。ワンチャンここかも
Okay, please wait a sec. This might just be it.
やばい、またそしてござる先輩を見失ったビビ
Oh no, and Bibi lost sight of Gozaru-senpai again!
あれだ、メディカルブリューあれよね
That's it, Medical Brew, right?
どこ待ち？えっと
Waiting where? Um...
じゃビビさんもちょっと1回下行こう
Then Bibi-san, let's head down once too.
ブロントサウルス
Brontosaurus.
来た！もう来た！うわ、ここ来たことあるなしかも
I'm here! Already here! Woah, and I've been here before too!
ねえ
Yeah.
もうダメだ
It's no use.
ビビ、ボイチャ2に来てほしい
Bibi, I want you to come to VC 2.
はい、行きます
Yes, going now.
みんな色々大変だ
Everyone's having quite a time.
イナー
Inaaa!
イナ、イナ何してる今？
Ina, Ina, what are you doing now?
今何をしてまーす？
What am I doing right now?
探知
Detecting.
メディカルブリューを...
The Medical Brews...
そうですね
Right.
作るやつだね。トワ様、トワ様今これミュートか？
The ones you make, right. Towa-sama, is Towa-sama muted right now?
トワさまー
Towa-samaaa!
トワ様が多分スピーカーじゃないわ
Towa-sama probably... not on speakers, rather...
スピーカーもミュートになってるから多分聞こえないんだよな
Her speaker is also muted, so she probably can't hear us.
メディカルブリューってティントベリーと、あれち...
For Medical Brews, Tintoberry and... wait...
ですよね
Right.
麻酔薬？
Narcotics?
うん
Yeah.
ただね なんか工業用の なんかあれがいる 鍋 何だっけ？
Though, we need like an industrial pot... What was it?
だから 多分麻酔薬いっぱい作っとけば
So, if we just make lots of narcotics...
麻酔薬いっぱい作っとくわ 鉄の鍋か？
I'll make a bunch of narcotics. An iron pot?
工業用…
Industrial...
調理鍋でもいけんの？
Can we use a Cooking Pot too?
えっと Cooking Potって何だろう 日本語で
Um, what is "Cooking Pot" in Japanese?
普通の鍋でも作れるけど水筒がいる
You can make it in a regular pot, but you need water jars.
あ 水筒バンバンぶち込んで普通の鍋でも作れるらしいよ
Ah, apparently if you chuck a bunch of water jars in, you can make it in a regular pot too.
ああー
Ahh.
へえ 水筒に水入れてそれごと鍋に突っ込む
I see, fill the jars with water and toss the whole thing in the pot.
え そっちの方が楽なんじゃない？ていうか今トワ様が作ってんのかな？
Wouldn't that be easier? Wait, is Towa-sama making it now?
トワ様がね 今あれなんだよね
Towa-sama is currently, you know...
ミュート…
Muted...
はい
Yes.
スピーカーミュートで こっちの声が多分聞こえてないんだよね
...on speaker mute, so she probably can't hear us.
あ でも水 水源は所々にあのアレ 井戸水じゃないけど設置されてるからそこから引っ張れるから
Ah, but as for the water source, those well-like taps are placed around, so we can draw from there.
はい
Yes.
トワ様がどこまでやってるかなんだよな
It depends on how far Towa-sama has gotten with it.
あ トワさん作ってんだ じゃあいいか
Ah, Towa-san is making it. Then we're good.
作ってるらしい
Apparently she's making it.
あ オッケーです
Ah, okay.
オッケー あ じゃあちょっと下行くか？
Okay. Ah, should we head down then?
はい
Yes.
イナ 下行こう スムーズに
Ina, let's head down. Smoothly.
落ちた
I fell.
もしもし
Hello?
はい
Yes.
おかえりー
Welcome back!
今 て 手持ちぶ 無沙汰っす
Right now, I'm kind of at a loose end.
パイロ今テイムしに行く？
Wanna go tame a Pyromane now?
パイロ行く？ パイロ行く？
Go for Pyromane? / Go for Pyromane?
でも私ね…
But you know, I...
恐竜が別の…になるかな 行けたとしたら
...wonder if I can switch dinos... if we can go.
あー なる…
Ah, I see...
ほんとに？
Really?
あの さっき死んであれになっちゃったから
Because I died earlier and ended up like that.
あー
Ah.
あー そっかそっかそっか
Ah, right, right, right.
で じゃあ皆持ってるよね あの クエでもらったさ恐竜使えば多分… 盾にはできるから
Then everyone has one, right? If we use the dinos from the quest, they can probably tank.
うん 多分行けるはず
Yeah, it should work.
だよね
Right?
んむんむ ほんだらパイロ行こうか
Mhm. Then let's go for the Pyromane.
行けそうだったら
If it seems doable.
うん
Yeah.
うん じゃあパイロ行こう え 何がいい？
Yeah, let's go for Pyromane. What should we bring?
何がいいんだろう？オビラプタ…オビラプト…
What's good? Oviraptor... Ovirapt...
あ あれだ あの イナのテリ…テリジノだっけ？
Ah, that one, Ina's Theri-... Therizino, was it?
あ ユティラじゃないっすか？
Ah, isn't it Yuty?
あ ユティラかも イナのユティラでも戦える
Ah, maybe Yuty. We can fight with Ina's Yuty too.
だから イナが引き付けてししろんが乗る感じかな？
So Ina draws aggro and Shishiron mounts it?
オッケー
Okay.
うん
Yeah.
頑張るぞ
Let's do this!
すいません お願いします ごめんなさい
Sorry, please do! Apologies.
で 乗った後に何か敵倒しに行かないといけないんだよね
And after mounting, you have to go defeat enemies, right?
あ そうそう 近くのやつを多分殴るのかな？
Ah, right right. Probably hit nearby ones?
はいはいはい
Right, right, right.
で なんかゲージを溜めるらしい 自分まだテイムしたことなくて
And apparently you build up a gauge. I haven't tamed one myself yet.
で ゲージ溜めて…
And once you build the gauge...
行けそう？
Can we do it?
火を消す みたいな感じよね
...you extinguish the fire, something like that.
あ そうそうそうそう
Ah, yeah yeah yeah yeah.
よしよしよしよし
Alright, alright, alright.
どこ行った？居た居た居た居た
Where did it go? There it is, there it is!
らしい
Apparently.
分かった やってみる
Got it. I'll give it a try.
行ってみてくれ
Go give it a shot.
これで…
With this...
あ 追って…
Ah, wait...
あ クモ クモやっちゃいな
Ah, take out the spider!
クモ多分飛ぶ
The spider will probably jump.
うん よいしょ
Yeah. Heave-ho.
255やば
255 is crazy.
え 倒せんのかな？
Wait, can we beat it?
大丈夫 多分行けるはず
It's okay, we should be able to.
ほんならイナちょっと行ってみるか
Then Ina, wanna go check it out?
はい
Yes.
いいよ
Go ahead.
いで
Come forth.
頼むー
Good luck!
やばい
Oh no.
いや ビビに阻まれた ちょっと待って こっち向いて
No, Bibi blocked me. Hold on, look this way.
よしよし 嫌だー
Okay, good. Nooo...
降りて やばい 糸まみれすぎてやばい
Dismount... Oh no, covered in too much web, this is bad!
うん
Yeah.
あ ししろんという名のボイチャさんの方がいいかもしんねぇ すまん こっちめっちゃかかりそう
Ah, Shishiron aka Voice Chat-san might be better. Sorry, this is gonna take me a while.
やばいやばいやばい
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
頑張れー
Hang in there!
イナさん イナさん
Ina-san, Ina-san.
はい
Yes.
ビビはもう死んでもいい…
Bibi can die...
うん タンクできるやつだったらなんでもええっぽい
Yeah, looks like anything that can tank will work.
さあ ユティ持って…
Now, bring the Yuty...
あ それかテリジノ？
Ah, or Therizino?
あのー クエで貰ってるはずなんだけど 個人クエでテリジノ貰えるもんね
Um, you should have gotten one from the quest... You get a Therizino from the solo quest.
あー
Ah.
テリジノだと多分余裕
With a Therizino, it's probably a breeze.
あ じゃあ…
Ah, then...
私テリジノ余裕だった ステ振りして
Therizino was easy for me after allocating stats.
ちょっとまだ取りに行ってないので 多分…
I haven't gone to pick it up yet, so probably...
あ オケオケ 周回以上よ
Ah, okay okay. More than enough laps.
はい
Yes.
えっと あ ここか
Um... ah, here?
ほんだら ちょっと待って 私がやることは えー寝袋を近くに置いた方がいいんだよね
Then, hold on. What I need to do is... uh, place a sleeping bag nearby, right?
え、多分... ここだっけ？
Um, maybe... Is it here?
ここだったかな？
Was it here, I wonder?
テリ... テリジノサウルス？
Theri... Therizinosaurus?
かな？
Maybe?
オッケー。
Okay.
テリジノ。
Therizino.
んで...
And then...
これってマウントも必須...
Does this also require a saddle...
テリ...
Theri...
え、スペリングが... T-H...
Uh, the spelling is... T-H...
テリジノサウルス。
Therizinosaurus.
え...
Um...
えーっと、どこ...
Um, where...
木材、わら... え、何？
Wood, thatch... Wait, what?
スミスィー。
Smithy.
えー、4個ぐらい作っとこ。
Um, I'll craft about four.
あれ？
Huh?
で、パイを捕獲した後は、どのみちダンジョン行くのにいた方がいいから、欲しいって感じだね。
And after we tame the Pie, we'll need it for the dungeon anyway, so it's good to have it.
Hide, wood, fi... fiber, ingot.
土台か。えー...
A foundation, huh. Um...
木の...
Wood...
土台。
foundation.
あ、もうあった。オッケ、オッケ、オッケ。
Ah, it was already there. Okay, okay, okay.
わらでもいい。木の土台。
Thatch is fine too. A wooden foundation.
あ、聞いて... たんですか？
Ah, did you hear me?
はい、はいはいはい。
Yes, yep, yep, yep.
あ。
Ah.
えーっと...
Um...
今テリ持って...
Now that I have the Theri...
うん。
Yeah.
何かもっと必要なこと... ありますか？
Is there anything else that we need?
行く前に？
Before we go?
えっとねー、
Well,
イナはー、イナは生きててくれたらいい。
Ina... as long as Ina stays alive, that's fine.
が、頑張ります。
I-I'll do my best.
死ぬのは私だけでいいかな？
It's fine if only I die.
はい。
Okay.
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a second.
お、わら。
Oh, thatch.
木材と繊維。
Wood and fiber.
イナ、ちょっと待ってね。
Ina, wait a moment, okay?
はい。
Okay.
わらの土台でいいか。
A thatch foundation should be fine.
じゃあ、ユウティは持って行かなくてもいいですよね？
Then, we don't need to bring the Yuty, right?
あの、テリがあるから。
Since we have the Theri.
そうだね。まあ一応持っててもいいよ。あの、出すのは一匹でいいから。
Right. Well, you can bring it just in case. You only need to deploy one.
あ、そうですね。オッケーです。
Ah, that's true. Okay.
そうそうそう。
Yep, yep, yep.
ほんだら...
In that case...
今アイテム作ってます。
I'm crafting the items now.
はい
Okay.
雪降ってきた
It started snowing.
おっ
Oh.
よし
Alright.
じゃあ、イナ、テレポート...
Alright, Ina, via teleport...
はい
Yes.
で、火山？
to the volcano?
えっとね、ちょっと待ってね
Um, wait a second.
乗っててもろうて...
Get on it...
違う
wait, no...
うーん、ここか
Hmm, here maybe?
飛びまーす
Teleporting!
おふ
Oof.
あ、でも、あ、今チャンスだ。雨降ってるから、
Ah, but, ah, now's our chance. Since it's raining,
はい
Yeah.
火が消えてるはず
the fire should be out.
パイロの
On the Pyromane.
はい
Yeah.
この隙に... じゃあどっか、じゃ近場でもいいかも
While we have the chance... Then somewhere... maybe nearby is fine too.
あ、あっちに一匹...
Ah, there's one over there...
あ、いるいる。あ、これこれ。で、
Ah, there it is. Ah, this one, this one. And,
タレ、えっとタンク...
the turr- um, the tank...
はい
Yeah.
テリジノ... テリジノでターゲットになって
Therizino... draw aggro with the Therizino...
うん
Mhm.
あ
Ah.
いやー！やめろー！
Nooo! Stop it!
いける？
You okay?
戦って！
Fight!
オッケー
Okay.
で、ヒットポイント半分、半分まで行けば...
And if its HP goes down to half...
え、えっと...
Uh, um...
あ、いや！
Ah, no!
プテラ逃がしてもいいかも
You can let the Ptera fly away.
えっ
Eh?
ほらっ
There!
まだ乗れない
Can't ride it yet.
あ、ターゲット...
Ah, target...
いやー！
Nooo!
どこ行った？え？どこ？
Where did it go? Eh? Where?
あれ？あれ？どこ行った？
Huh? Huh? Where did it go?
あれ？
Huh?
あれどこ行った？
Where did it go?
あれ？
Huh?
え？消えた？
Eh? Did it disappear?
どうした？
What happened?
いや、倒したって出てないよね？
It didn't say it was defeated, right?
ないですよね？
It didn't, right?
あれどこ行った？
Where did it go?
き、消えました？
D-Did it disappear?
あれ消えた？
Huh, did it disappear?
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
え、なんか...
Uh, looks like...
あ、自爆したんだ。あ、自爆したんだって
Ah, it self-destructed. Ah, chat says it self-destructed.
ああー！
Ahhh!
飛んでる、戻ってー
Tonderu, come back!
じゃあ...
Well then...
オッケー、じゃあイナ、テリジノ乗っといてもらってたら、
Okay, then Ina, maybe you can stay mounted on the Therizino,
はい
Okay.
いいかも
that might be good.
はい、乗りました
Okay, I'm on it.
じゃあ、次のおっ...
Then the next...
次の... 次の探して...
Looking... looking for the next one...
探しましょう
Let's search.
はい
Yes.
オッケー
Okay.
ちょっと待ってね、こいつ...
Hold on, this guy...
ダスキンさん...
Duskin-san...
着陸してもらわないと。オッケー。
Need to have it land. Okay.
はい
Okay.
あの、で...
Um, and...
テラはヘルスでタンクがいいですね
Theri would be good as a health tank, right?
あ、イナは乗ったまま攻撃でいいかも
Ah, Ina, you can just attack while staying mounted.
はい
Okay.
うん
Yeah.
あ、なんかポイントをヘルス、HPに入れたら多分...
Ah, if we put points into health, HP, maybe...
うん、半分...
Yeah, half...
いいですね
Sounds good.
オッケー
Okay.
うん、ハーフHP？
Yeah, half HP?
いるかなー
I wonder if there are any...
レベル低い奴がいいんだよなー
A low level one would be better...
うーん、なんか前はいっぱい居ましたけどね
Yeah, there used to be a lot before, though.
いや
No.
あ、雨が...
Ah, the rain...
あ、雨止んじゃったわ
Ah, the rain stopped.
いやーーー
Nooo!
じゃあ...
Well then...
えっと、海の方に、海の方？
Um, towards the sea, towards the sea?
はい
Yes.
2匹連れて行こうか
Let's bring the two of them along.
ちょっと待ってね、ほんなら...
Hold on, in that case...
あ、また雨？
Ah, rain again?
かな？
Maybe?
あ、また雨振っ... あ、火山の方だと雨降ってるかも。エリア...
Ah, it's raining agai- Ah, it might be raining by the volcano. The area...
あー、そうですね
Ah, that's true.
エリアの境目だね。そう、そうだね。
It's the biome boundary. Right, yeah.
じゃあ、ちょっとでも施策はあるか
Well, do we have some sort of plan?
バイオームで変わるんだね
It changes by biome, huh.
あ、確かにバイオームで変わってるわ。でも水の中でもいいかも。
Ah, it definitely changes with the biome. But in the water might be fine too.
ですね
True.
うん
Yeah.
てなるとちょっとこっち側なんだよな
In that case, it's a bit more on this side.
あ
Ah.
ちょっと待ってね、イナ
Wait a moment, Ina.
はい
Okay.
オッケー
こっち、こっちだよ
This way, this way!
ああ、ちょっとテレポーター一旦戻ってきてもらっていい？
Ah, could you head back to the teleporter for a moment?
あ、はい
Ah, okay.
と思ったんだけど
That's what I thought, but...
あの、ここのバイオームだと雨降ってて
Um, it's raining in this biome,
はい
Right.
ここで今やりきっていいかもっていう
so maybe we can finish it off right here.
テレポどこだったっけ？
Where was the teleport again?
えっと、ここで…上だった
Um, around here... It was up above,
上か。オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Up above? Okay, okay, okay.
気がします。
I think.
あ、いるいるいるいるいる。
Ah, there it is, there it is!
あ。
Ah.
いる？
Is it there?
その先に。
Just ahead.
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ、行きます！
Alright, going in!
はい。
Okay.
ぴょんって。
It leaped.
なんか、いつ止ま…
Like, when does it stop...
イナ、イナ、イナ助けて！後ろに…
Ina, Ina, Ina, help! Behind me...
あ、カマキリがいる。
Ah, there's a mantis!
あー！
Aah!
おらぁ！
Take that!
ごめんね。
Sorry!
あ。
Ah.
危ない。
Watch out.
おら！俺はちょっと逃げます。
Take that! I'm gonna run away a bit.
に、逃げてください！
P-Please run away!
痛い痛い痛い痛い。
Ow ow ow ow!
おら、おい！
Take that, hey!
オッケー。
Okay.
痛い痛い痛い痛い。
Ow ow ow ow.
あー。
Aah.
重い。
I'm heavy.
あ、でも私まあ死んでも、最悪。
Ah, but even if I die, worst-case.
何がそん…こんなに重いんだ。
What's making me so heavy?
イナの方行くね。
I'm heading toward you, Ina.
はい。
Okay.
いや、ちょっと…
Wait, hold on...
あ痛い…いやーちょっと…
Ow, ow... Man, wait...
行く？
Shall I come?
いや、すぐ行く、すぐ行く。
No, I'll be right there, right there.
すぐ行くんで、ちょっとお待ちください。
I'm coming right away, so please wait a moment.
あーっと、どこだ？
Umm, where is it?
これ雨降ってんのやべえな。低体温になっちゃう。
This rain is bad news. I'm gonna get hypothermia.
うっ
Ugh.
今行きますー。
I'm on my way~
あっちから行った方が早かったか。
Would it have been faster to go from that way?
まだ迷える、まだ迷える。
I can still get lost, still getting lost.
ボタンとイナ大丈夫かー？
Botan and Ina, are you guys okay?
今、パイロテイム頑張ってる。
Right now, we're working hard on taming the Pyromane.
オッケー。
Okay.
そっち合流できる…
Can I join you guys...
あ、でも来て、武器欲しいかも。
Ah, but come over, we might want weapons.
オッケーオッケー分かった。今行くねー。
Okay, okay, got it. Coming over now~
はい、いいよー。
Alright, sure thing~
ちょっと遅れますよ。いいよー。
I'll be a bit late. No problem~
さみー。イナ、まだいる？
So cold. Ina, still there?
はい！同じところです！
Yes! In the exact same spot!
はい、戦ってる？
Okay, fighting it?
戦ってます！
We're fighting it!
オッケー。乗れそうなら乗る。
Okay. If you can mount it, ride it.
近くに水辺とかあんの？
Is there water nearby or something?
あ、なんか止まった？
Ah, did it stop?
いや、今雨降ってんの、雨。
No, it's raining right now, rain.
あー、オッケーオッケー。
Ah, okay, okay.
うん。
Yeah.
そちらどんな感じー？
How's it going over there?
今雨降っててチャンス。
It's raining now, so it's a great chance.
あ、確かに大チャンスじゃん！
Ah, you're right, that's a huge chance!
大チャンス。イナどこー？
Huge chance. Ina, where are you?
え、そっち行こうかな、ちょっとじゃあ。
Eh, maybe I should head there too then.
来て欲しい。
I'd like you to come.
えーっと、ししろんが死んだところくらい…
Um, around where Shishiron died...
かなり、あ、オッケー。オッケー。
Pretty much, ah, okay. Okay.
え？
Eh?
今のんびりでもいいかなと思ったりしたけど…
I was thinking we could take our time now, but...
え、あ、何でもいい。それか、溶岩…ゴーレムやりにいくか。溶岩ゴーレムだっけ？
Eh, ah, either is fine. Or should we go do the Lava... Golem? Was it Lava Golem?
イナの方に行きます。
I'm heading toward Ina.
あの、丸火の方、丸火の方行こうかなーと。
Um, I was thinking of heading toward the circled fire icon.
とはいえね、ボタンのところ合流しようかなと思った。
Even so, I thought I'd join up with Botan.
あ、じゃあ丸火行ってきます。
Ah, then I'll go to the circled fire.
はーい。
Okay.
チナ、パイロは今火山に…
By the way, the Pyromane is at the volcano now...
えっと、右上だよね、今。
Um, it's top right right now, right?
うん。
Yeah.
オッケーオッケー。右上行って…
Okay, okay. Going top right...
え、いつ止ま…
Eh, when does it stop...
で、あ、イナいた。
And, ah, found Ina.
今それ半分行ったかな？
Did that reach half HP now?
分かりません。
I don't know.
あ！
Ah!
爆発した。
It exploded.
あ、爆発したね。オッケーオッケー。
Ah, it exploded. Okay, okay.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
固まった。
It froze.
ゲーム？
The game?
え、半分にしたら何か分かるんですか？
Wait, can you tell once it's at half?
なんかに、吠える。1回吠えるらしいよ。「わー」みたいな。
Supposedly it roars. It roars once, like "Raaar".
おー。
Ohh.
あ、なんか止まった時乗る感じですか？
Ah, so we ride it when it stops?
フリーズした…
When it freezes...
そうそうそうそう。
Right, right, right, right.
あー、なるほどー。
Aah, I see.
ヒットポイント半分になると、あの、乗れるんだって。
When its HP drops to half, apparently you can ride it.
あーー。
Aahh.
で、乗ったあとに色々…
And after riding it, you do various...
はいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right, right.
やるみたいな。
things, apparently.
了解です。
Understood.
うん。
Yeah.
オッケー。
Okay.
そして…もうちょっと上げよう。
And... let me level it up a bit more.
はいはいはい。じゃ、次…
Right, right, right. Alright, next...
次のやつ行こっか
Shall we go for the next one?
はい、行きましょう
Yes, let's go.
オッケー
Okay.
ただ、望遠...あ、トワ様ー？
Though, spygl... Ah, Towa-sama?
トワ様ー？
Towa-sama?
あ、聞こえてない？
Ah, can't she hear?
あ、聞こえてないか。
Ah, she can't hear, huh.
望遠鏡あった方がまあ、分かりやすいらしい。
Apparently it's easier to tell with a spyglass,
うーん。
Mhm.
ヒットポイントが分かるから。
since you can see their hit points.
うん。
Yeah.
ま、でも1回やってみよう。
Well, let's just give it a try once.
はい。
Okay.
Alright.
吠えたら私がスッて乗ればいいのか。
If it roars, I just smoothly mount it, right?
あ、でもその先にいるかも？
Ah, but maybe there's one further ahead?
違うか。水晶か。
No? Ah, it's crystal.
うーん。
Hmm.
望遠鏡覗いて3秒もなかなかシビアな気がするな。
Still, looking through a spyglass for 3 seconds feels pretty tough.
そうですね。
That's true.
なかなか...
Pretty tough...
どこかなー？
Where could it be?
どこかなー、いるかなー？
Where is it, are there any around?
ちょ待ってねー。
Wait a sec~
PC落ち...PCっていうかゲーム落ちたんで再起動してましたー。
My PC cra... Well, the game crashed, so I was restarting it~
はーいよー。
Okaay.
はい、今探している、パイロ。
Right, currently looking for a Pyromane.
おいっ。
Oof.
雨降ってるとさすがに見づらいな。
It's really hard to see when it's raining.
ここらへんなのね。
Around here, huh.
なんか青色のパイロとかもいたよね？
There were blue Pyromanes too, weren't there?
あ、いたいた。
Ah, yeah, there were.
結構いろんな色いる。
There're quite a few different colors.
ね！
Yeah!
ジンオウガみたい...ジンオウガみたいなパイロいた。
Like Zinogre... There was a Pyromane that looked like Zinogre.
確かに。
Indeed.
ね。
Right.
かっこいいよ。
It looks cool.
やばい、トワが前回死亡したやつまだついてる。「もういいよ、それぇ！」
Oh man, Towa's death marker from last time is still active. "That's enough of that already!"
もうそっから流れが悪いんだよ！もうこのクソクソクソクソクソがぁ！
The bad luck started right from there! Argh, crap crap crap crap crap!
あれ？雨降ってると、いないのかなー？
Huh? Do they not show up when it's raining?
てか夜だから...
Or maybe because it's night...
あー、確かに。
Ah, true.
寝てるとかあんのかな？
Maybe they're sleeping?
あ、いたいた！
Ah, found one, found one!
あ、どこですか？
Ah, where is it?
えーっと、連れてくわ。
Umm, I'll lure it over.
お、これかな？
Oh, is this it?
あ、いたわ。いたかな？
Ah, there is one. Or is there?
ん？いた？
Hm? Found one?
これだな。いたいたいた。
This is it. Found it, found it.
1匹いたね。緑の綺麗なやつがいる。
There's one. A pretty green one.
あ、じゃあそっちでもいいかも。
Ah, then maybe that one works too.
テレポーターの近くにいます。
I'm near the teleporter.
あ、オッケー。持ってく。
Ah, okay. I'll bring it.
どれくらいの体力なのか分かんないな。
I don't know how much HP it has.
なんか吠えてくれるらしいけどね。
Apparently it's supposed to roar though.
え、今吠えた？
Wait, did it just roar?
これだ。待って。
Here it is. Wait.
今連れてってますー。
Bringing it over now~
行けた！行けた行けた行けた。
Got it! Got it got it got it.
はーい。
Okay.
こいつでーす！
Here it is!
ほらぁ！
There!
お願いしまーす。
Take it away~
はい、ダッシュと...
Okay, Dash and...
じゃあ降ります。
Alright, I'm dismounting.
今、イナの方に行きまーす。
Heading towards Ina now~
吠えたら近づきます。
When it roars, I'll get close.
え、待って、フレーム...フレーム吸収すんのどうやってやんだ、これ？
Wait, how do you absorb the flame on this?
え？こいつレベル15だったからめっちゃ弱かったかも。
Huh? Since this one was level 15, it might have been super weak.
ああ、そっかあ！
Ah, I see!
ごめん、イナちゃん！
Sorry, Ina-chan!
レベル低いとくっそ弱いから...
Low levels are stupidly weak, so...
Ctrl右クリックのほうか。
Ctrl + Right click, maybe?
右クリックだった。
It was right click.
いいよー。
It's fine~
あ、イナ、こいつ頼みます。
Ah, Ina, please take care of this one.
あ、これですか？
Ah, is it this one?
トワのとこにもう一匹いるな。
There's another one by Towa.
じゃあ、トワっちさ、どこにいる？
Then, Towacchi, where are you?
うん？
Hm?
今ね、うち等見えないかも。ちょうどやっちゃってるわ。
Right now, you might not be able to see us. We're fighting right now.
オッケー。
Okay.
うち乗ったりする？
Should I mount it?
あ、トワ、そのパイロメインちょっと弱いかも。
Ah, Towa, that Pyromane might be a bit weak.
ちょっとこれいいや。ごめん。
Forget about this one. Sorry.
ちょっと...
Just a sec...
あ、あっちですか？
Ah, is it over there?
リセットするわ。パイロメイン。
I'll reset it. The Pyromane.
ちょい...
Just...
あ、オッケー。今近いよ。
Ah, okay. It's close now.
あいそう...
Looks like it...
近いですー。
It's close~
あ、イナいる！
Ah, Ina's here!
ここ。
Here.
あ、行きます。
Ah, here I go.
はい、お願いします。
Okay, please do!
このパイロはもう倒れるのかな？
I wonder if that Pyromane is going down?
あいつはもう倒している。
That one's already been taken down.
ほりゃ！
Take that!
あ、20か。
Ah, level 20?
弱いか。
Is it weak?
20です、レベル。
It's level 20.
じゃあ、頑張って。
All right, good luck!
痛い。
Ouch.
まだ、まだ乗れない？
Can you still not ride it?
どうですか？
How about now?
乗れた、乗れた！
You mounted it! You mounted it!
あ、よかった！
Ah, thank goodness!
で…あ、なんかマンティスが…ちょっと。
And... Ah, there's a Mantis...
で、倒しに行くんだよね、これ敵を。敵いる？
And then you go kill enemies, right? Are there any?
そうそう、敵倒しに行く。
Yeah, go defeat enemies.
いるかな敵。
Are there any enemies?
あの、ここにマンティスがあったんですけど、殺しちゃった、スバル先輩。
Um, there was a Mantis here, but I killed it, Subaru-senpai...
あ、いいよいいよ。
Ah, that's fine, that's fine!
で、別の…
And another...
あ、でもいるわ。
Ah, but there are some over here.
あ、ダメだ、降りちゃった。
Ah, no good, it dismounted.
ああ。
Ah...
イナ、こっち来れる？敵がいなかったわ。
Ina, can you come here? There were no enemies.
まだ行き…行きます！
I'm still... I'm coming!
いや、やばい、やばい、ちょっと。やばい。
Wait, oh no, oh no, hold on. Bad.
あああ！
Aaaah!
固まった今、ね、スタックした！
It froze just now! It got stuck!
え、2匹？
Wait, two of them?
90か。
Is it 90?
熱い！
It's hot!
2匹…
Two of them...
あ、パイロは燃えないんだ、そうなんだ。
Ah, Pyromanes don't burn, huh. I see.
あ、ちょっと、プールとかなんかある？
Ah, wait, is there a pool or something?
1回死ぬ？
Do you want to die once?
うわー！
Wah!
ベッド。
Bed.
ベッドから行こうかな。
Maybe I'll respawn from the bed.
これはレベル90か。
This one is level 90, huh...
レベル90のそれ、まだいけるんだったら…
If you can still take on that level 90 one...
大丈夫そう？
Does it look doable?
多分いけると思います、ちょっと…
I think I probably can, just...
テレポーター…
Teleporter...
しんど。
So rough...
もうなんでやねん！ついてきて。
Why, seriously?! Follow me!
テレポーターまで行けるかな？
I wonder if I can make it to the teleporter?
あ。
Ah.
あれが欲しいな。
I want that.
いや、乗れるかどうか分かんないな。
Man, I don't know if I can ride it.
騎乗までは行けた？
Did you manage to mount it?
行けた。騎乗までは行けたんだけど、敵がいなくて、なんか時間切れで倒せなかったんだよね。
I did. But there were no enemies, so time ran out and I couldn't beat it.
ああ、なるほど。近くにか。
Ah, I see. Need them nearby, huh.
そうそうそう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
なんかここに敵もあるし、
There are enemies here too, and...
レベル90なんですけど…
It's level 90, but...
布が欲しいな。
I want cloth.
革これ貰っとこ。
I'll grab this hide.
できるかな？
Can I do it?
バック。
Back.
バックちゃん。
Back-chan.
いや、分かんない。
No, I don't know.
条件揃えば行けそうなんだけどね。
It seems doable if the conditions are met, though.
うん。
Yeah.
あれだね、アルゲンでなんか弱い敵を掴んで待機させとくっていう方法もあるらしい。
Apparently there's also a method where you grab a weak enemy with an Argent and keep it ready.
ん〜。
Hmm...
殴り用で、うん。
For hitting, yeah.
ここ来れますか？
Can you come here?
素材がないな。
I don't have materials.
てか雨終わっちゃったのか？
Wait, did the rain stop?
見る？
Should we check?
雨？やってるの？
Rain? Is it still going?
まだ降ってると思う。
I think it's still raining.
え、乗れない。
Huh, I can't mount it.
おお。
Ooh...
あ、今行ける、行ける。
Ah, now I can, I can!
行けるか？
Can you?
行けない、行けない。
I can't, I can't.
行けるか？
Can you do it?
なんでやねん。
Why, seriously?!
え、逃げた？
Huh, did it run away?
とりあえず。
For now...
そっちにまた戻ります。
I'll head back over there.
あ、できた！乗れた！乗れた！
Ah, I did it! I mounted it! I mounted it!
お！
Oh!
敵！で、敵を倒しに行って、燃やした時にコントロールと右クリックで炎を吸っていくみたいな。
Enemies! Go defeat enemies, and when they burn, suck up the flames with Ctrl + right-click!
え、でもなんか敵がもうない…
Eh, but there are no more enemies...
あら。
Oh dear.
あ、お肉。
Ah, meat.
敵！敵どこ？どこ行った敵？
Enemies! Where are they? Where did they go?
あ、そう、敵がね、少ないんだよね、そこ。
Ah, right, there are few enemies there.
虫とかいないか。
Are there any bugs or anything?
ああ、もう時間ない。
Ah, there's no more time!
時間切れだ！
Time ran out!
ああ。
Ah...
雨夜だとあれなのかな？敵少ないのかな？
Is it because of the rainy night? Are there fewer enemies?
いや、居たんですけど、ちょっと…
No, there were some, but...
なんかね、敵があんまり居なくて。
Yeah, there weren't many enemies around.
ほうほうほう。
I see, I see.
倒せなかったんだよね。
I couldn't defeat any.
アルゲンでじゃあ敵捕まえて持っていった方がいいか。
Then is it better to catch enemies with an Argent and bring them over?
敵の湧きが厳しかったね。
Enemy spawns were tough.
チョ…
Dang...
ほなじゃあアルゲンを…
Well then, an Argent...
ちょっとお借りしようかな、アルゲンを。
I think I'll borrow an Argent for a bit.
うん。
Yeah.
There was a worm, but I can't find it now.
初めてだから難しいね
It's my first time, so it's difficult.
手合ね
Yeah.
えっ、あ、このアルゲン、サドルがないのか
Wait, ah, does this Argent not have a saddle?
ワイバーンでも掴める。ほなじゃあワイバーンで行ってみるか。
You can grab it with a Wyvern too. Well then, should I try going with a Wyvern?
俺の死体...
My corpse...
あ、イナ、後ろ。バック、バック。敵が。あ！
Ah, Ina, behind you! Back up, back up! An enemy! Ah!
うわっ！危ない！
Whoa! Watch out!
痛い痛い痛い。あ、そいつ乗れたらラッキーだな、でも。
Ow ow ow. Ah, if you could mount it, that'd be lucky, though.
あ、3分...
Ah, 3 minutes...
やばいやばい！やばい！
Oh no, oh no! Bad!
行けるか？
Can you do it?
逃げてください！
Please run away!
俺はいける。
I can manage.
ここでちょっとアタックしますので...
I'll attack a bit here, so...
え、これ雨？雨降ってる？え、そこ雨降ってる？
Wait, is this rain? Is it raining? Is it raining there?
火消えてる？
Is the fire out?
いや、火... 雨降ってるんですけど火が...
No, fire... It's raining, but the fire...
え、なんか火ついてるよね。
Wait, it's lit on fire, right?
ですよね。
Right?
いやー
Nooo!
間違えた。えっと、どうやって掴むんだ？
My bad. Um, how do you grab it?
熱い！
Hot!
もうちょい上の方かな。
Maybe a bit higher up.
熱い！えっ、テリ死ぬかも...
Hot! Wait, Terry might die...
いや、やばい、やばい、やばい。大丈夫？
Oh no, bad, bad, bad. Are you okay?
なんか火...
Like, the fire...
熱い！
Hot!
あー、敵をおびき寄せてはいるんだけど、無理か。
Ah, I'm luring the enemy, but is it impossible?
ですよねー
I guess so~
乗れない？
Can't you ride?
待って、乗れ...
Wait, ride...
今乗れないんです、クールダウンが... あっ、テリー！
I can't ride right now, the cooldown... Ah, Terry!
私も死ぬかもー！
I might die too!
あー、テリジノ！
Ah, Therizino!
テリー！
Terry!
テリジノ...
Therizino...
いや、死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ！
No, dying dying dying!
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
うわ、止まってんの、すっごい...
Whoa, it's standing still, that's crazy...
助けてー！
Help meee!
ここにいるけど...
It's here, but...
ここにいる、向かってはいるんだけど...
It's here, heading towards it, but...
うわっ、そっちか！
Whoa, that way?!
熱、熱、熱、熱、熱...
Hot hot hot hot hot...
え、雨降ってんのにそれ火消えてなくない？
Wait, it's raining, but isn't that fire not going out?
消えてないんだよー。死んだ。
It's not going out~ I died.
なんでだろう？
Why?
嫌でなんだってー
Whyyy, seriously!
これ今雨降ってるよね？
It's raining right now, right?
うん、雨降ってるだね。
Yeah, it's raining.
ワイバーン君、ワイバーン君、ワイバーン君...
Wyvern-kun, Wyvern-kun, Wyvern-kun...
オキオキ。ああ、やばいよー。
Oki-oki. Ah, this is bad~
私の荷物どこだろう？
I wonder where my items are?
That was fall damage probably, yeah.
ちょっと待って、乗りたいのに乗れないんですけど。ワイバーン！カモン！
Wait, I want to ride it, but I can't. Wyvern! C'mon!
ワイバーン！
Wyvern!
おい、なんか誰かの... 誰かのライトニングワイバーンがいる、ここに。
Hey, someone's... Someone's Lightning Wyvern is here.
トワ、トワ、トワ。
Towa, Towa, Towa.
あーん
Aah...
呼んでる？呼んでなくない？
Calling? Aren't you calling it?
あ、騎乗したあと燃えてるんだ。へぇー。
Ah, it burns after you dismount. Hehh.
あ、出た番に？ うん。
Ah, when it comes out? Yeah.
多分距離最短にしてないからめっちゃ遠くに行かないと来ないかも。
Maybe because follow distance isn't set to lowest, it won't come unless you go super far away.
あ、そういうこと？
Ah, is that it?
そういうこと。
That's it.
距離最短ってなかったっけ？
Wasn't there a lowest distance setting?
あったあった。
There was, there was.
居るには居るが。
It's there, though.
うわ、今ちょっとトラブルってて対応できないっすわ、キロです、すまん！
Whoa, I'm having trouble right now and can't respond, it's Kiro, sorry!
よいしょ。
There we go.
私の荷物...
My items...
いっか。
Whatever.
いやー、マップに出てるか。いや、イナごめんねー。
Man, is it on the map? Ah, Ina, I'm sorry.
いえいえいえ。
No no no.
大丈夫大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
あー、敵がいたら...
Ah, if there's enemies...
いけるか？
Can we do it?
おっ
Oh.
今こいつを着地させなきゃいけなくて、えっと...
Right now I have to make this guy land, and um...
着地...
Landing...
着地、一旦追従解除でも...
Landing, even if you stop following once...
お、来たかな？
Oh, did it come?
着地してー！
Land, please!
待ってよー。
Wait up~
うーーん。どこ、ここ？
Mmh. Where is this?
停止。
Stop.
ん？
Hm?
やばいやばいやばい。俺あとヒットポイント113。
Oh no oh no. I only have 113 HP left.
あー。
Aah.
あった。
Found it.
着地してくれないねー。
It won't land for me.
うん、着地してくんないんだよなー。
Yeah, it really doesn't land.
あれ？
Huh?
ちょっと待ってよ。一旦、トワ、ちょっとおいで。
Hold on. For a sec, Towa, come here a bit.
広いところに...
To a wide open place...
ちょいむずいなー。
This is kinda hard.
荷物どこ？
Where's my bag?
これで岩の上から乗れない？トワ様。
Can't I mount from on top of the rock like this? Towa-sama.
ジャンプで...
With a jump...
ちょっと待ってね。
Wait a second.
危ないかも。
Might be dangerous.
あ、イナの恐竜が...
Ah, Ina's dinosaur...
テリジノが...
Therizino is...
いやー、もう無理っすよ、無理そう。バサバサしてる。
Man, it's impossible, looks impossible. It's flapping around.
これ無理やな
That's impossible.
うん
Yeah.
て、イナ、テリジノのさ
Ina, for the Therizino...
はい
Yes?
サドル？
...saddle?
あ、取ってないですね
Ah, I didn't grab it.
オッケー、オッケー
Okay, okay.
オッケー
Okay.
お、行ける行ける。よいしょーい
Oh, I can make it, I can make it. Up we go!
お、ナイスー
Oh, nice!
はいはーい
Yes, yes~
ほいよ
Here you go.
あー、ありがとう！マジありがとう！すいませーん
Ah, thank you! Seriously, thank you! Sorry about that!
オッケー
Okay~
ありがてぇー
Much appreciated~
ライトニングワイバーン...
Lightning Wyvern...
よいしょ
Alright.
トワ様がいる
Towa-sama is here.
おーい
Hey!
戻りましたー
I'm back~
おかえりー
Welcome back~
今、て、テリさんのサドル、取れ、取れた？
Did you, uh, manage to get the Theri's saddle?
テリジノサドル取れた？イナ、テリサドル
Did you get the Therizino saddle? Ina, Theri saddle.
これこれ。あ、ありがとうございまーす
This one, this one. Ah, thank you so much!
そして、雨がやんじまったんだなー
And just like that, the rain has stopped...
だったら水辺だね
Then we should head to the water.
そうだね、水辺連れてくる方がいいかもね
Yeah, it might be better to lure it near the water.
あ、もう...
Ah, jeez...
焦らず行こう
Let's not rush it.
ワイバーンどこ行った？
Where did the wyvern go?
取れたわ
I got it.
何これ？
What's this?
よいしょ
Alright.
僕のワイバーンくん、どこ行ったんだろう
I wonder where my wyvern went.
いやー、パイロきついかなー
Man, Pyromane might be tough...
難しいねー
It is hard, isn't it?
ねー。近くに餌がいなかったのがねー
Yeah. Not having prey nearby made it hard.
そう、近くに餌いなかったんだよねー
Right, there was no prey nearby.
あ、でも、なんか音は雨か？
Ah, but wait, does that sound like rain?
雨じゃないかな？
Could it be rain?
なるほど
I see.
あ、雨降ってます！
Ah, it's raining!
あ、じゃあプテラ迎えに行きまーす
Ah, then I'll go pick up the Ptera~
こちらの樽に入れていただければ... ああ
If you could put it in this barrel... ah.
了解ー
Roger that~
よいしょ
Alright.
あれ、雨降ってきた？
Wait, did it start raining?
うん
Yeah.
あ、ラッキー
Ah, lucky!
ラッキー、雨降ってます
Lucky, it's raining.
ここのパイロ、敵いるん...
For this Pyromane, are there enemies...
いっぱいいる？
Are there a lot?
待って待って、どこだどこだどこだ？えーっと
Wait, wait, where is it, where is it? Umm...
待ってよ、イナが... イナどこどこ？
Wait, where is Ina... where is Ina?
たぶん下
Probably below.
ちょっと下？
A bit below?
俺のワイバーンくん...じゃねえわ、プテラくん
My Wyvern-kun... wait no, Ptera-kun.
あれ、ここじゃない？もしか...
Huh, isn't it here? Maybe...
パイロの、あの、テイムのマークが多分見える
You can probably see the Pyromane's taming mark.
あ、なんか0%、0%...
Ah, like 0%, 0%...
はい
Yes.
あー、そこか
Ah, over there.
こっちか
This way?
そうですね
That's right.
オッケーオッケー
Okay, okay.
ここです、ここ下。おっ
Right here, down below here. Oh.
あ、これか！
Ah, this one!
こいつとこいつ
This one and this one.
あれ、あれか？
Wait, is that it?
なんか、これが0%...
Like, this one is at 0%...
あ、オッケーオッケー、こいつか
Ah, okay okay, this one?
こいつをじゃあ... 今消えてるから...
Then for this one... since it's extinguished right now...
途中までこれば...
If we bring it halfway...
うわー
Whoa!
よいしょ
Alright.
これ体力どれぐらいなんだ？
How much health does this have?
あ、でも
Ah, but...
なんか0%になったやつはまた乗れるんですかね？
I wonder if you can mount the one that reached 0% again?
乗れるかな、これ？どう？
Can we ride it? What do you think?
あ、今ね、もうちょい、乗れる乗れる、今乗れる、今乗れる！
Ah, right now, just a bit more, you can ride it, you can ride it now, ride it now!
乗って！うん、行け
Ride it! Yeah, go!
で、敵を倒しに行く
And go defeat enemies.
で、火を、あれ、取る
And then, uh, absorb the fire.
えっ、痛たたたたたたた！
Eh, ouch-ouch-ouch-ouch!
あ、パイロは燃えないんじゃないかな
Ah, I don't think Pyromane gets burned.
うわー！落ちた！乗れたですけど落ちたー！あはは！
Whoa! I fell off! I got on, but I fell off! Ahaha!
落ちちゃった？
You fell off?
落ちちゃったー
I fell off~
あ、ちょっとこっちが体力ヤバいかも
Ah, my health might be in danger.
すいません
Sorry!
やばい、なんか、なんか、なんか、なんか、うわーこれ
Oh no, wait, wait, wait, whoa this...
これがライトニングワイバーンくんがやばいかも
The Lightning Wyvern might be in trouble.
これどう、あー、こうだこうだ、引っかかってた、引っかかってた
How do I... Ah, this way, this way. It was stuck, it was stuck.
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
大丈夫ー
I'm okay~
ライトニングワイバーンくんが死を... 死んでしまう
The Lightning Wyvern is going to... die.
今、ひっ... 今、連れてる
Right now, I'm... I'm luring one right now.
1匹釣ったよ
I lured one!
よいしょ
Alright.
ハードだぜ
This is hardcore.
ハード
Hardcore.
あー、難しい
Ah, it's difficult.
はー、難しいねー！
Haa, it's so tough, isn't it!
でも捕まえられたら、ハッピーだから
But once we tame it, we'll be happy!
ですねー
Indeed~
ハッピーのために頑張るんだー！
We gotta do our best for happiness!
ハッピーダッピー、うわーー！
Happy dappy, whoaa~!
おいしょ、はー、ワイバーンくんの体力がもう...
Whew, haa, Wyvern-kun's health is already...
こいつ...
This one...
行けるか？
Can you do it?
オッケー
Okay.
1匹、まだ引き連れたまんまのやつをあれにしたけど
I turned the one I was still luring into that, but...
おっ
Oh.
イナが来れるか？
Can Ina make it over?
パイロメイン95
Pyromane level 95.
あ、できますか？
Ah, can you do it?
あぶね！
Watch out!
うーーん
Uuun...
ちょっと押せません。回復待って、ちょっと...
I can't push yet. Wait for my recovery a bit...
炎吸収...
Absorbing flames...
敵を燃やして、それ吸うといいらしいよ。
Apparently, you burn enemies and absorb that.
よいしょ...
Up we go...
ベントからゲットして...
Get it from the vent...
大丈夫ですか、トワ様？
Are you alright, Towa-sama?
大丈夫。
I'm fine.
行けそう？敵連れてった方がいい？なんか雑魚。
Think you can do it? Should I bring some mobs over?
ちょっとこいつで行くか...
Guess I'll go with this one...
おっ。
Oh.
え、これ死んだ？
Huh, did this one die?
うわ、死んだわ！うわぁー！
Whoa, it died! Uwaaah!
いや、ちょっと待って...
No, wait a sec...
死んじゃった？
Did it die?
うん...ちょっと敵が多すぎたな...
Yeah... There were a bit too many enemies...
周りの？
Around it?
うん、周りの敵が多すぎて死んだな...
Yeah, there were too many enemies around it and it died...
この辺にもう1匹いるわ。
There's another one around here.
ははー、ふんふん。
I see, okay.
あ、よいしょ。
Ah, up we go.
乗れそうなら乗るか。
If we can mount it, should we?
うーん...
Hmm...
いける？
Can you?
25だ、これちょっとガチ弱いな。
It's 25, this one is seriously weak.
あ、でも乗れそうなら...
Ah, but if you can mount it...
あーめっちゃ弱い。弱いか...
Ah, super weak. Too weak, huh...
ちょっと強めなやつ？
A bit stronger one?
うん。
Yeah.
ま、最低90は欲しいかなと思うけどな。
Well, I think we want at least level 90 though.
もう1匹いる。
There's another one.
結構湧きは早いかな。
The respawn seems pretty fast.
なんか湧きはいいのにね。
The spawns are good, at least.
あ、85！
Ah, 85!
よわー！
So weak!
あらららら...
Oh dear, dear...
待って...
Wait...
ワイバーン強くしたから、もしかして強い？
I buffed the wyvern, so maybe it's too strong?
やべ、トワの体力がない！バカバカバカ！
Shoot, Towa's out of health! Idiot, idiot, idiot!
強そうなのがいるかな...
Is there a strong-looking one...
でもこっち行ったら虫がちょっといるか...
Though if we go this way, there are bugs around...
うーん...
Hmm...
ちょっとワイバーン強すぎて、これ無理だこれ。
The wyvern is just too strong, this is impossible.
あ、もう1匹そこいるよ。
Ah, there's another one right there.
燃え！
Burn!
こいつ、こいつこいつ！
This one, this one, this one!
でも炎消えてない？
But hasn't the fire gone out?
あ、まだライディングのクールダウンが...
Ah, the riding cooldown is still...
ああ、クールダウン中かな、今。
Ah, is it on cooldown right now?
はい。もうすぐかな？
Yes. Maybe soon?
あ、消えてる消えてる！
Ah, it's out, it's out!
乗れない、こいつ？
Can't ride this one?
パイロ？
The Pyro?
熱っ！
Hot!
3秒らしいからな...
Apparently it's only 3 seconds...
結構短いんだ。
That's pretty short.
あ、でもまだあいつ火ついてるかも。
Ah, but that one might still be on fire.
火ついてるね。熱っ、熱っ...
It's on fire. Hot, hot...
あ、雨が...
Ah, the rain...
あー！雨降っちゃった！
Ah, it started raining!
あ、熱い！熱い！
Ah, hot! It burns!
雨降った...終わった...
It rained... It's over...
雨止んじゃったか...
Did the rain stop already...
うわー、本当だ、雨止んじゃったー！
Whoa, you're right, the rain stopped!
もう1回降ってくれーー！
Rain one more time, pleaseee!
頼むー！頼むー！
Please! Please!
あ、そっか、タコすん来れるか、お前。
Ah, right, Takosun, can you come here?
お、来た来た来た。
Oh, here it comes, here it comes.
やっぱ海辺の方がいいかなー？
I wonder if the beachside would be better?
海辺の方がいいかもね。
The beach might be better.
ねー。
Right.
海辺に...
To the beach...
そうそう。
Yeah, yeah.
ちょうど雨降ってたから、そこでやってたけど...
It was just raining before, so we were doing it there, but...
いや、惜しい！
Man, so close!
惜しいねー！
So close!
惜しいなー！惜しいねー！
So close! So close!
初挑戦だから結構大変だね。
Since it's our first try, it's pretty tough.
ねー。
Yeah.
よしよし。
Alright, alright.
ふぅー。
Phew.
なんか服ねえかなー。
I wonder if there are any clothes.
よいしょ。取るか。
Up we go. Shall we grab it?
あ、トワ...
Ah, Towa...
ふぅー。
Phew.
石...
Stone...
よいしょ。
Up we go.
ししろん待ってるで、ポータルのとこに。
Shishiron is waiting at the portal.
お疲れ様ですー。
Good work~
あ、マジ？
Oh, really?
お疲れ様ー。
Good work~
ビビ、個人ミッション終わりましたー。
Bibi finished her individual mission~
イェーイ！ヤバイ！
Yay! Awesome!
はい。で、これって終わったら何をもらえるんですか？
Yes. And what do you get once this is finished?
個人ミッションはー、えっと、何だったっけかな？
Individual missions... um, what was it again?
拳で収穫。
Harvest with fists.
個人ミッションの報酬が...何をやった？
The individual mission reward... What did you do?
あ、えっと、個人ミッションで、えっと、クレートまで全部達成して、もうミッション全部成功しました。
Ah, um, in the individual mission, we reached all the crates and succeeded all the missions.
おめでー！えっと、今やったミッションは何をやったんだい？
Congrats! Um, which mission did you do just now?
今やったミッション？えっと、個人で、個人ミッション...
The mission I just did? Um, individual... individual mission...
クレートだけ？
Just crates?
クレートをやりました。すべて達成になりました。
I did crates. All completed.
あ、今さっきやったやつ、今さっきやったやつ。
Ah, the one you just did right now, the one right now.
今、今さっき...
Just now...
え、今さっきやったのは... ん？何だ？クレー...
Um, what we just did was... Huh? What was it? Crate...
何？クレートだけ？
What? Just a crate?
あ、え、クレートとあと交配、交配しました、交配。
Ah, um, a crate and also mating, we bred them, mating.
なら、集会場のあれからオヴィラプトルとテリジノサウルスが貰えるはず。
Then you should be able to get an Oviraptor and Therizinosaurus from the meeting place.
オヴィラプトルとテリジノサウルス。はい。
Oviraptor and Therizinosaurus. Got it.
あ、そう。集会場のところから貰えるはず。そこは自分で取りに行かなきゃいけない。
Yeah, you should get them from the meeting place. You have to go pick them up yourself, though.
あ、はい、分かりました。ありがとうございます。
Ah, okay, I understand. Thank you very much!
はーいよ。
Sure thing.
じゃ死んだとこのあれ取ってくるわ。
I'll go get my stuff from where I died, then.
はーいよ。
Alright.
えーっと...
Umm...
ワンチャンここで、雨もう一回降んないかな待ってみる？
Is there a chance it'll rain again if we wait here?
雨待ち？
Waiting for rain?
来るでしょ。さっき連続で来てたもん。
It should come. It was raining back-to-back earlier.
3回目は無いやろって！
There's no way it's happening a third time!
絶対海行った方が早いて！
It's definitely faster to just go to the ocean!
海のが早そう。
The sea does seem faster.
絶対海のが早いて。
The ocean is definitely faster!
じゃ海行く？雨乞いソング...
Shall we go to the sea then? Rain dance song...
雨乞いソングじゃなくて... 雨乞いソングで。
Instead of a rain dance... with a rain dance song.
よいしょ。
All right.
えーっと...
Let's see...
あ、でもパイロ、あ、そうか。パイロ... その辺で私の死体があるんだよな。
Ah, but the Pyromane... Oh, right. Around there is where my corpse is.
雨よ、雨よ～ 降れ降れ～
Rain, oh rain, fall, fall~
集会場来ちゃった。
I ended up coming to the meeting place.
いや、移動してるからね、でも。
Well, but it's moving around.
こっちだ。
Over here.
よーし。
Alright.
私の死体が...
My corpse...
これ何になってんだ、これ？
What is this set to?
この辺に...
Around here...
凄い視界がドクドクしてるのは何でだ？
Why is my vision throbbing so much?
どこだ？死ぬのか？
Where is it? Am I dying?
水辺って、水辺っていうか、どこら辺だ？
By the water... where is that exactly?
海です、海。
It's the ocean, the ocean.
上？下？マップで。
Top? Bottom? On the map.
えーっと、上かな？
Umm, near the top, I think?
イナが向かってる？
Is Ina heading there?
イナについて行こうかな、じゃあ。
I'll just follow Ina, then.
どこだ？
Where is it?
多分こっ...ち...じゃないかな？
Maybe it's... this... way?
あ、こっち側ね。
Ah, on this side.
今なんかマップでフブキ先輩のマーク...
Just now on the map, Fubuki-senpai's marker...
あ、自分もう拠点に戻ってる。
Ah, I'm already back at base.
あ、これ、ごめんごめん、これ拠点に戻ってるから。
Ah, sorry, sorry, this one is heading back to base.
あ、でもここにパイロ... 1匹見つかりました。
Ah, but I found... one Pyromane here.
それをね、海にまで連れて行かなきゃいけないんだよね。
You need to lure it all the way to the ocean.
水を...火を消すやつ。
To... put out the fire in water.
はい。
Yes.
え、ここで待ちます？それとも...
Um, should I wait here? Or...
ここで一旦待ちかな？
Maybe wait here for now?
はい。
Okay.
何だこれ？
What's this?
近く、安全な場所に待ちます。
I'll wait in a safe place nearby.
ここ暑い。暑い。
It's hot here. So hot.
あ、パイロいるね。
Ah, there's a Pyromane.
そう、そのパイロを海辺に連れて行かなきゃいけない。
Right, we have to lure that Pyromane to the beach.
目がおかしいのか？
Is something wrong with my eyes?
それね、何かね熱中症っぽいんだよね。
That looks like heatstroke.
そういうこと？
Is that what it is?
そう、自分もちょっとボヤボヤすぎて、画面気持ち悪っと思って戻ってきたんだけど。
Yeah, it got way too blurry for me too and made me dizzy, so I headed back.
あー、これ水に入ったら大丈夫なのかな？
Ah, will it be okay if I go into the water?
そうそう、水にね、しばらく浸かってたらいいんだって。
Yeah, they say it's fine if you soak in water for a bit.
オッケー。
Okay.
うん。
Mm.
火山はギリース...いや、パイロは別にギリースーツ無くても良いの...ギリースーツ要るのかな？
Volcano needs Ghillie... Wait, Pyromanes don't need a Ghillie suit... or do they?
荷物ねぇかも。
My items might be gone.
くー。
Guh...
死んだところにないかい？
Isn't it where you died?
あー、ない。あのね、空中で死んだんだよね。
Ah, nope. See, I died mid-air.
あ、多分その下にいないかな？空中で死んだら、その真下に落ちると思うんだけど。
Ah, maybe it's below? If you die in mid-air, it should drop straight down.
真下かなー。
Straight down, huh...
うん。
Yeah.
カバンらしいものが...
Anything looking like a bag...
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
何一つ無いかも。
There might not be a single thing.
熱中症回避してください。
Please avoid heatstroke.
ワンチャン岩の間だな。
Maybe between the rocks.
ティラノの...
Tyrano...
お、イナ気をつけてね。
Oh, Ina, be careful.
はい。水の中にしばらくいたら...
Yes. If I stay in the water for a bit...
えーっと。
Let's see.
オッケー。
Okay.
えーっと。
Umm.
よ。
Hup.
ちょっと一旦火山、火山の近く行くか。えーっと。
Let's head near the volcano for a moment. Umm.
なんだこいつマジで。しかも身体マジで重いし。
Seriously, what is up with this guy? And my body feels so heavy.
マジで重い。
Seriously heavy.
イーナのところに行くかな。イーナがどこだ？
I guess I'll go to Ina. Where is Ina?
海のとこ？イナ。
By the sea? Ina.
はい、海です。
Yes, at the sea.
オッケー。
Okay.
え、なんかめっちゃ...
Wait, there's so many...
めっちゃ食っとる。
It's totally eating it.
あ。
Ah.
多分こっちかな。
Probably this way.
なんか映んないんだよな。何で？
It's not showing up. Why?
いや、無いなー。
No, it's not here.
何で映んないんだろう。
I wonder why it's not showing up.
うん。
Yeah.
無い気がする。
I don't think it's here.
ここなんだよな。
It should be right here...
こっちにいるのかな？イナが。
Is Ina over this way?
えっど、今、17.1と...
Umm, right now I'm at 17.1 and...
64.7です。
64.7.
あ、ありがとお、あ、じゃあそこだ。
Ah, thank you! Ah, then it's over there.
ヘビです
It's a snake.
いや、ないわ。ま、いいや。
Nah, it's not here. Well, whatever.
どうせしょぼいもんしかねえ。
It'd probably only be lame stuff anyway.
あ、あ、ここか。なんか、ん？あれは誰かが乗っておられるライトニングワイバーン？
Ah, here? Wait, huh? Is someone riding that lightning wyvern?
あ、トワ様です。
Ah, it's Towa-sama.
あ、これトワか。
Ah, is this Towa?
トワ、それ罠行けそう？
Towa, can you lure it into that trap?
ちょっとやってみる、かな。
I'll give it a try, maybe.
うん。
Yeah.
なんレベルだ、これ？
What level is this?
それをね、この水の中に連れてきてほしいんだよね。
I want you to lure it into this water, you see.
うん。
Yeah.
今そっち行きまーす。
Heading over there now!
いた！
There it is!
あれ、どこ行った？
Huh, where did it go?
あ、戻りました。たぶん。
Ah, it went back. Probably.
やべ
Shoot.
こっちよ。ええと、どっちだ。
This way. Um, which way?
イナちゃん、連れてこれる？
Ina-chan, can you lure it over?
ワイバーンだとちょっと...
With a wyvern, it's a bit...
えーっと、どこ...
Um, where...
あ、連れて...こいつか？こいつかな？
Ah, lure... This one? Is it this one?
小回りが利かねえな
It doesn't turn sharply...
こいつかも、こいつかも。
Might be this one, might be this one.
あ、それだ、それだ！
Ah, that's it, that's it!
ああ、はいはいはい。
Ah, okay, okay, okay.
行ってー
Go for it~
あ、これはもしや木に引っ掛かっちゃってる？
Ah, is it stuck in the tree by any chance?
あ、出ました、出ました。
Ah, it got out, it got out.
行けそう行けそう。あ、来た来た来た。
Looking good, looking good. Ah, here it comes, here it comes!
テレポーターはどこだー？
Where's the teleporter?!
あ、こっちに。
Ah, over here.
いったん休憩。
Taking a break for a second.
あ、入った入った入った！入ったよ！
Ah, it's in, it's in, it's in! It went in!
これでどうだ？
How about now?
あ、出た。
Ah, it came out.
あ、行けそう。
Ah, looks doable.
どうだ、どうだ？
How is it, how is it?
うわっ！
Whoa!
はー
Haa...
無理だ。なんか、ちょっと待って、ここあれ...
Impossible. Wait a sec, here is...
ど、どうにか、なった、今。
I somehow managed it just now.
カマキリが...
The mantis is...
あ、飛んでる。飛んでる戻って。
Ah, Tonderu! Tonderu, come back!
なんか飛んでったで。
It flew off somewhere.
テレポーター迷子、あ、でっか。
Teleporter lost... ah, it's huge.
これでどうだどうだ。
How about this, how about this?
な、乗れるか？
C-can I ride?
なんか私狙ってますけど！
Wait, it's targeting me though!
乗れるかな？
Can you ride it?
乗れたらいいけど、ここに死ぬのは嫌だ！
It'd be great if you can, but I don't wanna die here!
こっちこっちこっちこっち...
This way, this way, this way...
迷子です。どこだったっけ、テレポーター。
I'm lost. Where was the teleporter again?
飛んでる...
Tonderu...
あ、カマキリが...
Ah, the mantis...
この辺だった気がするんだよな。
I feel like it was around here.
カマキリナイス！
Mantis nice!
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
オッケーオッケー、オッケーオッケー。
Okay okay, okay okay.
岸まで。
To the shore.
上から見るか。
Should I look from above?
結構高い位置だったよね。
It was in a pretty high spot, wasn't it?
よいしょ。あーもう引っ掛かってる引っ掛かってる、ふー。
Heave-ho. Ah, it's stuck, it's stuck. Phew.
やばいかも。おっと...
Might be bad. Oops...
うわあ！ごめん死。
Whoaa! Sorry, I died.
パイロメインになんか引っ掛かってる。
It's stuck on a Pyromane or something.
あ、出れた出れた。
Ah, got out, got out.
乗る？乗る？
Ride? Ride?
あ、266...
Ah, 266...
やっちゃったよ、これ。
I messed up here.
乗る？
Riding?
炎消えてる、まだ。あ、まだ生きてる。
Fire is out, still... Ah, still alive.
待って、カマキリが近くにいるのか。
Wait, is a mantis nearby?
うおおお！
Whoaa!
これ乗れるか乗れないか...
Can I ride this or not...
2662だった。
It was 2662.
これを...
This...
今無理か、イナ。
Impossible right now, Ina?
あー、ワイバーン...
Ah, wyvern...
また、また火が。
Fire again...
あーオッケーオッケー、火火火火。こっちね。
Ah, okay okay, fire fire fire fire. This way.
この辺だな。
Around here.
こっちに来てほしい。
I want it to come here.
どこ行った？
Where'd it go?
やばい。てか死ぬ、ワイバーン死ぬ。
Shoot. Wait, it's gonna die, wyvern's gonna die.
無理だこれ、カマキリが多すぎて。
Impossible, there're too many mantises.
ねえ、カマキリがえぐいよね。
Yeah, the mantises are insane, right?
ここ数えぐーい！
There's an insane amount of them here!
ちょっとカマキリの処理してもらった方がいいかな？
Maybe we should get someone to deal with the mantises?
オッケー、ちょ...
Okay, wa...
これ乗れるのかな？
Can I ride this?
あ、待って、これお前こっち来いこっち来いこっち来い。
Ah, wait, hey you, come here come here come here.
みんな、どこにいる？
Where is everyone?
あーやば、これ...
Ah, shoot, this...
やるなら今の...
If we do it, now's the...
今乗れる？
Can you ride it now?
いや騎乗ができないの、そもそも。うーん。
No, riding isn't even an option to begin with. Mmm.
乗れなかったー。
Couldn't ride it~
まだでしたかね。
Was it still too early?
あー、もう連れてかれちゃった。
Ah, it got dragged away already.
まだだったのかな。ごめん、自分のプテラ呼べるかな、イナ？
Was it still too early? Sorry, can Ina call her own Ptera?
あ、はい。
Ah, yes.
騎乗がなかったなあ。50%削れてなかったっぽい、HP。
There was no ride prompt. Seems like its HP wasn't down 50%.
ああ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
あ、そうそうそう。だからもうちょっと攻撃必要だったかも。
Ah yeah, yeah, yeah. So maybe we needed to attack it a bit more.
およー、ほほー。
Oyo~ Hoho~
この辺か？
Around here?
ちょっといったんワイバーンちょっと置いてくるわ。
I'll go park the wyvern for a bit.
はい、いいよー。
Okay, sure~
いいよ。
Go ahead.
体力は...
Health is...
危ない危ない危ない...はまってるはまってるはまってる...
Watch out watch out watch out... It's stuck it's stuck it's stuck...
とりあえず一旦肉を...
For now, let's just get some meat...
キモすぎるキモすぎる、もうここキモすぎる！
Too gross, too gross, this place is way too gross!
火山行ったのみか？
Did you go to the volcano?
先輩がお亡くなりになってるやつある。
There's a senpai who died here.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
ここどんだけ大変なんだよー！
How difficult is this place?!
おかしくなっちまうよ、バカタレーイ！
I'm gonna lose my mind, you idiots!
入れるか？
Can I enter?
入れた。
I made it in.
いや、まだ...
No, not yet...
ちょっと肉もらいまーす。
Getting some meat~
なんかレベル見るやつなかったっけ？
Wasn't there something to check levels?
レベルじゃない、体力見るやつなかったっけ？
Not level, wasn't there something to check health?
望遠鏡とかかな。
Maybe a spyglass or something?
望遠鏡？でもなんか敵にマウスカーソル当てるとヒットポイントはなんか結構見えたりはする...
Spyglass? But when you hover your cursor over an enemy, the HP is pretty visible...
だけどね
But you know...
本当？
Really?
ただなんか、誰かがやってる時じゃないと見る余裕ないかも。
Though, you might not have time to check unless someone else is doing it.
ま、そうだよね。
Well, that's true.
スパイグラス？
Spyglass?
そう、私はそれで見てやってたけど。
Yeah, that's how I did it, but...
あの、望遠鏡でなんかあれらしいよ。
Apparently, you use the telescope to do it.
ないな。スパイグラス検索してもないや。
It's not here. Even if I search "Spyglass", nothing comes up.
エングラムに。
In the engrams.
なんかスパイグラスっていうやつらしい。
Apparently it's called a Spyglass.
けど、スパイグラスがそもそもエングラムにないから何なんだ？
But if Spyglass isn't even in the engrams, what is it?
エングラム...
Engrams...
この音... 濡れ箸貰おうかな。
That sound... Maybe I should get some wet chopsticks.
スパイグラ... えっとね製作、エングラムで幾つだったかな望遠鏡。
Spyglas... let's see, crafting... what level was the telescope in engrams?
スパイ... ス... S-P-Y... S-P-Y...
Spy... s... S-P-Y... S-P-Y...
あ、これかスパイグラス！
Ah, here it is, Spyglass!
あ、これだ！
Ah, this is it!
スパイグラスっていうやつじゃないとダメなのかな？
Does it have to be the Spyglass?
スパイグラスってやつが遠くからでもあれなの、HPとかが見えるらしい。
Apparently the Spyglass lets you see their HP and stuff even from afar.
あ、遠くからでもね。
Ah, even from afar, I see.
あ、そうそうそうそう。
Yeah, exactly, exactly.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
みんなテレポーターまで来れるかい？
Can everyone make it to the teleporter?
あ、じゃあ戻ります？
Ah, should we head back then?
うん、戻ってきてほしい。
Yeah, I'd like you to come back.
はーい。
Okay.
テレポーターってどこだっけ？
Where was the teleporter again?
えっと、テレポーターはね、えっと...
Um, the teleporter is, let's see...
死んだ場所行こうかなー。
Maybe I'll go to where I died.
26の62だね。
It's 26, 62.
26の...
26...
あれ？ 俺のワイバーンどこ行った？
Huh? Where did my wyvern go?
62。
62.
よいしょ。
All right.
あ、スパイグラスじゃないとダメなんだね。
Ah, so it has to be the Spyglass.
え？ え？ え？
Huh? What? What?
エリートバーン...
Elite Wyvern...
え？ え？
Eh? Eh?
なんだなんだなんだ。
What is it, what is it?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
なん、なんかこ、殺されちゃった...
I... I got killed somehow...
は、ハワック... ハワック...
Ha- Havok... Havok...
うわー！
Uwaah!
リスポーンまで、しかもすぐリスポーンできないし...
Until respawn... and I can't even respawn right away...
うわっ、うわー！
Uwah, uwaah!
あと20秒まで戻れない！
I can't go back for another 20 seconds!
す、スポー... できない！
Re- spaw... I can't!
ええー！？ えー！
Eeeee?! No way!
早く戻らせてくれー！
Let me go back already!
えっとー...
Let's see...
水... 水を汲む...
Water... getting water...
いけた、やっと帰れる！
Done, I can finally go back!
いけた！ よかったー！
It worked! Thank goodness!
え、どこここ？
Huh, where is this?
え？ 待ってなんか全然知らないとこ来ちゃった。
Eh? Wait, I came somewhere completely unfamiliar.
あ、ござるさんのとこに来ちゃった。
Ah, I ended up at Gozaru-san's place.
こっちだ。
It's this way.
イナい... え、火山の、まだみんないる？
Ina is... wait, is everyone still at the volcano?
イナがまだいるかな？
Ina might still be there?
あ、まだテレポートに...
Ah, still at the teleport...
オッケー、じゃあ行きます。
Okay, I'm heading over then.
行ってきまーす、多分。
On my way, probably.
火山だよね？
It's the volcano, right?
火山だね。
The volcano, yeah.
オッケー。
Okay.
いてー、いてー。
Ouch, ouch.
えっと、こっちだ。こっちに...
Um, this way. Over here...
よいしょ。
Up we go.
ふぅ。
Phew.
痛かった、痛かったー。
That hurt, that hurt!
よいしょ。
Up we go.
交代要員？
よいしょ。
Up we go.
えっと、こっち行ってこっ... おおー。
Um, go this way, and th- woah.
で、海の方か。
And then toward the ocean?
あ、そうそうそうそう。
Ah, yeah yeah yeah.
これは誰？ あっち側の人... ああ、うわあああああ！
Who is this? The person over there... Ah, uwaaaah!
おー、はい。
Oh, right.
来てしまった。
I arrived.
ん？ みんな、どっちの海の方だ？ こっちか。
Hm? Which ocean is everyone at? This way?
よいしょ。火山に行きまーす。
All right. Heading to the volcano!
はい。
Okay.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
付いて行こう。
Let me follow you.
あ、待って、イナ、イナ待ちなんだけどね今。
Ah wait, they're actually waiting on Ina right now.
オッケー。
Okay.
どこです... えっと...
Where is it... um...
えっと...
Um...
26の67。
26, 67.
67...
ここから...
From here...
あ、26...
Ah, 26...
雪山側まだ貰ってない。後で取る。
I haven't gotten the snowy mountain side yet. I'll get it later.
雪山の方かな？
Toward the snowy mountains?
26の60...
26, 60...
67... 62。
67... 62.
うん。
Yeah.
ビビの所。
Where Bibi is.
あ、そうそう、ビビの所かな。
Ah right, where Bibi is.
なんで自分表示されないんだろう。
Wonder why my marker isn't showing up.
トライブなのに
Even though we're in the same tribe...
なんでだ？
Why is that?
いるよな
They should be there, right?
あ、ちょっとスタミナ
Ah, my stamina is a bit...
なんでだ？
Why is it?
でもあと30分で終わる。早っ！
Only 30 minutes left though. That was fast!
ハンズアップ！
Hands up!
うわー
Whoa~
行けるかな？来れるかな？
Can you make it? Can you come over?
あ、いつか、着きました。ふぅー
Ah, finally, I made it. Phew.
あ、良かった良かった良かった。ああ、そっち？
Ah, great, great, great. Oh, over there?
行き過ぎました。
I went too far.
通り過ぎてたね。
You flew right past.
見えてた。
I saw you.
アキ？
Aki?
ありがとー。で…
Thank you. And...
えっと、追従をキャンセルかな？
Um, cancel follow, right?
止まれっていうのが多分…
Tell it to stop, probably...
あー、うん。
Ah, yeah.
止まれ
Stop.
あるかな？
Is it there?
お、まだあっち…
Oh, it's still over...
あ、オッケーオッケーオッケー。
Ah, okay, okay, okay.
ありがとー！
Thank you!
おし、で、こっちか。
Alright, so this way?
はい。
Yes.
いいよー
Ready.
Alright.
で、海側の方にまた行きましょう。
And let's head toward the sea side again.
はいよ
Sure thing.
よいっしょー
Yo-ho~
さあ、じゃあちょっとアイテムを回収しなければ…
Now, let's see, we need to retrieve the items...
えっと…
Let's see...
よいしょ、ういー
Alright, whew~
なんか持って来たら良かったかな…
I wonder if I should've brought something...
ん？
Hmm?
恐竜
A dinosaur.
あー確かに、ちょっと今戦える恐竜がいないかも。
Ah true, we might not have any combat dinos right now.
私、たぶんユティ持って…ありますけど。
I think I... brought a Yuty, though.
じゃあ行けるか。
Then we'll be fine.
なら行けるかも。
We might be fine then.
うわ、いるな海辺に。
Whoa, there are some by the sea.
僕テリジノが帰ってこないから何もできないんだよね
I can't do anything since my Therizino hasn't returned yet.
おや、テリジノはどこに？
Oh, where is the Therizino?
あの、さっきの洞窟探検のスタックで…
Um, it got stuck during that cave exploration earlier...
死んで消えて補填待ち…
and died, so I'm waiting for compensation...
なるほどね
I see.
そう、プテラもだからメインで使ってたやつ補填待ちなんですよね。
Yeah, so the Ptera I mained is also waiting for compensation.
あーなるほどなるほど。あ、これ、これか？もしかして自分の…
Ah, I see, I see. Ah, is this it? Maybe my...
あ、でもパイロいますよ、あそこ。
Ah, but there's a Pyro over there.
あ、パイロいる。あいつさっきやろうとしたんだよね、確か。
Ah, a Pyro is there. That's the one we tried to fight earlier, right?
今、あいつ、再…再できんのかな？
Can we retry that one now, I wonder?
これじゃないな。
Not this one.
あ、これか。これでいいんだ。
Ah, is it this? This should be fine.
よいしょ
Yo-ho.
えっと…
Let's see...
これで…
With this...
あれ？自分のプテ…あっちに行っちゃったのか。
Huh? My Ptera... did it go over there?
よいしょ
Up we go.
オッケー。これでじゃあ行けるかな？
Okay. Can we go with this?
じゃあイナが引っ張ってきてもらって…戦ってもらった方がいいのかな？
Should Ina lure it and... have you guys fight it?
怖い
Scary!
私ができるかな？
Can I do it?
あ、でも自分もこれ、えっと何持ってきてんだっけ今？
Ah, but wait, what did I bring with me right now?
一応私生身で乗れる準備しとくよ。
I'll prepare to ride bareback just in case.
あ、オッケーオッケー。乗れる準備するなら、じゃあえっと…
Ah, okay okay. If you're getting ready to ride, then um...
じゃあテリで私が…
Then with the Theri, I'll...
そうだね、ちょっと攻撃して…
Yeah, attack it a bit...
テリじゃなくて、あのユティか。
Not Theri, um, the Yuty.
あ、ユティかユティ。そうだね、ユティで。
Ah, Yuty, right! Yeah, with Yuty.
はい、ちょっと…
Yeah, hold on...
えーっと、プテラはどうするのがいいかな？
Um, what should I do with the Ptera?
プテラは置いといてもらえたら。
If you can just leave the Ptera parked.
はい。
Okay.
うん。
Yeah.
コマンドは何…ここで大丈夫かな？
What command is... is here okay?
ここで大丈夫かな？止まって…
Is here okay? Stop...
ホイッスルパッシブ？
Whistle Passive?
止まってもらったらオッケーだと思う、多分。
I think just telling it to stop is fine, probably.
じゃあ…
Then...
おっと
Oops.
うわっ / 来ちゃったー！
Whoa! / It came over!
ここやばい
It's dangerous here!
パイロ…パイロの、もしかして卵？あれ。
Pyro... Is that a Pyro egg, maybe? Over there.
ここで止まっ…
Stop here...
いや、でもここ敵が…いやー！
No, but there are enemies here... Nooo!
どこか岩場の上に置いといてもらえたらいいよ。この辺りとか。
You can just leave it on top of some rocks. Around here or so.
そうだねー。
Right.
うん。
Yeah.
あっち高いかも。
That side might be high.
あ、消えちゃった。
Ah, it disappeared.
消えちゃった？
Disappeared?
卵消えちゃった。
The egg disappeared.
オッケー、ここで…
Okay, here...
うん、なんだ、なんだったんだろうな、何の卵？
Yeah. What was that? What egg was it?
えっと、ユティ…
Um, Yuty...
おーい
Oof...
よいしょ
Yo-ho.
はい、ユティ。行くぞ。
Alright, Yuty. Let's go.
ユティいるか？ユティを…ユティでちょっと殴ってくれ、こいつを。
Is the Yuty out? With the Yuty... punch this guy a bit with the Yuty.
飛んでる、ちょっと！戻って！飛んでる！
It's flying! Wait! Come back! It's flying!
ほっ
Hup.
着地させたらオッケーかな？
If I make it land, will that be okay?
行くっすかね
Shall we go?
えっと、とま... とま... ま...
Um, st- ... st- ... st- ...
止まっ、止まるやつが
The one that st-... stops.
オッケーオッケー、それでオッケーかな？うん。
Okay, okay, is that good? Yeah.
大丈夫ですか？オッケー
Are you all right? Okay.
うん
Yeah.
じゃあゆっくりに...
Then, slowly...
乗っ... え？
Mount... huh?
やばい、カマキリが！
Oh no, a mantis!
はい！
Yes!
行きます！
Here I go!
よいしょ、はいよー
All right, okay!
おら！
Take that!
いけるか？
Can you get it?
お、今乗れるかも
Oh, maybe you can ride it now.
あ、乗れるかも！乗れる！
Ah, maybe you can ride it! You can!
乗れるかも、乗る！
Maybe I can ride it, getting on!
あ、遠い
Ah, too far.
あ
Ah.
乗れる？
Can you ride?
あ、まだだ。乗れない
Ah, not yet. Can't ride.
あ、もう一回
Ah, one more time.
消えてる
It's gone.
あ、今！今今今今！
Ah, now! Now, now, now, now!
なんかカマキリ、カマキリ...
Wait, mantis, mantis...
今、今！ああー！カマキリ！
Now, now! Aaah! Mantis!
今乗れないね、出ないね
Can't ride right now, the prompt isn't showing.
たま、止まってる時...
Wh- When it's stopped...
なんで降りたんだ、今
Why did I get off just now?
乗れた！乗れた乗れた乗れた！
I got on! I got on, got on, got on!
あ、ちょ、ま、このマンティス、マンティス！
Ah, wait, this mantis, mantis!
イナ、イナ、退いてほしい
Ina, Ina, please back up!
あ、はい
Ah, okay.
あ、爆発した！
Ah, it exploded!
あーー！
Aaaah!
くっ
Shoot!
いやー、あ
Man... ah.
おら！カマキリが...
Ora! The mantis...
あー、死んだ！
Ah, it died!
あーーー！
Aaaah!
カマキリが強すぎた！
The mantis was too strong!
だからだー！カマキリが強かった！
That's why! The mantis was strong!
水に触れてたのかな、今。落ちちゃったのかな？
Was it touching water just now? Did you fall off?
おらーー！
Take that!
水に...
In the water...
カマキリ
Mantis.
水の中って燃える？敵
Do enemies burn in water?
燃えない
They don't.
ちょっと、乗れたら陸上がらないといけないから
If I mount it, we have to head onto land, so...
そうだね、そうだね、陸でやったほうがいいね。うん、乗るときは。
Right, right, better to do it on land. Yeah, when mounting.
よいしょ
Yoisho.
くーー
Ughhh...
カマカマ2匹いたからな
There were two mantises, after all.
ねえ、急に飛んできたからね。ちょっと白、迎えに行ってくるわ。
Yeah, they flew over so suddenly. I'll go pick up White.
はいよー
Sure thing.
よいしょー
Yoisho!
くー
Kuuu...
ここで
Here...
まだもうちょっと時間あるからきっと行けるはず
There's still a bit of time, so we should be able to make it.
あ、じゃあもう生身であれ行くわ。あの、火山。
Ah, then I'll just go on foot to that... volcano.
うん、生身で一旦火山来て大丈夫。
Yeah, you can just come to the volcano on foot for now.
プテラだけ連れてくわ
I'll just bring Ptera with me.
よいしょ
Yoisho.
よいしょ。ふー。えーっと、こっちだっけ？
Yoisho. Whew. Um, was it this way?
おっしょっしょ
Osshossho.
よいしょ、たたた
Yoisho, ta-ta-ta.
うん
Yeah.
ちゃっちゃっちゃーん
Ta-da!
ねえ、それで言ったよー！
See, I told you!
やっぱ言いましたよなー
You really did say so...
ちょっと、あ、待って、曲がり角、曲がり角、道間違えた道間違えた道間違えた
Wait, ah, hold on, the corner, corner, wrong way, wrong way, wrong way!
おっしょっしょ
Osshossho.
あ、Thank you
Ah, thank you.
えーっと。あれ？あれ？オッケー？
Um. Huh? Huh? You okay?
うん
Yeah.
よいしょ
Yoisho.
ほな！
Hona!
えーっと、あ、もしかして自分これ肉は、肉がない！
Um, ah, don't tell me I... I don't have meat!
あ、行っちゃっていいよ、全然。
Ah, you can totally go ahead.
いいかい？
You sure?
自分の食べ物の肉がなかった
I didn't have any meat for my own food.
はーちー
Roger that.
えーっと
Um...
よーし、オッケー
All right, okay.
えーっと
Um...
よいしょよいしょ、オッケーと、よいしょ。すいー
Yoisho yoisho, okay, and yoisho. Swoosh~
わっさわっさ
Wassa wassa.
あちゅ、あちゅ
Hot, hot.
あっちゅ、あっちゅ
ほい
Hoi.
えーっと、お肉...
Um, meat...
ベッド置いた方がいいかな？
Should I place a bed?
ああまあ近くにね、いっそね、ベッド置いちゃっても、でそこから復活でもまあいいのかな。
Ah, well, placing a bed nearby and just respawning from there might be fine too.
やべえ、なんかでけえ恐竜がいる。あれイナか？
Oh crap, there's a huge dinosaur. Is that Ina?
違うか、あ、イナだった。よかった。
No? Ah, it was Ina. Thank goodness.
はい 待ってます
Yep! I'm waiting.
待ってた、よかった。
You were waiting, thank goodness.
俺のアイテム...
My items...
うん
Yeah.
快速すればかんた... 簡単って言いますけどね、苦労してるんですよ！
They say "fast travel is eas- "... they call it easy, but we're struggling here!
おい初プレイだぞ、俺！
Hey, this is my first playthrough, you know!
おーそうだぞそうだぞ！こっちも初プレイ、初メンバーなんだぞ！
Oh yeah, that's right! It's my first playthrough with the new members too!
イナ、カマキリ助けて！
Ina, help me with the mantis!
はいしょ
Haisho.
ふっふっふっふ、ありがと
Heheheh, thank you.
いよっ
Iyo!
レッツゴー
Let's go.
えー、えーっと
Uh, um...
あ、またカマキリ
Ah, another mantis.
海辺、海辺行きます
I'm heading to the beach, the beach.
この、アキロゼ、のぜキャンARKのためにDLC買ったんだからな
Look, Akirose bought the DLC just for the Nozekyan ARK, after all!
買ったんだからなー！
Because she bought it!
そうだぞ、買ったんだからな
That's right, she bought it!
よいしょ
Up we go.
えっと
Let's see...
寝袋作るか、じゃあ近くに
Should I make a sleeping bag nearby, then?
そうやね
Yeah.
私の分も欲しいかも
I might want one for myself too.
オッケー。じゃあ、ちょっと近くの森で草でも刈りますか
Okay. Then, should I cut some grass in the nearby forest?
やばい、「実力不足」ってすごい煽られてる
Oh no, they're really roasting me with "skill issue."
なんだとお？ブロックしなきゃ
What was that?! Gotta block them.
な、なんだってー？
Wh-What did you say?!
う、う、う、そ、そんな、う、う、う
N-N-No way... U-U-U...
う、う... ほら、う、う、う
U, u... Look, u, u, u.
えっと
Let's see...
よ
Here...
ここで
Right here...
あれ？
Huh?
あれ？よっこらしょ
Huh? Heave... ho.
ん？なんか、なんかずっと...
Hmm? Why does it keep...
あれ？
Huh?
あ、ここここここ
Ah, here, here, here.
えっと、こうやって繊維取って...
Let's see, gather fiber like this...
あれ？寝袋、寝袋... 寝袋、寝袋...
Huh? Sleeping bag, sleeping bag... Sleeping bag, sleeping bag...
止まったか
Did it stop?
え？なんか飛んでる。めっちゃ攻撃されてる
Eh? Something's flying. It's totally attacking me.
皮がいるのか。皮か...
I need hide? Hide, huh...
あ、拠点... あの仮拠点に皮結構あったよ
Ah, at the base... at the temporary base there was plenty of hide.
一回戻るか、じゃあ。うん
Let's head back once, then. Yeah.
皮...
Hide...
やめなさい！
Stop it!
よいしょ
Up we go.
やめなさい！
Stop it!
えっと
Let's see...
うい
Yup.
よいしょ
Alright.
大丈夫か、飛んでる？
Is Tonderu alright?
いいよ
Okay.
飛んでる、多分ここに...
Tonderu, maybe in here...
んぎょ
Ngyo.
入れたほうがいいかも
I should probably put him in.
んにょ
Nnyo.
皮、皮、皮、皮、皮...
Hide, hide, hide, hide, hide...
あ、こっちだこっちだこっちだ
Ah, over this way, this way, this way.
おいしょ
Heave-ho.
赤くなった、飛んでる
Tonderu turned red.
えっと、これで... 寝袋を...
Let's see, with this... the sleeping bag...
よいしょ
There.
てい
Hup.
えっと
Let's see...
皮、皮、皮、皮...
Hide, hide, hide, hide...
あった、これで寝袋が作れるかな？
Found it. Can I make sleeping bags with this?
オッケー。なんかすっごいいっぱい作っちゃった
Okay. I made way too many though.
お
Oh.
よいしょ
Alright.
お、お、お、お、お、お、お、お
Oh, oh, oh, oh...
あ、よかった、よかった。と、と、トッケッキー。これで...
Ah, good, good. Tokkekki-. With this...
あっしょ
Heave-ho.
これで寝袋作... う、う、う
With this, make sleeping ba-... ugh, ugh, ugh.
オッケ。で、火山行くぞー！
Okay. And now, let's head to the volcano!
あ、待って、うーん
Ah, wait, hmm.
火山、火山... えっと、ここ
Volcano, volcano... Let's see, here.
ふう
Phew.
おいしょ
Heave-ho.
そういえばトワ様ってなんちゃらヴリュー作ったんかな？
By the way, did Towa-sama make that whatever-vliew?
うん。で、ライトニングワイバーンでもみんなゲットしてる
Yeah. And everyone's getting Lightning Wyverns, too.
あ、そっかそっか
Ah, I see, I see.
そうそうそうそう
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
トワ様も乗ってんのか
So Towa-sama is riding one too?
そうそうそう
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
え、それって今日受け取らないとダメなやつ？
Wait, is that something we have to claim today?
冷蔵庫の中入ってる
It's inside the refrigerator.
あ、オッケー
Ah, okay.
うん
Yeah.
よいしょ
Alright.
犬も取らないといけないんだよな
We also gotta get the dog, huh.
えっと
Let's see...
これで海岸へゴー！
And with this, off to the coast we go!
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
すー
Phew.
おっしゃ
Alright.
おいん
Boing.
明日何だっけ？あの、まるまる... あの、ケツなんちゃらだっけ？
What was tomorrow's? Um, the whatever... the Ketsu-something?
ラバエレメント？
Lava Element?
エレメント行けんのかな？
Can we do Element, I wonder?
行けるかな？でもワンチャン、あのパイロをテイムできたら行ける
Can we? But maybe, if we can tame that Pyromane, we can go.
あー、明日ちょっと行きたいね、じゃあ
Ah, let's try going tomorrow then.
そうそう、行きたいんだよね
Yeah, yeah, I want to go.
行きたいね
Let's go.
ちょ、ちょっと離れたところに寝袋を作るか、じゃあ
Sh-Should we make sleeping bags a bit further away, then?
え、この岩場置いとく？寝袋
Should we put the sleeping bags on this rocky area?
岩場いいと思います
I think the rocky area is good.
じゃ、ここ置くよ
I'll put them here, then.
1個もらおうかな
Maybe I'll take one.
オッケー。よいしょ
Okay. Up we go.
いいよ
Okay.
うわ、飛びすぎ
Whoa, jumped too far.
俺のジャンプ飛びすぎ
My jump went way too far.
「俺のジャンプ飛びすぎ」
"My jump went way too far"!
俺のジャンプ飛びすぎ
My jump went way too far.
えい
There.
ちょっと待ってね。え、俺...
Wait a sec. Huh, I...
シロン、どこ行った？
Where did you go?
今ね、岩場... あのスカイリムジャンプチャレンジしてる
Right now, on the rocks... I'm doing the Skyrim jump challenge.
いや、これ下、下でもいい、下でも、下でも
No, down here is fine, down here, down here.
下でもいいな
Down here is fine too.
全然いける 全然いける
Totally doable, totally doable.
降りるか、ちょっと待ってよ
Should I dismount? Hold on a sec.
オッケー
Okay.
イナもこっちだ、こっち
Ina is over here too, over here!
ここに この辺りに寝袋置いちゃうか
Should I just place a sleeping bag around here?
この...
In this...
あちゅ
Hot.
平べったいところに
...flat area...
ここに寝袋を置いちゃおう
Let's put a sleeping bag right here.
えーっと、待ってよ
Umm, wait a sec.
イナにも寝袋を、はい
A sleeping bag for Ina too, there we go.
ちょっと待って、フブちゃんどこ行った？
Wait a sec, where did Fubu-chan go?
あ、この岩場のところにいる
Ah, she's over by the rocks.
ちょっと待って、ほっ
Wait a sec. Hup.
ここです、ここです
Over here, over here!
どこだ、上か？
Where is it, above?
さっきのところにいるよ、よいしょ
I'm where I was earlier. Up we go.
あとワイバーン呼ばないとあれなんだよね
Also, if we don't call the wyvern, it won't...
あ、待って待って、待ってよ。たぶん離れたら来てくれるはず、それで
Ah, wait wait, hold on. It should follow if you get away from it.
ワイバーンさん来てく... ワイバーンじゃないわ、プテラさん！
Wyvern-san, come here... Not a wyvern, Ptera-san!
あ、来た来た来た来た、よいしょ
Ah, it's here, it's here! Here we go.
オッケー
Okay.
はいはい
Alright.
よし、ここを、ここを今日のキャンプ地とする！
Alright, let's make this today's campsite!
いいよ
Sounds good.
Okay.
あ、ここいいね、オッケー
Ah, this spot is nice, okay.
そうそう、ここに置いちゃっていいよ
Yeah, you can place it here.
１個貰いまーす
I'll take one.
いいよー
Sure thing~
ここをリスポーン地とする
We'll make this our respawn point.
革の寝袋って土台要らないんか？
Do hide sleeping bags not need a foundation?
要るっけ？要らない、要らない、要らない
Do they? No, they don't, they don't, they don't.
あ、要らないんだ、へぇー
Ah, they don't. Huh.
オッケー
Okay.
助かるー
That helps~
よーし、これで...
Alright, with this...
これでたぶん行けるはず、よし
This should probably work. Alright.
ほな、行きますか
Well then, shall we go?
ええよ
Sure.
よし、こっちだ、じゃあ
Alright, over this way then.
どこだー
Where is it~?
どこにいる？連れてこないといけないんだよね、まずね
Where is it? We have to lure it over first, right?
そうやね
Yeah, right.
えっと
Let's see...
どこだー
Where is it~?
もう近場に... もういない？あ、いたいたいたいた！
Nearby... is it gone already? Ah, there it is, there it is!
こっちこっちこっちこっちこっち、こっち
Over here, over here, over here!
プテラさん動いてなくね？
Isn't Ptera-san not moving?
あ、来た来てる来てる！今連れて来てる連れて来てる！
Ah, it's coming, it's coming! I'm luring it right now!
はい、で海行って
Right, and head to the sea...
うん
Yeah.
そして、乗っ... 乗ったら
And then, ri-... once you mount it...
うわっ
Whoa!
このあたり、この... このあたりいいかな？炎が消える距離
Around here, this... is around here good? Far enough for the flames to go out.
ほっ、乗って、ほら
Hup, mount it, come on.
待ってよ、こっちに連れて連れてこよう
Wait, let's lure it over here.
そうそう、そのあたりそのあたり！
Yes yes, right around there!
あ、今行けるかも！行けるかもだし、沈めろー！
Ah, maybe now! You might be able to, sink it!
はい
Okay.
行けるかも？どうだ？
Can you? How is it?
いや、まだ無理か？
No, still can't?
いや、行けるか？気絶させる？気絶かも
No, can I? Knock it out? Might be knocked out.
まだだね
Not yet, huh.
あ、ちょっ... てかヘビヘビヘビ！ヘビいる！あー！
Ah, wait... I mean snake snake snake! There's a snake! Aah!
あー！ヘビが！逃げる？
Ah! A snake! Can you escape?
もうクールダウン、クールダウン... クールダウン
Cooldown now, cooldown... cooldown...
やば、乗ったけど... クールダウンがー
Oh shoot, I mounted it, but... the cooldown...
あら、ま 気絶してます
Oh dear, well, she's unconscious.
オッケー、あ、でも死んじゃった？
Okay, ah, but did you die?
死ん... 死んじゃ、あ、プテラは死んだ
Die... did it die, ah, Ptera died.
あばよ、バイバーイ
Farewell, bye-bye!
じゃ、もう... ちょうどプテラの下にヘビがいて
Well, right underneath Ptera there was a snake...
「助けてよ」って
Screaming "Save me!"
「ヘビに噛まれてる」っていう
Saying "I'm getting bitten by a snake!"
くそー
Damn it~
毎回邪魔が入るよな、やっぱなー
Something always gets in the way every time, doesn't it?
えっーと、どこだ？ちょっと山の上に行かないといないかも
Umm, where is it? Maybe it won't be here unless we go up the mountain.
多分、山の洞窟みたいに行きながら見た気がするんですけど...
I feel like I saw it while going up towards the mountain cave...
うん
Yeah.
あと1、2分ほどちょっと気絶してます、僕
I'll be knocked out for another minute or two.
あ、了解でーす
Ah, roger that!
了解でーす
Roger that!
ヘビに噛まれて気絶してるんだよね、今
I got bitten by a snake and passed out right now.
そう、気絶しがねー
Yeah, getting knocked out, huh...
なんか近場に、本当に近くにいないかなー
I wonder if there's any nearby, really close by?
あー、ちょっと遠く行かなきゃいけないか。くー
Ah, do I have to go further out? Shoot.
よいしょ
Up we go.
えっーと... いる？
Let's see... is there one?
あ、でもあと30秒ぐらいでいけそう
Ah, but looks like I can move in about 30 seconds.
あとここ、今のところに、あの、まっすぐここ、こっち、1匹やれます
Also here, where I am now, straight this way, you can do one.
こっちいるか？
There's one here?
はい、見えました
Yes, I saw it.
およ？
Oho?
お、どこ行った？
Oh, where'd it go?
ちょっと右の...
A bit to the right...
あ、右のここ、この辺り？
Ah, on the right here, around this area?
はい
Yes.
ヒットポイントやべー
My HP is in dangerous shape...
あ、ほんとだ、ほんとだ、ほんとだ！黄色いのいた、黄色いの！
Ah, it's true, it's true, it's true! There's a yellow one, a yellow one!
はい
Yes.
お前来い、お前来い！
Come here, you, come here!
自分ヒットポイントちょっとないんで、行けないっすね
I barely have any HP, so I can't go.
やばい？
Is it bad?
ちょっとやばいね。ヒットポイント100しかない、今
It's pretty bad. I only have 100 HP right now.
あらら、じゃちょっとししろんが...
Oh dear, then maybe Shishiron...
うん、ちょ、あれだね、ユウティ乗ったほうがいいかも
Yeah, maybe she should ride the Yuty.
あ、確かに！ししろんがユウティ乗ったほうがいいかもね
Ah, true! It might be better if Shishiron rides the Yuty.
ん？ オッケー
Hm? Okay.
はい。あれ？どこ行った？
Alright. Huh? Where did it go?
あれ、なんかどっか... どっか消えちゃった？
Huh? Did it disappear somewhere?
はい。
Yes.
あれ？
Huh?
あ、なんか引っかかってろお前。
Ah, looks like you're stuck, buddy.
パイロ... パイロ、え、なんかなんか逃げてろお前。ど- どうしたパイロ？どうした？
Pyro... Pyro, uh, why are you running away? What's wrong, Pyro? What's wrong?
じゃあ僕、湖で...
Then I'll head over to the lake...
あ、こっちこっちこっち... あ、来た来た来た来た！
Ah, this way, this way... Ah, it's here, it's here!
うわー！熱い！
Wahh! Hot!
こっちか。
This way?
こっち来いこっち来い... 来た来た来た来た！
Come here, come here... It came, it came, it came!
カモン！
Come on!
どう？
How is it?
ほら、この水辺で...
Look, by the water...
どう？まだか？
How is it? Not yet?
逃げてる？
Is it running away?
トワちゃん追ってるね。
It's chasing Towa-chan.
あ、ヤバい。イナ、イナ追ってるかも。
Ah, shoot. It might be chasing Ina.
うわー！攻撃してあげて、攻撃してあげて！
Wahh! Attack it, attack it!
オッケー、オッケー。これで... これで多分...
Okay, okay. With this... with this, probably...
どう？乗れそう？
How is it? Can you ride it?
まだ...
Not yet...
あれ？今できるかな？
Huh? Can you do it now?
ちょっと泳いじゃってるから、もうちょっと陸側に...
It's swimming a bit, so get it a little more onto land...
まだ？
Still?
あ、乗れました！
Ah, I mounted it!
オッケー！あ、敵倒して、敵倒して！敵、敵が、敵がいないか？
Okay! Ah, defeat enemies, defeat enemies! Are there any enemies around?
イナ、陸上がっていいよ、陸上がって。陸上がって、敵に、敵攻撃して。
Ina, you can go up on land, get up on land. Get up on land and attack the enemies.
敵を、敵を...
Enemies, enemies...
敵がいない！ 敵ィ！なんでないんな？
There are no enemies! / Enemies! Why aren't there any?
10秒！
10 seconds!
あ、いるいるいる！イナこっち！イナここ！
Ah, there's one! Ina, this way! Ina, over here!
これこれこれ！このフンコロガシ倒そう！このフンコロガシ倒そう！
This one, this one! Let's beat this dung beetle! Let's beat this dung beetle!
これ、弱い、弱い、弱い！
It's weak, weak, weak!
このカブトムシみたいなやつ！
This beetle-looking thing!
ああー、落ちたー！あー！
Aahh, I got kicked off! Ahh!
もう一回だ！
One more time!
うわー、熱熱熱熱熱！
Uwaa, hot hot hot hot hot!
水の中に！
Into the water!
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー？あっつあっつあっつ...
Okay, okay, okay? Hot, hot, hot...
あー、よいしょ。
Ah, phew.
でも5分かかんのか。
But does it take 5 minutes?
5分です。
It's 5 minutes.
ああー、やばいかもー。
Aah, this might be bad.
5分はちょっと長えわ。
5 minutes is a bit long.
長いねー。
It is long.
惜しい！
So close!
惜しかったねー。
That was so close.
あ、なんかクラフトしてクリアしてるね。
Ah, someone cleared a crafting mission.
リニューアルだった？あれか、昆虫か？
Was it renewal? Is it that, the insect?
あー、5分はちょっと長いなぁ。
Ah, 5 minutes is a bit long.
乗れないもんね、多分今。
You probably can't ride it right now.
今乗れないねー。
Yeah, can't ride it now.
しょうがないしょうがない。うん、新しいやつ連れてこよう。
Can't be helped, can't be helped. Yeah, let's bring a new one.
ね。
Yeah.
えーっと...
Umm...
新しい、行こう！
Let's go find a new one!
いるかなー？
Is there one?
あー、でももうあと5分しかないんだ。ちょっと厳しいか。
Ah, but there are only 5 minutes left. Might be tough.
ラストチャンス行こっか。
Shall we go for a last chance?
ラストチャンスだな。ラストチャンス行こっか。
Last chance, yeah. Let's go for a last chance.
こっち、こっち、来てる来てる来てる。いいよいいよ、降りてこい、降りてこい。
Here, here, it's coming, it's coming. Nice, nice, come down, come down here.
あ、来た来た来た来た！
Ah, it's here, it's here!
おっしょ、おっしょ。
Alright, alright.
レベル55か。
Level 55, huh.
まあまあ、でも1体テイムしちゃってもいい。
Well, well, but it's fine to tame one.
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a second.
ちょっとベストポジション...
Looking for the best position...
どう？まだ？
How is it? Not yet?
今...
Right now...
ちょっと泳いでるから足が遅いんだね。
It's swimming, so it's slow.
まだですね。
Not yet.
あ、痛っ、痛っ、痛っ！
Ah, ouch ouch ouch!
痛い！
Ouch!
もうちょっとかな？
A little more?
あ、乗れました！
Ah, I mounted it!
よし、来た来た来た！
Alright, here we go!
これどう... どう使うんですか、この火？
How... how do you use this fire?
あのね、なんか攻撃ボタン... はい。コントロール右クリックで火だったかな？
Well, like the attack button... Yes. Was fire Control + Right Click?
いないかな、敵？
Are there any enemies?
さっきサソリとかこの辺だったけどな。
Scorpions were around here earlier, though.
ね、あ、あ、ここここ！ここにいる、これこれこれ！
Yeah, ah, over here! It's here, this one, this one!
これこれこれ！ コントロール、火...
This one! Control, fire...
1回、まあ倒して多分攻撃あて... そうそうそう！
First, beat it and land an attack... Right, right, right!
もうちょっと、もうちょっと手前...
A little more, a little closer...
で、それ、普通、そうそう、コントロール右とかで...
And then, normally, right, with Control + Right or something...
で、イナ、後ろ！そうそうそうそう！
And Ina, behind you! Right, right, right, right!
で、イナ、こっちにも敵いる！これこれこれ！
And Ina, there's an enemy over here too! This one, this one!
そうそうそう！
Right, right, right!
そのまま吸っちゃっていいよ、いいよいいよ、吸っちゃっていいよ。
You can just absorb it like that, go ahead, absorb it.
あ、できたー！ あ、テイムできた！ありがとー！
Ah, I did it! Ah, tamed it! Thank you!
うわー、できたー！あー！
Wahh, we did it! Aahh!
やったー！
Yay!
イナ、1回やればいけるね！ナイス！ いけるねー！ナイスナイス！
Ina, once you do it, you've got it! Nice! Yeah, totally! Nice, nice!
やったー！
We did it!
イナすごいよー！
Ina, that was amazing!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
できたー
We did it!
いや めっちゃ... なんか
Man, that was totally... kind of...
イエーイ！
Yay!
じゃあ 経験値... レベリング、レベリング！
Alright, exp... Leveling, leveling!
レベリング、レベリング！
Leveling, leveling!
おら！
Take that!
ナイスー！
Nice!
いやー
Phew~
後ろにもいるぞ、イナ！フンコロガシが！
There's one behind you too, Ina! A dung beetle!
あ、また虫がまた来てる。
Ah, the bugs are coming again.
虫、虫出てるぞ。
Bugs, bugs are showing up.
全然動いてないです、なんか。
It's not moving at all, somehow.
え？大丈夫？
Huh? Are you okay?
いや、ここで何とかなるか...
Well, can we manage here...?
何とかなったねー。
We managed somehow~
何とかなったー！すごーい！
We managed! Amazing!
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
イナ、モンボ... モンボある？モンボっていうか、あのー、なんか...
Ina, do you have a cryopod? Or like, um...
あ、持っていないです。
Ah, I don't have one.
あ、オッケー。んじゃ、これ戻して帰るか。
Ah, okay. Then shall we return this and head back?
そうだな、入れちゃおうかな、じゃあ。
Yeah, should I put it in, then?
じゃあ、自分のあれ持ってくるわ。あのー...
Then I'll bring my own. Um...
あ、イナ、降りちゃってもいいよ。
Ah, Ina, you can hop off.
あ、オッケーです。
Ah, okay.
プテラ... プテラの所まで行っちゃおう。
Ptera... Let's head over to the Pteranodon.
あれ？あ、もうここで... / あ、モンボできないか。
Huh? Ah, already here... / Ah, we can't cryopod it?
あれ？モンボできない？あ、もしかしてイナじゃないとできないか？
Huh? Can't cryopod it? Ah, maybe only Ina can do it?
イナじゃないとできなさそうだね。
Looks like it has to be Ina.
イナ、ある？
Ina, do you have one?
今、怪我がついてできないって... ちょっとメニューが...
It says it can't right now because it's injured... The menu is a bit...
ああ、そうなんだ。なんかできないんだ。じゃあ、パイロの... ああ、なるほどね。
Ah, is that so. It can't. Well then, Pyro's... Ah, I see.
メニューで... ご飯？
In the menu... food?
もう入れちゃって...
Just put it in...
肉はもう要るっぽいです。
Looks like it needs meat now.
肉、肉あるよ。
Meat, I have meat.
これでも大丈夫だな。行ける。
It should be fine like this. We're good to go.
あ、待って！あー、今サソリが！
Ah, wait! Ah, a scorpion just now!
あ...
Ah...
ナイス！
Nice!
え、なんで動いてない... お。
Huh, why isn't it moving... Oh.
あ。いや、バックステップはやったんですけど。
Ah. Well, I did do a backstep, though.
いや、全然... 全然動いてない。
No, it's not... It's not moving at all.
肩に乗せられるらしいよ、なんか。
Apparently you can put it on your shoulder.
乗ってCtrl+Cだって、イナ。
It says mount it and press Ctrl+C, Ina.
乗ってCtrl+C？
Mount and Ctrl+C?
うん。
Yeah.
おお、乗った乗った！ / おお！
Oh, it's on! / Oh!
えー、かわいい！
Ehh, so cute!
かわいい！じゃ、帰ろ帰ろ！こっちだこっちだ、イナ！
So cute! Let's head home! This way, this way, Ina!
それで帰ろ！
Let's head back like that!
ユウティ、ユウティラはここだよ。
Yuty, the Yutyrannus is here.
あ、じゃあユウティも回収しよう。こっちだこっちだ。
Ah, let's retrieve the Yuty too. Over here, over here.
これ回収、回収して。
Retrieve this, retrieve it.
あ、多分回収して... えっ... と。
Ah, probably retrieve it... and...
うん。で、あの、飛んで帰る。
Yeah. And then, um, fly back.
はい。
Okay.
オッケー。あ、イナのプテラ連れてくればいいんだ。えっと...
Okay. Ah, we just need to bring Ina's Ptera. Um...
あ、私のプテラ乗ってますよ、私が。
Ah, I'm already riding my Ptera.
あ、乗ってる？あ、よかったよかった！
Ah, you're on it? Ah, great, great!
よーし！
Alright!
よしよしよしよし。
Alright, alright, alright, alright.
え、待って、名前が「MEOW」なんだけど、なんか。
Wait, its name is "MEOW"?
なんか名前思いつかなくて...
I couldn't think of a name...
「MEOW」て！
"MEOW", really?!
今、離れたら「イナ MEOW」って書いてあって...
When I moved away just now, it said "Ina MEOW"...
やったー！
Yay!
やったねー！
We did it!
ああ、よかったです！
Ah, thank goodness!
これで... これで戦えるか。
With this... can we fight with this?
でも欲を言うともう1匹欲しいね。
Though if I'm being greedy, I want one more.
ま、そうだね、もう1匹行けたらいいね。
Well yeah, it'd be great if we could get one more.
うん。
Yeah.
でもやり方もできたから... / ね、明日やりたいね。
But we figured out how to do it... / Yeah, let's do it tomorrow.
明日1匹取ってボス行けたら。 / はい。
If we get one more tomorrow and go to the boss. / Yes.
うーん、いいね。
Mmm, sounds good.
あとミッションとボスに行けたらいいかな。
And if we can do missions and the boss, that'd be great.
いやー、行けたー！
Man, we did it!
もうちょっと上か。
A little higher up?
ういー。
Wheee.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho.
ああ、今日寝れるー。
Ah, I can sleep tonight~
寝れる、寝れる！寝れるわ、今日！
You can sleep, you can sleep! You can sleep today!
いやー。 / 今日本当よかったー！
Phew~ / Today was really great!
よしよしよしよし。
Alright, alright, alright, alright.
えいっ、うー。
Ei, ooh.
もう、イナのほう見ると「MEOW」って書いてある。ほんとだ。
Whenever I look at Ina's, it says "MEOW". It really does.
なんか名前何にしようと思って。
I was wondering what to name it.
MEOW。
MEOW.
えー、じゃあこれ入れよう。入れようん。
Eh, let's put this in then. Put it in.
よいしょ、あ！これで今日終了だー！
Yoisho, ah! That wraps it up for today!
えーい！ / お疲れー！
Yay! / Good work!
はーい！ / 自分は本拠点のほう戻ろうかな？
Okay! / Should I head back to the main base?
あ、そうだね。本拠点戻っちゃってもオッケーだよーん。
Ah, yeah. Heading back to the main base is totally fine.
はい、お疲れ様です。
Okay, thank you for your hard work.
よいしょー。日記書かなきゃ。
Yoisho. I have to write in the journal.
ディメンションネット、これ回収して...
The Dimension Net, retrieve this...
よいしょ、冷やしとくか。恐竜も冷やしておく。
Yoisho, should I cryo it? I'll cryo the dinosaurs too.
えーっと、こっちから行くと... で、今日の...
Um, going from here... And today's...
ミッション報酬の...
mission rewards...
何だっけ、チームミッション、ライトニングワイバーンこれ貰っていいのか？
What was it, team mission? Can I take this Lightning Wyvern?
あ、そうそうそう。あ、ワイバーンはもうね、ある。
Ah, right right right. Ah, we already have Wyverns.
あるか。じゃあいいや。
We do? Then never mind.
そう、こっちの仮拠点側のほうの冷蔵庫の中に全部入ってるはず。
Yeah, everything should be inside the fridge at this temporary base.
了解です。はい。
Understood. Yes.
ていうかさ、もう私の補... 何だっけ？テリジノサウルス、ここから取っていいかな？
By the way, my com... what was it? Can I take the Therizinosaurus from here?
うーん、いいんじゃないかな？
Mmm, shouldn't that be fine?
補填、補填のテリジノ。
The compensation, the compensation Therizino.
ああ、いや、それちょっと聞いといたほうがいいかもしれない、補填テリジノは。
Ah, no, you might want to ask about that first, the compensation Therizino.
あ、確かにね。
Ah, true.
補填、結局どっちかまだ分かんないんだよな。これじゃないんだよな。本物屋台じゃないんだよな。何某のエキスで死んで...
We still don't know which one is the compensation. It's not this one. It's not the real stall. It died from some kind of extract...
イベント参加賞ってどこだったっけ？イベント会場だっけ？
Where were the event participation prizes again? Was it the event venue?
イベント会場の外の、なんかピンクの床のところ、ゲートがあると思うんだけど...
Outside the event venue, at the pink floor area, I think there's a gate...
ピンクの床
The pink floor...
この中にないかな？
I wonder if it's in here?
お、回復してるね、こいつも。
Oh, this one has recovered too.
えーで...
And then...
オッケー。
Okay.
入れておこ。
Let's put this in.
参加賞。
Participation prize.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
アルマドック...
Armadog...
オッケー。
Okay.
お？
Oh?
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
All right, what to write...
あ、なんかすごい集めてるじゃん。
Ah, you collected a whole lot!
よいしょ。
All right.
Today was a struggle,
よいしょ、ちょっと一回...
Okay, just once...
but we didn't...
えーと、こっちだったっけ？藁...
Um, was it this way? Straw...
敷いてくるか。give up. Oh.
Should I lay it out? "...give up." Oh.
あ、これ石だな。
Ah, this is stone.
Give up, and in the end we got...
えーと...
Let's see...
the flaming...
ここに藁...あ、もうここでいっか。
Straw here... ah, right here is fine.
meowmeow! :3
いや、一応書いとくか。ここでした。
No, I should write it just in case. It was here.
よーし。
All right.
これもう船放置しとくしかないけど、これ船壊されないのかな？大丈夫かな？
We have no choice but to leave the boat here, but will it get destroyed? Will it be okay?
Yes.
Lots...
大丈夫か。
It'll be fine.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
...of learning, lots of progress...
ほな、ほな日誌を...
Well then, let's go...
...yay!
書きに帰りましょー。
head back to write in the logbook~
よいしょ。あーやばい、脱水症状だ。
Oof. Ah no, dehydration symptoms.
Oh yeah, I should write the date.
September 5th, I guess.
よし、いいな。
All right, looks good.
ういー。
Whew.
Okay.
みゃうがいる、みゃうが。
There's a meow, a meow!
Meow.
えーっと、ほい。
Let's see, here.
集会場、オッケー。
Community area, okay.
ふぅー、んー。
Whew, hmm.
かわいい。
So cute.
よいしょ。じゃあ稲葉家、家にいっちゃうねー。
Alright. Then the Inaba family is heading home!
はーい。
Okay!
入ってきたからやっといた。
You came in, so I went ahead and did it.
あ、お疲れ様でしたー！お疲れ様でしたー！
Ah, thank you for your hard work! Thanks for your hard work!
あ、そう、最後にイナがテイムできた！
Ah right, in the end, Ina was able to tame one!
できましたー！
I did it!
おおー！やったー！すごいすごい！ナイスー！
Woah! Yay! Awesome, awesome! Nice!
やったやったー！やったやったもうー！
We did it, we did it! We did it, finally!
ナイスです。大変すぎた。
Nice job. That was way too tough.
全部入れたか？確かに。
Did you put everything in? Indeed.
いや、マジで大変すぎた。
No, seriously, that was way too tough.
アルゲン狩ろうと思ったんだけど...
I thought about hunting Argents, but...
15匹で1ポイントしか入んないから、効率悪いなと思ってやめたんだよね、こっち。
since 15 of them only give 1 point, I thought it was inefficient so I stopped doing that.
やっぱちょっと効率悪いよなー。うん。
Yeah, it really is a bit inefficient. Yeah.
一応ね、太鼓は叩いて...太鼓叩いたから太鼓のそのマル秘ミッションは...
Just in case, we beat the drum... since we beat the drum, the secret drum mission...
1個クリアはしてる。
has one cleared.
うん、よかった。まだ報酬は明日受け取ろうかなんて。
Yeah, that's great. I was thinking of collecting the rewards tomorrow.
了解です。助かりましたー。すいません、本当にありがとうございます、色々と。
Roger that. Thanks for your help! Sorry about that, and thank you so much for everything.
よかった、よかった。じゃあ日誌を書いていこう、日誌を。
Glad to hear, glad to hear. Well then, let's go write in our logbooks!
今実は仮拠点に石の壁をめっちゃ貼る作業をしてて...
Actually right now, I'm working on putting up tons of stone walls at the temporary base...
おお！ありがたやー。
Oh! Much appreciated!
もしちょっとだけまだ元気だよって人がいたら、壁を作って貼ってくれませんか？
If anyone still has a bit of energy left, could you craft some walls and put them up?
壁を...壁を貼るの？
Walls... put up walls?
あ、ファーミングだめかもしんない、もしかすると。ファームはだめなんだ。
Ah, farming might not be allowed, maybe. Farming isn't allowed?
うん、ファームだめだね。直してるか。
Yeah, no farming. I'll repair it.
よいしょ...ふぅー。
All right... whew.
えーと、これのオートだっけ、消費か。
Let's see, was it auto for this? Or consumption?
あれ、向こうにいるビビアンとか...連れて行きたいな。
Wait, Vivian and the others over there... I want to bring them along.
ポットー...えっとね、ポットがね、あるんだ。今ビビどこいる？
Pods... Um, yeah, we have pods. Where are you right now, Bibi?
ビビ仮拠点です。
Bibi is at the temporary base.
あ、じゃポット持ってくね、そっちに。あ、ござるもちょっとポット...
Ah, I'll bring the pods over there then. Ah, Gozaru wants some pods too...
パイロはポット...あればあるほど助かります。いらないんですかね？
For Pyromanes, pods... The more we have, the better. They're not needed?
ん？パイロはポットに入れない？
Hm? Pyromanes can't go into pods?
パイロ...あ、パイロー！は入れないかもしれないからー。
Pyromanes... ah, Pyromanes might not be able to go in...
じゃあその、この余ってたやつ...置いてったらいいかな？あの集会場のところかな？
Then should I leave the leftover ones here? At the community area?
あー、はいはい。オッケーです。
Ah, right, right. Okay.
あ、野良、野良とトワ様...よいしょ、じゃちょっと。
Ah, wild, wild and Towa-sama... Alright, let me just...
え、待って、トワ様まだ日記書いてないですよね？
Wait, Towa-sama, you haven't written in the diary yet, right?
うん。
Yeah.
出れない...ちょっと待って、一回...ちょ日記書こうかな。日記書いて...
I can't get out... Wait a sec, let me write the diary first. Write the diary and...
オッケー。残った時間でやろうかな。
Okay. I'll do it in the remaining time.
あ、一応入るって、ポットにパイロ。あ、入れるかな？
Ah, apparently Pyromanes do go into pods. Ah, they can go in?
うん、入れられるらしいよ。
Yeah, apparently you can put them in.
じゃ、ちょっとやってみます。
Then I'll give it a try.
あれ、落ちた？
Wait, did it drop?
おぶ...
Oof...
なんか落ちちゃったのかな、このゲーム。
Did my game crash?
ほよ。
Hoyo.
これ、ど、どう戻せる？んっと...
How... how do I put this back? Um...
あ、すごい、めっちゃ...
Ah, wow, super...
えっとなんだっけ。
Uh, what was it?
O、Oダブルクリックか、Gをダブルクリック、どっちだったっけかな。
Double click O or double click G, which one was it again?
肩に担いでいる恐竜を...
The dinosaur I'm carrying on my shoulder...
Fを... あ、Fでした。
F... Ah, it was F.
あ、Fだった、ごめん！
Ah, it was F! Sorry!
ちっちゃい！
So tiny!
ポットない。
I don't have a pod.
えっーと。
Um...
1, 2, 3, 4... 4匹、4つあればいいのかな。1, 2, 3...
1, 2, 3, 4... Four of them. Do I need four? 1, 2, 3...
あ、これも集計期間外に... あ、こうやってやって... よいしょ。
Ah, this is outside the counting period too... Ah, doing it like this... Up we go.
あ、4つだ。離れたところに...
Ah, it's four. In a separate place...
あれ、死んじゃいそうだな。
Wait, it looks like it's about to die.
えっーと、じゃあ...
Um, then...
いろはが作ってくれた枠... 壁、上に広げちゃったよ、ちょっとだけ。
The frame Iroha made for us... I expanded the wall upwards a bit.
あ、ありがとうございます！多分上に行けば...
Ah, thank you very much! Probably if we go up...
ウォール・マリアできてる！
Wall Maria is complete!
もうちょっと簡易的な感じなんですけど、まあでもこれで仮拠点作り囲っこみたいなのができたと思うんで。
It's a bit rudimentary, but I think we now have an enclosed temporary base sort of thing.
おおー！
Ooh!
もう石がないから無理かもな。
There's no stone left, so this might be all we can do.
あ、オッケーです、オッケーです！よいしょ。
Ah, that's fine, that's fine! Here we go.
石結構取ったけど全然足りなかった。で、まあ1周ぐるっと囲ったから...
I gathered quite a lot of stone, but it wasn't enough at all. Well, since we enclosed the entire perimeter...
ま、一旦なんて言ったらいいんだろう、こう突進してくるやつは... なんとか防げるかな。
for now, how should I put it, the ones that charge at us... we should be able to block them somehow.
なんか... ベイビー？どう、どうするの？
Wait... The baby? What do we do with it?
コントロール、ひ、左... ん？
Control, l-left... huh?
え、プテラノドン死んど...？
Wait, the Pteranodon is dead...?
へ、これや！ / わああー！
Wait, this is it! / Whoaa!
にゃー、はい！ / 目も...
Meow, yes! / The eyes too...
多分ね、チェンジなのかな。変身ってのがあったんだよね。
Maybe it's 'Change'? There was a 'Transform' option.
そう、Eを長押しして...
Yeah, hold down E and...
ああ、なるほど！
Ah, I see!
右下に、そうそうそうそう。
To the bottom right, yes, yes, yes, yes.
ベスト。
Best.
あれ？で、えーっと、BBの子達はどこだ？
Huh? And, um, where are BB's babies?
BBの子達、あの... なんかちょっと離れた所にいるんですけど...
BB's babies, um... they are a little further away...
あ、あの離れたやつもね、これこれ、ポット、ポット、ポット、どうぞ！
Ah, those distant ones too, here, here, Cryopods, take them!
ありがとうございます。そしてなんかここにいたプテラが1匹死にました。で、サドルもなくなっちゃいました。
Thank you very much. And somehow one Pteranodon that was here died. Also the saddle is gone.
ああー... あ、じゃ... / 時間経過かな？
Ah... Ah, then... / Could it be time elapsed?
あ、できた。え？ここでポッドを...
Ah, done. Eh? A pod here...
時間経過で死んじゃったかな？
Did it die from time running out?
関係ある？あら。
Is that related? Oh.
あ、入れる！
Ah, it goes in!
ありがとうございます、ポッド。 / うん。
Thank you for the pods. / Yeah.
あれー？なんでー？困るな、これどうやっていこ... えっーと。
Huh? Why? This is troubling, how should I... Um...
モンボで出せばいいのか。
Should I just take it out with a Cryopod?
えーっと... / 大丈夫か？
Um... / Are you alright?
はい。で、あっちのこのBBアンとかギュギュットとかもそうだよね？
Yes. And the ones over there like BB-an and Gyugyutto are the same, right?
そうです、そいつ... あ、了解！こいつらじゃあ捕まえていくわ。
Yes, those guys... Ah, got it! I'll go catch them then.
ありがとうございます。 / はーい。
Thank you very much. / Okay.
じゃあここにいるやつをモンボに入れたらいいですか、とりあえず？
Then should I just put the ones here into Cryopods for now?
そうだね、モンボに入れといて、で集会場の方の自分の個人チェストでもいいし、冷蔵庫の中でもいいし、どっかチェストの中入れとけば。
Yeah, put them in Cryopods, and you can put them in your personal chest at the meeting hall, or in the fridge, anywhere inside a chest.
はい、ありがとうございます。 / うん。
Okay, thank you very much. / Yeah.
よーし。よいしょ。
Alright. Up we go.
倒れながら寝れるのか、これ。
Can you sleep while collapsing like this?
じゃあ、ここで...
Then, here...
ニャオ。
Meow.
あら、バグで死んじゃった？
Oh, did it die from a bug?
ほ？ほ？
Huh? Huh?
ピピピ... あれ？ピピピ今入れたけどな。
PiPiPi... huh? I just put PiPiPi in though.
あれ？ピピピのイベントリーが残っている。あ、これはでも... あ、よいしょ。
Huh? PiPiPi's inventory remains. Ah, but this... Ah, there we go.
モンボ入れたからや。
That's because I put it in a Cryopod.
解決？解決した？
Solved? Did you solve it?
はい、大丈夫です。
Yes, it's fine.
よかった。
Good.
えっーと、ギュギュットと... そう、遠くにいるね。なんか「女」ってのもいるんだけど何この「女」？
Um, Gyugyutto and... Yeah, it's far away. There's also one named 'Woman', what is this 'Woman'?
女？女？
Woman? Woman?
女は繁殖するためだけに作られた...
Woman was created solely for the purpose of breeding...
いませーん。
They're not here!
はーい！ / はい、はい。
Okay! / Yes, yes.
ボタンたん今ミュートなんだけど、ちょっと取れるかな？
Botan-tan is muted right now, can you unmute for a second?
今ね、そ-スピーカーミュートだから...
Right now, my speaker is muted, so...
あ、オッケーオッケー。
Ah, okay okay.
そしたらちょっとお伝えしてほしいんですけど、えっと、さっきロスした恐竜とかアイテムとかについては、返却が、え、ボタンちゃんの個人ボックス、集会場の拠点にある中にある、そこに、えっと、返しますということでお伝えいただければと。
In that case, could you please pass along the message? Um, regarding the dinosaurs and items lost earlier, they will be returned to Botan-chan's personal box inside the base at the meeting hall. If you could tell her that.
あーい。 / はい。
Okaay. / Okay.
お願いしまーす。了解でーす。はーい。
Please do. / Understood. / Okay.
お疲れ様でしたー。
Good work, everyone.
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good work!
全員は無理やな、なんか回収できるやつ回収しとくね、これ遠くのやつら。
We can't get all of them. I'll retrieve whatever we can collect, the ones that are far away.
はい。
Okay.
えっーと、BB-anと... よいしょ。
Um, BB-an and... Up we go.
ギュギュットか。もうBB... BBか。
Gyugyutto, huh. Already BB... it's BB.
わかりましたー。
Understood!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good work!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちょ、こいつらここ... この辺どっか行った。
Wait, these guys were around here... they went somewhere around here.
確かに。免疫のアーティファクトってどこ行ったんだろう？飾ってないけど。
True. Where did the Artifact of the Immune go? It's not displayed anywhere though.
あれはでも、個人の、あの...
That's, though, in someone's personal...
納品か、納品になっちゃうから
Since it'll just end up as a delivery...
名義はないです。飾るあれではないのかな
There's no name on it. Maybe it's not meant to be displayed?
あ、みんな帰ってきてる。なるほどね
Ah, everyone's back. I see.
包括だけはなんか飾るやつなのか、ま、それか納品したから明日飾られる可能性？
Is only the comprehensive one meant for display? Or maybe since we delivered it, it'll be displayed tomorrow?
ああ〜。うんうんうん。
Ahhh. Yeah, yeah.
あやーー！
Aahhh!
えっ、ええ〜〜
Wait, what?!
あれに入ってしまった
I walked right into that!
吸引力がすごかった、ブロワックの
The suction was insane on that vacuum!
ああ〜。あれマジやばいよね、超吸い込んでくるよね
Ahhh. That thing is crazy, it really sucks you in.
吸い込んじゃって、「ええ〜避けたつもりが〜」ってなっちゃって今
I got sucked in like, "Wait, I thought I dodged it!"
わかる〜
I know, right?
おいしょ。じゃ、ビビこれいきましょうか。ボンボン持ってるからぎゅぎゅっと
Alright. Shall we do this, Bibi? We've got bonbons, so we'll pack it full...
ああ〜、どちらでも大丈夫だよ。多分
Ah, either way is fine. Probably.
これみんな日誌、2枚書いたほうが？
Should we all write two diary pages?
ああ、そうしよう。お任せしよう
Ah, let's do that. Let's leave it to you.
え、2枚？
Wait, two pages?
うん
Yeah.
どういうこと2枚って？
What do you mean by two pages?
マル秘ミッションだか、デイリーミッションもゲリラミッションだかって
Like the secret mission, daily mission, or guerrilla mission...
あ、でも今ミッションできてないから、ミッションが...
Ah, but right now no missions are available, so...
明日かな？明日ポコロンって入ってくると思う
Tomorrow, maybe? I think they'll pop up tomorrow.
ああ、なるほど。じゃ、日記今入れとけば一旦明日クリアになるってことですよね？
Ah, I see. So if we put our diaries in now, it'll count as cleared tomorrow, right?
多分。じゃあ、9月5日続きで書けばいいか
Probably. Then I'll just write it as a continuation for September 5th.
9月5日続き...続きの2枚目
September 5th continued... Part 2.
何がこう...続きの2枚目...
What should I... Part 2...
よいしょ。ふぅ〜
Alright. Phew~
え〜〜。Number 2
Uhhh... Number 2.
ええ〜
Uhh...
日記の一番悩むな
Thinking of what to write in the diary is the hardest part.
よし
Alright.
1日に2枚書くってことなのかな？
Does that mean we write two pages per day?
ねえ、そうみたいですね。ね
Yeah, seems like it. Right?
よし、これでいいのかな
Okay, wonder if this is good.
怒られるかなこれ？
Will I get scolded for this?
何書いてんだ？怒られるようなこと書いてるな
What did you write? Sounds like something you'd get scolded for!
いや、怒られることじゃないんだけど、なんか書くことなかったんだなって思われそうだな
No, not really scolded, but they'll probably think I just had nothing to write about.
書くことなかったんだろうな〜
Probably had nothing to write, huh~
ないよ、ないよ
No way, not at all.
ビビは迷子になったぐらいだな
For Bibi, it was pretty much just getting lost.
いや、そうや。今日...洞窟迷子！
Yeah, exactly. Today... lost in the cave!
結構時間食ったからビビが先輩やった今日、迷子で
It took quite some time, so Bibi was the senior pro at getting lost today.
いや、そんなことあらへん。でござるも戻れなくてごめん。ダブル迷子だった
No way. Sorry I couldn't make it back either, degozaru. We were doubly lost.
本当にありがとうございます
Thank you so much, really!
いやいやいや。ええと、集会所...
No problem at all. Let's see, the meeting place...
どぅい。よっ、こっちだ。来た〜、ふぃ〜
Hop. There, this way. Made it~ whew~
よし、できた日記。書いたぞ日記。ナイス〜
Alright, diary done! Wrote the diary! Nice~
大分うざい日記を書いて、2枚ほど格納。よいしょ
Wrote a pretty annoying diary and stored two pages. There we go.
水
Water.
ちょっとじゃああの、皆さん作業片手にちょっと耳を貸してもらえると大変ありがたいのですが、ちょっと色々確認してもいいですか？
So um, if everyone could lend an ear while working, that'd be super helpful. May I check a few things with you all?
いいよ〜。は〜い
Sure~ Yes~
えっと結局、パイロメインってやつはテイムができたんでしょうか？
So in the end, were we able to tame that Pyromane?
1匹できたんだけど、できればもう1匹ほしいなっていう感じかな
We got one, but ideally we'd like one more.
ああ、なるほどです。了解です。じゃあまあ2体目ってことでめくっときます
Ah, I see. Understood. Then I'll check off looking for a second one.
と、ええと...あとは...
And, um... what else...
あとは、あの、マル秘ミッションの...あれ。あの、なんだっけ。変わんないか
Next is, um, the secret mission's... that one. Um, what was it? Never mind.
マンモスに乗って太鼓を叩くが、太鼓ができたから明日やればできそうが1つと
Riding the mammoth and beating the drum. The drum is ready, so we can probably do that tomorrow. That's one...
と、えっと、ケツ...ケツァールじゃないほう。名前忘れちゃう
And, um, Quetz... Not the Quetzalcoatlus. I keep forgetting its name.
あと何だっけ？ええ、溶岩エレメントだ。溶岩エレメント
What was it? Ah, Lava Element. Lava Element.
まあ、明日かな。パイロが2体いたら多分行けそうかなっていう感じは
Probably tomorrow. If we have two Pyromanes, I feel like we can handle it.
なるほど、じゃあ分かりました。そしたら一旦...そうですね
I see, got it. In that case, for now... right.
よし
Alright.
よいしょ
There we go.
あ、でも先にこれかも。明日はアイスの、アイスワームだっけ？あれ行っちゃった方が先にいいかも。うんうん
Ah, but maybe this first. Tomorrow is the Ice... Iceworm, was it? Might be better to go do that first. Yeah.
アイスワーム？だっけ？何だっけ？クイーンアイスワームだっけ？ボスミッションのやつ。あ、それやね
Iceworm? Was it? What was it? Queen Iceworm? The boss mission one. Ah, that's it.
ボスミッション明日行った方がいいかもね。せやね〜
It might be better to do the boss mission tomorrow. Yeah~
じゃ、ボスミッションじゃ入れときますね。うん
Then I'll put down the boss mission. Yeah.
じゃ、これを明日やるとして...あ、ヤバい、ちょっと待って、関数が終わっている可能性が...ぐっ
Okay, assuming we do this tomorrow... Ah shoot, wait, my spreadsheet formulas might be broken... ugh.
クイーンアイスワームやったっけ？うん
Was it Queen Iceworm? Yeah.
沼アタックは正直分かんない。戦ったことないやつらばっかだからな、この後
Honestly, I'm not sure about the Swamp attack. We haven't fought any of those coming up.
了解です。うん
Understood. Yeah.
そしたら明日はマストでやり...
In that case, tomorrow is a must-do...
ないのが、マル秘ミッションの4と、マル秘ミッションの1？
The ones we're missing are Secret Mission 4 and Secret Mission 1?
で、そのために開幕に、えっと、やんなきゃいけなさそうなのが...
So what looks like we need to do right at the start...
えっと、パイロをま、もう一匹テイムしに行く部隊と...
...is a squad to go tame another Pyromane, and...
えっと、マンモスを...
...a squad to go...
捕りに行く部隊が、まず確実にちょっと必要そうなので、そこでちょっと戦力分けをして...
...catch a Mammoth, which definitely seems needed first, so we split our forces for that...
ちなみに明日って、みんな何時方、いらっし、いますか？
By the way, what time will everyone be around tomorrow?
明日はですね、19時からいます！
Tomorrow, I'll be here starting at 7:00 PM!
明日は19時からいます！はい！ / いますよー
I'll be here from 7:00 PM too! / I'll be there.
みんな居そうなので、じゃあ、それでやるとして、えっと...
Since everyone will be here, assuming we go with that, um...
で... そうですね...
And... Let's see...
で、明日はそのパイロテイム次第、クイーンアイスワームボス... え、クイーンアイスワームボスって...
Then tomorrow, once the Pyromane is tamed, the Queen Iceworm boss... Wait, the Queen Iceworm boss...
...どのくらいの人数が必要そうなものなんですか？
...about how many people do you think we need for that?
一応全員で行った方がいいかな？
Just to be safe, maybe everyone should go?
なるほど。じゃ、一旦全員明日いると思うので、パイロがテイムでき次第、そのクイーンなんちゃら行っちゃいましょう。
I see. Since everyone should be here tomorrow, let's head to the Queen whatever as soon as the Pyromane is tamed.
うん、いいよー！
Sounds good!
で、クイーンなんちゃらが終わったら、ま、そのぐらいには多分マンモスできてると思うので、こう地道にマンモス部隊が...
And after the Queen whatever is done, the Mammoth should probably be done by then, so the Mammoth squad can steadily...
...こうマル秘ミッションを引き継いでいく形でやっていけたらいいのかなと...
...take over the secret missions like that.
...いう感じですかね。であとは、できそうなのなんだ？ちょっと待って。
...is kind of what I'm thinking. Aside from that, what else can we do? Hold on.
あとミッション達成できそうなのが... / そうね...
Other missions we could probably complete are... / Let's see...
あれ見るか
Let's look at the list.
テイムいっぱいする、みたいなやつが... / 20体テイムかな？底上げの...
The one where we tame a bunch of creatures... / Taming 20 creatures, to raise the base count?
あーそうですね。えっと今何体までできてたんだっけ？なんか半分くらいできてた気がするんですよね。
Ah, right. Um, how many did we have done so far? I feel like we had about half done.
私がみた限りでは6、で、パイ、パイロして7、7はいってるはず。
As far as I saw, it was 6, and with the Pyromane, 7. It should be at 7.
7はいってた。じゃあー、なんかその辺にいるまでのドードーとかテイムしても入りそうなので、まあ...
We were at 7. Then just taming things around here like Dodos should count towards it, so...
そう、そうだよ。しょぼいやつで全然いいから、テイムしていけばいけそう。
Right, exactly. Anything weak is totally fine, we can just tame them.
あとは、ま、ティラノサウルス10匹倒す？ / はい、はいはいはい。
Then, how about defeating 10 Tyrannosaurs? / Right, right.
ただ、ティラノ10匹いくためにミッション07だっけ？ / あ、そっかそっかそっか。
Though, to go for 10 Tyrannos, is it Mission 07? / Ah, right, right, right.
クイーンやって大型恐竜を、テイムの大型恐竜がどれくらいのあれなんだ？ティラノとかは大型か。
We do Queen and then large dinosaurs... What counts as a large dinosaur for taming? Tyranno is large, right?
ミッション一覧どこだっけ？えっと待ってくださいね。
Where's the mission list again? Um, hold on a second.
チームミッション一覧だね。 / チームミッション一覧、これか。
It's the Team Mission List. / Team Mission List... is it this?
そっか、そっか。
I see, I see.
何？今、右から、右へ行けてるから、次、明日のしょっぱなにこのクイーンアイスワームのミッション5をやって...
Right now we've progressed from right to right, so next, first thing tomorrow we do this Queen Iceworm Mission 5, and...
で、ミッション6の大型恐竜テイムが、まあできたらいいけども。
Then, if we can do Mission 6's large dinosaur tame, that'd be great too.
で、秘密のミッションを... やれたらいいのか。
And then if we can do the secret missions...
それでマンモスもやるって感じかな？ / そう、マンモスと、あの、あれ...
And do Mammoth as well, right? / Yeah, Mammoth and that, um, thing...
出てこない。
...can't remember the name.
ラバエレメンタル？ / ラバエレメンタル！マジですぐ名前忘れちゃう。
Lava Elemental? / Lava Elemental! I seriously forget the name right away.
何、まずじゃあ、何ちゃらエレメンタル。
Yeah, anyway, the whatever Elemental.
そうだね、できたらいいねー。 / そうやねー。
Yeah, it'd be great if we could do that. / Right.
じゃないとポイント的にあれじゃないか？もし稼ごうと思ったら。
Otherwise, wouldn't we be lacking in points? If we want to earn them.
結構ね、そういうところで稼がないと差がつかないんじゃないかなーっていう。
If we don't earn points from things like that, we won't really make a difference.
そうですねー。うん。
That's true. Yeah.
マンモスって大型ではないのかな？
Is Mammoth not considered large?
大型じゃない？ / 大型に入るんじゃないですかね？
Isn't it large? / Shouldn't it count as large?
マンモス大型の可能性あり。 / ある、あるある。
Mammoth being large is possible. / Definitely possible.
やべ、日記書かなきゃ。
Shoot, I need to write my diary.
日記書いたら全て消えた。なんてこと。
I wrote my diary and it all disappeared. Oh no.
そうですね。じゃあ、あれですね、どっかに一箇所中型・大型テイム用のあの罠作って...
Right. So then, we should build a trap somewhere for medium and large tames, and...
...一升テイムするかー。
...tame together.
恐竜なんだろうか？確かに。マンモスは恐竜なんですか？
Is it a dinosaur though? Good point. Is a Mammoth a dinosaur?
マンモスはこの世界にいるテイムできるもの全て恐竜だと定義できるのであれば、恐竜です。
If we define everything in this world that can be tamed as a dinosaur, then it's a dinosaur.
確かに。どうなんだろう。
True! I wonder.
この世界にいるテイムができる存在を全て恐竜と扱うのであれば...
If we treat every tameable creature in this world as a dinosaur...
...恐竜ということになりませんかね？ダメですか？
...wouldn't it count as a dinosaur? Is that not allowed?
じゃないよねー。 / ねー。
Probably not, right. / Yeah.
どこからが恐竜でどこからが恐竜じゃないのか、ちょっと分かんないけど。
I'm not really sure where the line between dinosaur and non-dinosaur is, though.
難しすぎではあるか。
Might be getting too complicated.
え、ちょっとまたあのやりたいなってこととかがあったら...
Um, if there's anything else you guys want to do...
...適当に雑談に貼ってもらったら、あの、ござるがやっておきます。
...feel free to post it in chat, and Gozaru will handle it.
はーいよー！ / オッケー！
Got it! / Okay!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
いえいえ。 / はーいよー。
Not at all. / Alrighty.
ラバエレメントのメモ、備考に貼っておきますね。
I'll put a note about the Lava Elemental in the remarks.
はーいよー。 / ほい。
Gotcha. / Sure.
ほな、今日はお疲れ様かな？ / はい！
Well then, is that all for today? / Yes!
お疲れ様でしたねー！ / お疲れ様でした！
Good work today, everyone! / Good work!
明日頑張りましょう！ / はーい、おつー！
Let's do our best tomorrow! / Bye-bye, good work!
はーい！
Bye-bye!
これポイントって付与されてるかも含めてちょっと確認するので、ちょっと待ってください。
I'll check whether points have been granted for this as well, so please wait a moment.
うわぁ... うわぁ...
Ugh... Whoa...
...a lot.
All right, otsu everyone.
All right, good work, everyone.
Thanks for... Thanks for staying with me. It was a lot.
So much happened, but I'm learning.
We got... We got stuff done.
Tomorrow is gonna be a big day, so let's continue
the dwarfness. See you guys tomorrow, same time. Okay?
Otsu!
Good work!
Bye-bye!
Wah~
Wah!